<!--
Note: Many articles had unusable plaintext, and thus text had to be transcribed by hand.
For this reason, portions of relevant text are not included in their entirety - omitted text is
denoted by an ellipsis.
-->
<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-gettysburg</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030213/1863-07-03/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=lee+battle+fighting+gettysburg+pennsylvania+union+yankee+rebel+confederate</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          The battle opened yesterday morning by severe skirmishing.
          The First and Eleventh Corps, supported by Pleasanton's cavalry and artillery, engaged
          with Ewell's forces, near Gettysburg toward Bendersville.
          The fight continued throughout the day, with variable results.

          The battle was renewed this morning, and continued up to 4 o'clock, our forces gaining
          upon the Rebels when our messenger left the field.
          Since 5 o'clock, the firing has been much heavier and more rapid, pertaining to a general
          engagement.

          ...

          The number is stated at 6,000, but this may be an exaggeration. Gen Schenck has just
          announced at the Estaw House that 2,400 of them have arrived.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86053570/1863-07-03/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=lee+battle+fighting+gettysburg+pennsylvania+union+yankee+rebel+confederate&amp;st=image&amp;r=0.24,0.323,0.731,0.731,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          From Major Bumgarten we alearn some interesting particulars of the battle, and are happy
          to be able to say that it closed for the day with the army of Gen. Meade in a most
          advantageous position, either for attack or defence.
          Nearly all of the remaining divisions of our army reached the field shortly after firing
          ceased for the day.
          ...
          A great an decisive battle was considered imminent, and notwithstanding our severe loss in
          officers, the advantages of the day were regarded as decidedly with our forces.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030213/1863-07-07/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=lee+battle+fighting+gettysburg+pennsylvania+union+yankee+rebel+confederate&amp;r=0.044,0.017,0.833,1.091,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          The Rebels have retreated toward the Potomac.
          ...
          Our troops have been engaged all day in burying the dead, relieving the wounded, and
          collecting the small-arms, many thousands of which belongfed to the Rebels.
          ...
          Gen. Lee yesterday paroled about 2,000 Union pirosners. They were received by Gen Couch.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038443/1863-07-07/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=lee+battle+fighting+gettysburg+pennsylvania+union+yankee+rebel+confederate&amp;r=0.007,0.163,0.417,0.546,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          UNION VICTORY!
          The Gettysburg Battles.
          The Greatest Contests of the Times.
          ...
          These battles were the most sanguinary shock of arms our continent ever saw, or perhaps
          the world since Waterloo.
          ...
          Those who in the crisis fell, were in the noblest cause, on a field that may decide the
          Gigantic Struggle of the Age between Liberty and Despotism.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024738/1863-07-07/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=lee+battle+fighting+gettysburg+pennsylvania+union+yankee+rebel+confederate&amp;r=-0.064,0.266,0.294,0.385,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          LATEST FROM THE NORTH.
          THE GREAT BATTLE AT GETTYSBURG.
          ...
          We have received from Hon. Robert Oald, Commissioner of Exchange, New York papers of the
          2d, 3d, and 4th insts.
          The news of the battle of Gettysburg differs considerably from the first Yankee accounts.
          When they were first attacked they were some distance beyond Gettysburg, but were driven
          out, and are now this side of the town.
          ...
          Nothing is yet known as to results, but the impression prevails that the great decisive
          battle of the campaign has beeen fought in the neighborhood of Cashtown, between
          Gettysburg and Chambersburg.
          It is believed we have suffered heavy losses in officers and men, but Lee is so crippled
          as to be placed on the defensive.
          Yesterday Gen. Meade assumed the offensive.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86053570/1863-07-09/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=lee+battle+fighting+gettysburg+pennsylvania+union+yankee+rebel+confederate&amp;r=0.397,0.126,0.335,0.439,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          LATEST FROM GETTYSBURG.
          ...
          As the details, the incidents, and the general history of the great victory are brought to
          light, it is clearly defined as the most hotly contested and destructive engagement of the
          great rebellion.
          The peculiar feature of the battle is the ferocity and desperation with which it was
          fought by both armies.
          ...
          The wound is not dangerous.
          L. L. Crounse.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84025980/1863-07-10/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=lee+battle+fighting+gettysburg+pennsylvania+union+yankee+rebel+confederate&amp;r=-0.083,0.255,0.383,0.502,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          Federals Admit an Enormous Loss.
          ...
          It is said that the Confederates suffered fully as heavily as we did.
          ...
          Gen. Wadsworth was severely wounded.
          Our loss was enormous and heavy, and especially among the field and line officers.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85025181/1863-07-11/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=lee+battle+fighting+gettysburg+pennsylvania+union+yankee+rebel+confederate&amp;r=0.479,-0.037,0.335,0.439,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          ARMY OF THE POTOMAC VICTORIOUS.
          ...
          The fighting at Gettysburg, on Wednesday, Thursday, and Friday, of last week, was of the
          most desperate character, and the losses on both sides were dreadful.
          The results may be thus summed up.
          ...
          The loss of Thursday on both sides was fearful.
          The enemy made several vigorous assaults, in some cases approaching to the very mouths of
          our guns, but was as often driven back.
          ...
          The report respecting the death of Gen. Longstreet and the capture of Gen. Hill, of the
          rebel army, are not confirmed.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045160/1877-12-22/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=gettysburg&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.327,0.37,0.139,0.363,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          Correspondent General," I find in the Phil
          adelphia Times for this week a letter from
          Colonel Mosby, in which he charges you
          with the loss of the battle of Gettysburg. As
          well known as you are in Memphis, and so
          highly respected and esteemed by the people
          of that city, it becomes a matter of impor
          tance that you should vindicate yourself be
          fore them and relieve yourself from a charge
          which embraces, besides the responsibility
          mentioned, a want of soldierly discrimination
          and generalship which your history forbids
          your friends accepting as correct. Please
          state what the orders were issued by General
          J. E. B. Stuart under which you acted iu
          the movements preceding, pending and Bub
          sequent to- the battle of Gettysburg.
          General Robertson When General Lee
          had decided to move intoA'ennsylvania, and
          General Stuart, with a part of his cavalry
          corps, left camp near Rector's cross-roads in
          the direction of Washington, he left orders
          with me to assume command of Jones's brig
          ade, and with my own to hold Snicker s an
          Asbv s prans until a certain time (whinh.
          think, was stated, and the order will showV
          then to concentrate in the Shenandoah val
          ley, sweep through it, picking up all desert
          ers and stragglers, and join General Lee with
          as little delay as possible,
          Correspondent Y"ou obeyed these orders
          General Robertson I did, literally and
          promptly.
          Correspondent) What length of tiai
          elapsed between the departure of General
          Stuart and your loininer General Lee?
          General Robertson General Stuart left on
          the twenty-fifth of June, and I reached the
          vicinity of Lee's army on the morning of the
          third of July.
          Correspondent How long did you remain
          at Snicker's gap; and when you lett, what
          route did you take and what special work did
          you perform t
          General Robertson I remained until the
          twenty-ninth of June, when I removed to
          Berryville, in the Shenandoah valley, where
          I was joined by Jones's brigade, and marched
          directly on toward Gettysburg, executing the
          orders given me m route.
          Correspondent When did you reach the
          vicinity of General Lee?
          Gene, al Robertson Between twelve o'clock
          noon and one o'clock on the morning of the
          third ot J uly. 1 moved my command from
          its camp at Chambersburg, crossed the South
          mountain about daylight, reaching (Jiishtown
          in tbe vicinity of Gettysbury, about ten
          o'clock in the morning. There I learned, on
          information from Uenerai Lee, that Pleas
          anton's cavalry was moving from Emmetts-
          burg, with a view to capture our baggage
          trains. I immediately sent General Jones's
          brigade forward, following in a short time
          with my own. We encountered the enemy's
          cavalry at Fairfield, the advance of which
          was commanded by Colonel Starr. After a
          very short, but sharp contest between the
          Sixth United Slates regulars and the Sixth
          Virginia Confederate cavalry, the former
          regiment was routed, with heavy loss, and
          driven back and pursued in the direction of
          the main body of the Federal army. We
          followed until nearly sundown, when we re
          turned to the neighborhood of Fairfield,
          where we encamped.
          Uorrespondent then you did not join
          Lee's army, or take part in the battle of Get
          tysburg?
          General Robertson No; in pursuance of
          my orders I could not.
          Correspondent Could it have been possi
          ble for you to have acquainted General Lee on
          the first of July of the movements of the
          enemy then in his front?
          General Koiiertson JNO; because my in
          structions compelled me to remain where I
          was left by Stuart for a certain time, during
          which General Lee's army was marching to
          ward Gettysburg; and from the time when I
          left Snicker s and Ashby s gaps, on the
          twenty-ninth of June, it would have been
          impossible to have made the distance to Get
          tysburg. Correspondent Colonel Mosby, in his pa
          per in the Philadelphia Timt-s. savs "Rob-
          ertson's and Jones's brigades, under com-
          mand of the former, were lett in observo-
          tion of the enemy on the usual front (about
          .uiaaieourgj, witn iuu instructions as to
          "following up the enemy, in case of with-
          drawal, and jotning our main army." It
          seems to me that if you followed the enemy,
          then falling back, so as to cover Washington,
          you could not join Lee's army moving rapidly
          toward Gettysburg. Is there not a contra
          diction in this statement of Colonel Mosby?
          uenerai rtoDertson there certainly is.
          My orders were to follow Lee, as! have stated.
          After sweeping through tho Shenandoah
          valley, and performing the specific duty as
          signed me of picking up deserters and strag
          glers, I could not have pursued the enemy
          and executed my orders.
          Correspondentr-Suppose you had followed
          up the enemy instead of going to the valley
          and after Lee, what would have been the re
          sult? General Robertson With the Federal
          army between me and General Lee, commu
          nication with him would have been impossi
          ble. Correspondent On the morning of the
          fourth where were you, and what did you do
          that day?
          General Robertson I made a reconnoia
          sance in the direction of EmmetUburg, and
          ascertained the movement of Pleasanton, and
          picketed the road in that direction, so as to
          cover Lee's movaoicnU, should ke be com
          pelled to fall back.
          Correspondent I suppose your troops were
          in the saddle during all of that day?
          General Robertson I held them in readi
          uses for any orders I might receive from Gen
          eral fctuartor General Lee.
          Correspondent On the night oi the fourth
          of July where did you camp?
          General Robertson Near the same place as
          the night before, ia the neighborhood of Fair
          field.
          V-orresponaent un the tum, what move
          file retreat commenced on that morning, and
          1 remained in position until that night, when
          I took position in rear of the army, to
          cover its movements.
          Correspondent You remained and acted
          under General Stuart's immediate orders af
          ter that until the campaign ended by Lee
          arrival at Culpepper courthouse?
          General Robertson 1 did.
          Correspondent Were you engaged at any
          time uunng tne retreat r
          General Robertson Yes; several times,
          Near Uaggerstown and Funkstown, Mary
          land. Correspondent Have you a copy of the or
          ders under which vou acted?
          General Robertion I have not, but have
          written to my adjutant-general to procure
          them. I also intend to apply at the war de
          partment, with the hope that they may be
          lound among the Confederate archives.
          Correspondent Was your route prescribed
          in these orders
          General Robertson Distinctly. I recall
          particularly this sentence: "To sweep through
          the Valley, picking up deserters and strag
          glers.
          Correspondent Then, by your orders, you
          could not have crossed the river at Harper
          Ferry
          General Robertson I think not. I crossed
          at Williamsport, and marched directly to
          unamoersDurg.
          Correspondent What would have been
          the consequences had you not arrived in rear
          ot Lee s army on the third i
          General Robertson The unquestionable
          capture of all tbe baggage and supply trains
          ot the army, as Pleasanton was marching un
          molested upon them. Immediately upon my
          arnvai at astietown, a letter oi instruction
          from General Lee directed me to meet and
          drive back this force, which was done prompt
          ly, and as before stated, with heavy loss to
          the enemy.
          Correspondent Had you, as Colonel Mosby
          says you ought to have done, moved on to
          join Lee s army on a route parallel with his
          and Hooker's, so as to observe the latter and
          keep Lee acquainted with his movements,
          would you not have disobeyed your instruc
          tions?
          General Robertson Yes. I was ordered,
          as I have said, to march through the Shenan
          doah valley, and there had the specific duty
          to perform of picking up deserters and strag
          elers, aOor holdine the caps for a certain
          time, which I presume was to mislead Hooker
          menta did you make?
          r t t.-v
          as to General Lee's designs, or for some other
          purpose not communicated to me.
          Correspondent Did you meet General Lee
          at any time dunng the campaign f
          General Robertson I met him several
          times. The last time after the retreat from
          Gettysburg commenced, and when the army
          was passing Fairfield. I was sitting on a fence,
          surrounded by my staff, waiting for the army
          to pass so that I could take position in rear
          of it. As he passed along the lines he was
          greeted with hearty cheers, which, taken up
          by my own men, were repeated with warmth
          As he neared me I got down, walked over to
          him, and.salating, shook hands witn him and
          said something to this effect: General.
          am glad to see that, though you are going in
          the wrong direction, your troops have not
          lost confidence in you, and that they have an
          undiminished respect for you." To this he
          replid: "Yes; this grieves me more than all
          else. I assume all the responsibility.
          Correspondent When the army of North
          ern V lTinma returned from the Gettysburg
          campaign, ana went into camp at Uulpepper
          O J. i t house, were tormal charges i-relerred
          ixain&amp;t you or asaiust General Stuart for
          disobedience of orders, or for failure to act
          promptly, or for dila'onness in tho execution
          ot ftucli orders y
          uenerai nooertson io. luere were no
          grounds for such charges. I never heard that
          I was m the least, to be biamed until I read
          tbe statement of Colonel llosliy. upou which
          you base jour interview.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042461/1895-12-26/ed-1/?sp=5&amp;q=gettysburg&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.213,0.289,0.41,1.053,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text> TO THE EDITOR Reply to Colonel Dunkelberger's Criticism Colonel Dunkelberger, in hia
          reply to my article, accepts my statements as to the governmental action in rogard to the
          ex change of prisoners, but be is thrown off hia balance at a remark of mine in regard to
          the forces on each aide at the battle of Gettysburg. It is on this expression he wastes
          all his force; in this expression, which we quote: "Was not this the day of all the days
          in the year, when a general, for three days on inaccessible heights, with 95,000 men had
          hardly held at bay an army of 65,000?" lies the substance of his attack Now, why did we
          uae thisexpression, and who was the author of it? We were argu ing that "military
          necessity" hatl prevented the exchange of one confederate soldier for one union soldier,
          and that Gen. Grant had written to lieu. Butler, April Ist, 1804, "Not to take any step by
          which an other able-bodied man should be ex changed," and had said to Gen. Butler in a
          letter of August 18th, 1804: "At this particular time, to release all rebel prison ers
          would insure Sherman's defeat and would compromise our safety hsre." (In front of
          Petersburg.) We wished lo set forth (hat Lee, having been defeated on the 3d with a loss
          of 12, --227 prisoners, and as the government knew that on the next day Vicksburg would
          surrender with more than 30,000 prison ers, that it would be a good way of cele brating
          the 4th day of .Inly hy at least ex changing their captures at Gettysburg for an equal
          number of federal prisoners, thus relieving them of tho foot sore, travel of hundreds of
          miles to Libby prison. We here quote what wo aaid in our original article: "This mili tary
          necessity grew out of the fact that whereas the south had enlisted in her armies 000,000
          soldiers, the north had only 3,778,304 soldiers on her rolls." And while we claimed from
          Vol. 4, page 007 "Battle and leaders," the following statistics as tho enlis'tnents for
          the war, viz: Whites 2'404,5»2 Sailors 101,701) Negroes 178.075 Total enlistment
          2.77«.:ui4 Yet we ara wiling to give up the calcula tions of the Battles and Leaders,
          though they were the most accomplished men on the editorial corps of the Century and both
          federal soldiers. Yet, discarding the learnetl and very carefully prepared statistics of
          the Battles and Leaders, we are prepared to accept the fact that Mr. Lincoln called from
          the different states 2,850,040 soldiers and 2,05*1,353 responded and were sworn in. In
          1803 New York, New Jersey, Pennsyl vania, Ohio, Illinois and Indiana furnished as
          "emergency men" 120,000, which should be added to the regular enlistment. Accepting the
          llgures of the adjutant-gen eral, viz. 2,050,353, there were four fed eral enlistments to
          each confederate. Our reason for discarding the carefully prepared statistics of the
          Battles and Lead ers and accepting the official account of the adjutant general is because
          the strength of an array is always more correctly stated by its commanding general and
          officers and its accepted historians than by the enemy. And it ia only fair that the
          official reports of the officers on each side should be conclusive as to the strength of
          the army they represent. Guesswork will carry with it no force. General Meade, in his
          testimony before the committee on the conduct of the war, in giving a statement in regard
          to the battle of Gettysburg, said: "I had no informa tion concerning the enemy beyond the
          fact that a large force under General Lee, esti mated at about 110,000, had passed through
          Ungorstown," Part I, 1804-5, page 320. Report of Conduct of the War. When General Meade
          was asked as to the comparative strength of the two armies, he answered as follows, in
          regard to the confederates: "I think General Lee had about 90,000 infantry; 4000 to 5000
          artillery nnd about 10,000 cavalry." Kvery intelligent man knows that the strength of tho
          confederates was always overestimated. Comte de Pat is, the author of Tho Civil War in
          America, who was on General Met 'lei lans staff during the cam paign against Richmond,
          says on the sub ject "Since tho army of the Potomac came into existence, there has always
          been a disposition to overrate the enemy's num erical strength." (S «c letter of Comic de
          Paris written in 1874, Vol. 5, pages 205 and 206, Southern Historical Papers, city
          library.) Mr. Lincoln heard ho much of this exag geration of southern armies that he took
          it off in one of his most pungent anecdotes. An old gentleman and friend of Mr. Lin coln,
          from Illinois, who had a eon iv tho Army of the Potomac, called to have a friendly chat
          with the president. Feeling great solicitude about the safety c f his boy, he asked Mr.
          Lincoln how many men he thought Jeff Davis had in the field. Mr. Lincoln, with a twinkle
          in his eye, said: "Jeff Davis has 3,000,000 men in the field." With despair on his face,
          lie asked Mr. Lincoln how he knew this fact. Mr. Lincoln replied, that every time one of
          hia generals got whipped down in Virginia, he always said he had to light three times his
          own numbers. "Yes," said he, "I have 1,000,000 men in the field, and Jeff Davis has
          3,000,000 in his army." After General Lee crossed the Potomac General Hooker called
          continuously for more troops from the war department, claiming that Lee had more men than
          he had. Driven to desperation he telegraphed to_ General Halleck as follows, on June 27,
          1803 "That there may be no mis understanding as to my force, I would re spectfully state
          that including Heintzle man's command antl General Schenck's, now with me, my whole force
          of enlisted men for duty will not exceed 105,000." Keport on conduct of war, part 1, page
          SOl, Here General Hooker wrote that he knew better than any one else, and this was only
          four days before the battle of Gettysburg, and i was based on the report of his army,
          which would appear on June 30. That report is as follows: Present for duty, ollicers
          t>,*>2o men 9 ,t;:i7 Aggregate present 117,!IJ0 Note this telegram from General Hooker, in
          which he states bis enlisted men as 105,000. After the report of Juno 30th was made up,
          which ebowed as present for duty 104,20,6, Lookwood it Stannard'a brigade —5000—was added.
          These two brigades were not included in ihe report of June 30th. This would niako Meade's
          force 109,250, without including the 11,000 at Harper'i Ferry, and General Meade used 7000
          of tbem to proloet bis rear and cut Lee's communication. Comte de Paris, the titled
          historian of the Federal army, places Federals present for duly, 91,250; Confederates,
          ti(i,(>so, thus giving the federals, a majority of 24,011 over the Confederates. Tliis is
          the lowest number ever recorded by a historian to the Federals present and the highest
          ever given to the Confederates. General Eivell, who commanded a division of Ewells' corps
          at Gettysburg, has written with more critical uccuracy of the strength of Lee's army than
          uny writer living or dead, and after much sifting and calculat ing, based ou all official
          data obtainable, we present the result of his best thought: Probable strength ot the
          confederate infantry 48.000 Adrl for cavalry (i.ooo Artillery 4,000 Total 50000 We will
          not enter into thecalculatjonsas to how these results are obtained, but they can be found
          in the Southern Historical Papers, Vol. VI, page 12 and following. We now recapitulate our
          llgures: Generol Hooker admits as present for duty the day hefore the battle 104,'.!51i
          Lockivood's and Mannard's brigade! »'The Ha per'a Kerry command 11,000 j Total 120/253
          Comte do Paris puts tho army of Meade as pre out 105,000 M. Quo l puts It at 05,000
          Battles and Leaders, edited by federal LOS AKGELES HERALD: THURSDAY MORNING. DECEMBER 26.
          1898. nffl-CTa, puis Mettle's effective force at 1011079, and closes ita critical review
          of tho relative strength of the armies by say ing thai "General Lee had at his command on
          tiio Belli of bin tie, from Ur»t to last, an army numbering at east 7U.0U0 of all anna."
          It ia a fact that the 151 st regiment of Pennsylvania militia and 20th New York fought
          under General Gates in Doubleday's division. So much for the armies at Get tysburg. We do
          not commend to the honest in quirer after historical truth, Col. Dunkel herger'a manner of
          estima.ing tho strength of the enemy. He takes Lode's muster roll at Carlisle, Pa., June
          HO, and found be had an aggretrate present of 9098 and multiplies it by the nine divisions
          of the Confederate army, and thus settles it that the army of Leo hod at Gettysburg H I
          ,HH2. (See his reply in Los Angeles Hkrm.d, De cember 15, 1 898.) Now, he takes the ag
          gregate present and not the total effective. The effective in the same report were 8125;
          Now, General Early commanded a division in this tight and he reports his ag gregate
          present June 20 at I! 17b. Now, if Col. Dunkelberger had taken Early's re port of nearly
          the same date and multi plied it by nine, it would give 68,284, in stead of HI.HH'J. This
          proves the fallacy of selecting any one division or brigade to test the strength of an
          army. In Colonel Diuikelherger's reply to my i article, ho takes the report of General
          Lee, j one month after the battle of Gettysburg, when he was in Virginia, where reinforce
          ments and recruits could meet him, and I quoting Lea's muster roll on July Slat, as
          53,280, then adds !.ee's losses at Gettys burg in order to prove that Lee must have had
          96,000 at Gettysburg. Following this same line of reasoning, Swinton, the his torian,
          takes Lee's report of May 31st, giving 68,325 as his effectives and his re port a month
          after Ihe battto of Gettys burg, when Lee reports 41,1 Do, and then argues that 27,'J17,
          the difference between the two reports, allows the loas of Lee at Gettysburg. (Mcc not»,
          page 305, Swin ton's Campaigns of the Army of the Potomac.) Wore our personal respect for
          Colonel Dunkelberger less, wo would call this un fair. Take the report oi the army of the
          Potomac for July 10th, j.ist seven days after the battle of Gettysburg, an! the ag gregate
          present was !>7,r>tl4; now add to it 29,049, admitted to have been lost by Meade in that
          battle, and it gives Meade's strength at Gettysburg as 120,008. What the world wants to
          know is, not the strength of either army tiiirty days after the battle, but what was tho
          avail able strength on the day of the battle. We asked the question in the beginning of
          our reply Who is the author of the figures used by us as follows. Was not till* tiie duy,
          of all the days iv tho year, when a general, who for three days on inaccessible heights,
          with 05,00 V) men, had hardly hold at bay an army of 65,000?" We quote, as the author of
          the ab >ye figures, from a book, "Field, Fort and Fleet," by M. Quod, who is Mr. C. B.
          Lewis of the Detroit Free Press, a fetleral officer and soldier. In his article on page
          407 of that volume on "Gettysburg and lis Re sults," he says: "Sixty-livethousand men had
          failed to drive 90,000 from one of the strongest positions ever seen ou a bat tle field.
          That fact, and that alone, constituted the federal victory at Gettysburg. But would the
          05,000 attack the 05,000 in turn? All night Friday night Lee's shattered commands were be
          ing consolida ed and his lines strength ened. He was there and ready at day break; but
          Meade would not attack. He was there and ready at high nnon, but not a man moved to
          disturb him. Lee had failed to carry Meade's position, but still held half tiie
          battlefield, and was ready to be attacked." As a matter of fact, Gen. Kn ell's corp did
          not leave the field won on the 3d, till near noon on the sth. Lee retreated to the Po
          tomac, but finding it unfordable, while Meade's army gathered around him, "but instead of
          a vigorous attack, he ordered Ilia army to intrench against Lee." (Field, Fort and Fleet,
          page 468). Now a word as to the author of Field, Fort antl Fleet. More than forty yeara
          after the battle of Waterloo, Victor Hugo wrote a description of Hie same, autl It, today,
          is the grandest battle scene ever writ en of a European battle. On these pages stalked the
          heroes of forty years before; there is Ney charg ing at the head of his cuirassiers; there
          is Milliaud witii his twenty-six squares of cav alry, charging the plateau of Mont Saint
          Jean; there is the sunken road of Ohaio, where, as Byron says, went down "Rider and horse
          -friend and foe In one red burial blent." In the rythmic periods of this great bat
          tle-drama, we can see the military salute of General Delord, as he waved hia hand, when
          the English batteries opened upon him. M. Quod, Ihe nom-de-plume of Mr. C. B. -Lewis of
          the Detriot free Press, has painted more truthfully and graphically the Battle of
          Gettysburg. In his glowing periotls, the whole scene is before us. I'ickot, with his long,
          (lowing curls, look ing like a knight of medieval chivalry, with aword waving in air,
          charging at the head of the columns; Arm isted and Harnett, flinging themselves in
          reckless abandon on the stone walls of a cemetery, as though they courted death, against
          the brave columns of Hancock. There throbs and pulses in every line the steady tramp of
          infantry, the clash of sabres, the shrieks of the dying, while above the smoke and
          carnage, there issued out of tho battle clouds the hand of Destiny which wrote with pen
          dipped in the blood and tears of a grand army the word of doom to the Confederacy. "Field,
          r'ort nnd Fleet" has not been a popular book, simply because truth lias not been the thing
          most desired. Historic falsehoods have usurped our public schools nnd we have believed
          historic fables till they have become a part of our lives. Lord Byron speaks iv one of his
          most beautiful poems of "tho Pontic monarch of old days who fed on poisons, and they had
          no power to kill but were a kind of nutriment." Are there not millions of Americans do ing
          tho same thing today? Colonel Dunkelberger says in his article: Lee crossed north of the
          Potomac twice; the ilrst time he romained thirteen days and lost about 30,000 men." Now,
          ono ounce of fact is worth a ton of conjecture. What are the facts? In the eighteen days
          of the Maryland campaign, which includes Harper's Kerry, Lee' army, never larger than
          40,000, fought the battles of South .Mountain, Tampion's Gap, Harper's Ferry, Antie tam
          and Sliepherdstown, losing in killed, wounded and captured 11.172, while Mc- CleM.au, wltb
          an army of 87,163. lost: killed, 20(12, wounded 11,719, captured 13,494, a total of
          27,87,"), against Lee's loss of 11,172. (See vol. I iiattles and Leaders and vol. 11, page
          (303. Colonel Dunkelberger says in his reply that "the second timo Lee crossed the Po
          tomac he remained seventeen days and lost 40,000 men." If the statistics of this article
          do not re fute the absurdity of tliis charge, then it would do no good lor me to add
          further ar gument. If these tigures are true, the fed eral goverm nen tough t to have had
          General Lee cross tho Potomac very often, as in the two crossings he had lost, according
          to Colonel Duukelberger, about 70,000 men. It senms to have been a repugnant idea to
          Colonel Dunkelberger that it took a larger number of federals to subdue a smaller number
          of confederates, This, I have no doubt, waa owing to the personal bravery of Colonel P.,
          who was perhaps equal to any one confederate he met in battle, but the fact remains that
          it did take a larger nuulber of federals to defeat a much smaller number of confederates.
          We refer to some historic truths: General Grant had, in the first day "a light at Shi loh,
          41,54:1 effectives, while General Beau regard had only 38,773 effectives, and yet he drove
          Grant from every position, and night found him cowering under the pro tection of the
          gunboats on the river. General McClellan had, six days before the lights opened around
          Bichinond, 15(1, --838 as total present, and 115,102 as lit for duty; yet General Lee,with
          an army of from 82,000 to 85,000, drove him from ail his positions bock forty miles to the
          shelter of hia gunboata. Afterward General McClellan attacked Lee at Antietam with 87,163
          veterans, and Lee with leas Ur>n 40,900, drove him from the Held and remained all the nex
          day on the battlefield, and the second nigh crossed over into Virginia. Kurnslde, on
          December 13th, had 110, 083 present; at lacked Gen. Lee at Freder icksburg with 58,500
          present (gee vol. 3 p. 143, Battles and Leaders.) In this Ugh the Federals had a majority
          of 58,183 ant their total loss was 12,053, while Lee's total loss was 4201. General
          Hooker, on April 30th, crosset the Rappahannock with an army preset! equipped of 133,708
          and 104 pieces of artillery, and General Lee met him witl an army of from 55,000 to
          110,000 (vol. 3 Battles and Loaders.) Hooker in severa desperate battles was driven from
          the flelc and across tho river, losing a total of 17. --287, while total loss was 12,403
          (See Battles nnd Le.idets, vol. 3. p. 233.) General Grant crossed the Rappahan nock with
          11M.000 veterans, and was con fronted by Lee witli 02,000. In thirty days Grant's total
          loss was 61,144. (See Battles and Leaders, volume 4, pages 184 nnd 185.) Do tiot these
          great battles show that an equal number of Federals were never a match for the same number
          of Confeder ates? We will not give the reason why. The facts are known to every, reatler,
          anit was a knowledge of these facts which let! General Buell, the coumander of the army of
          the Cumberland, the Blocker, who met Grant's cry under the river bank at Bhiloh of, "Help,
          CassitM, or I sink and threw into liia dispirited and disheartened tanks 2 1,570 effective
          men. antl this turned the tide against Ihe Confederates. This General Buell, a brave Union
          general, thus speaks in an article entitled East Tennessee and The Campaign of Perryvllle,
          * 81, vol,
          3, Battles and Leaders "A philoso
          phical study of our civil c inflict must
          recognize that Influence of some sort opei
          nted fundamentally for the side of th"
          confederacy in every prominent event«f
          the war. They are Involved iv tho fact
          that it required enormous sacrifices for
          24,000,000 of people to defeat die political
          scheme of 8,000,000; 2,060,000 soldiers
          to defeat 800,000, a naval fleet and
          15,000 troops to advance against a weak
          lort manned by leas than 100 men at Fort
          Henry .35,000, with naval co-operation, to
          overcome 12,000 at Fori Douelson;
          •10,000 to overcome 10,000 at
          Shiloli; 120,000 to enforce the
          retreat of 65,000, entrenched, after a
          month's maneauvering at Corinth; ioo,
          --000 repelled by 80,006 in Ihe peninsula
          campaign against Richmond; 70,000 with
          a powerful naval fotee for nine months
          against 40,000 at Vicksburg; 90,000 to
          barely withstand the assault of 70,000 at
          Gettysburg; 115,000 sustaining a fright
          ful repulse of 00,000 at Fredericksburg;
          100,000 attacked and defeated by 50,000
          at Chansellorville; 83,000 field in check
          two days hy 40,000 at Antietam; 43,000
          retaining the field uncertainly againat 88,
          --000 at stone's river; 70,000 defeated at
          CbicktmaUga and beleaguered by 70,000
          at Chattanooga; 50,000 to defeat the in
          vesting line of 30,000 at Nashville, and
          lltmlly 120.000 to overcome 00,000 iv a
          year's strugg.e in Virginia."
          Pursuing mis same line of thought, Gen
          eral Palfrey, lor a long time the colonel
          of the Twentioth Massachusetts reg ment,
          in his volume on "An ietam and Freder
          icksburg," says on page 125: "Did the
          southern men tight better than the north
          ern men, and if they did, why did they?
          These questions are interesting, but they
          are also difficult, and should ba answered
          with diffidence. There oan be no
          doubt about the proposition that greater
          results were habitually achieved by a cer
          tain number of thousands or tens of thou
          sands of Lee's army than by an equal,
          number of the Army of the Potomac. The
          reason for this ia not to be found in any
          diiference of patriotic teal in the two
          arniie*. The first reason probably was
          that the different modes of life at
          the south and at the north, made
          the son hern soldiers more fond
          of fighting than the northern men.
          Not lo mention the intcuser and more pas
          sionate nature, an I the comparatively
          lawless (not to speak invidiously life at
          the tomb, where the population was scat
          tered, and the gun came ready to hand,
          made the southern man upter soldier than
          the peaceful, prosperous, steady-going re
          cruit from the north. Tbe southerners
          showed that they felt the gaudium eer
          tamiii's—with the northerner it was differ
          ent. Tney were ready to obey orders;
          they Were ready to do the work to which
          they had set iheir hands; th?y were ready
          to die in their tracks, if need be, hut they
          did not go to battle as lo a feast. Wiih
          officers and men it was the same. They
          did not like fighting. Sheridan, Hancock,
          Humphreys, Kearney, Custer, Barlow and
          such as they were exceptions, but the rule
          was otherwise.
          Another reason may probably be found
          in the needy condition which was common
          among the southerners. Their stomachs
          were not seldom empty, their backs and
          feet ill-clothed and ill-shod, while the
          northern soldiers were abundantly pro
          vided with everything.
          These are not our words, but the words
          of two most distinguished generals of the
          United States army.
          We have backed up every fact we have
          used in this article, by a reference to the
          authority and page, and if Colonel Dunkel
          berger or any of his critical friends wish to
          c.v.mino these authorities, we will bo glad
          to show the book and page, now in tbe city
          library.
          We accept all the results of the war
          fully, and we are certainly entitled to de
          mand that the truth shall be told about
          what was done.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045450/1854-10-25/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=gettysburg</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85040303/1842-11-02/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=gettysburg</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038518/1854-09-13/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=gettysburg</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-gregory-rasputin</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045433/1912-02-25/ed-1/?sp=22&amp;q=Gregory+Rasputin+russian+czar+peasant+romanoff+alexis+guseva+yusupov+heliodorus+trufanoff+monk&amp;r=0.538,0.67,0.497,0.652,0#
        </id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          RASPUTIN CONTROLS CZAR;
          DOUMA FEARS ASTROLOGER
          His Influence Over Nicholas Said to Menace Welfare of Russia.
          ...
          Rasputin, whose antecedents are obscure, and whose origin, it is believed, is most humble,
          is now installed in private apartments in the Winter Palace.
          He is busy consulting oracles, the stars, cards, summoning spirits, gazing into crystals,
          pretending to seek to learn what this year of fate holds for his credulous master.
          ...
          Russia may hang on the word of this mystic steeped in superstitious lore.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045433/1913-05-24/ed-1/?sp=10&amp;q=Gregory+Rasputin+russian+czar+peasant+romanoff+alexis+guseva+yusupov+heliodorus+trufanoff+monk&amp;r=0.177,0.222,0.289,0.379,0
        </id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          Gregory Rasputin, one of the brightest stars of the Russian court circles, is the son of a
          poor peasant, and belongs to the "Chlysty" order of the austere preachers who flagellate
          their bodies and preach privation as the only method of expiating sins.
          ...
          Rasputin made a deep impression upon both the Czar and Czarina on account of his marvelous
          memory.
          He can recite whole chapters of the Bible by heart, and invariably answers questions
          addressed to him by apt quotations from the Scriptures.
          ...
          He now edits a paper, for the acquisition of which the minister of finance voted him a
          special grant of 300,000 roubles.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025316/1914-07-14/ed-1/?sp=5&amp;q=Gregory+Rasputin+russian+czar+peasant+romanoff+alexis+guseva+yusupov+heliodorus+trufanoff+monk&amp;r=0.246,0.035,0.402,0.527,0
        </id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          MONK OF MYSTERY IS STABBED BY GIRL
          ...
          The mystic lay monk, Gregory Rasputin, a notable figure in the emperor's court, was
          stabbed recently by a woman named Guseva, at his native village Pekrovsky, in the province
          of Togolsk, Siveria.
          ...
          The attack upon Rasputin has excited intense interest in court and official circles here.
          He was recently recalled to the emperor's household after an absence of several months,
          and was credited with exercising an influence over the emperor far more potent than any of
          his ministers.
          ...
          He was also unfrocked by the holy synod, an action which threatened to split the Russian
          orthodox church.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87062268/1914-07-26/ed-1/?sp=16&amp;q=Gregory+Rasputin+russian+czar+peasant+romanoff+alexis+guseva+yusupov+heliodorus+trufanoff+monk&amp;r=-0.1,0.03,0.482,0.632,0
        </id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          RUSSIAN MONK THE ABSOLUTE MASTER OF CZAR
          CLAIMED THAT NO GREAT EUROPEAN COURT IS NOW UNDER SUCH MYSTIC SWAY AS IS EMPEROR NICHOLAS.
          ...
          This act had aroused the antagonism of the powerful heads of the church.
          It is with those big ecclesiastics that Rasputin will now have to deal in holding his
          position.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026925/1914-08-14/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=Gregory+Rasputin+russian+czar+peasant+romanoff+alexis+guseva+yusupov+heliodorus+trufanoff+monk&amp;r=0.158,0.685,0.433,0.567,0
        </id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          IS RUSSIA'S REAL RULER
          Illiterate Siberian Monk Said to be
          Power Behind the Throne in Czar's
          Realm.
          While Rasputin was visiting his
          family recently in his native town of
          Krekovksy, province of Tobolsk, Si
          beria, a woman named Guseva plunged
          a dagger into his abdomen. She wished,
          she said, to put an end to the awful
          evil wrought by this man in Russia by
          his impostures and intrigues under the
          guise of prophet.
          Rut Rasputin will recover. And when
          lie does, woe to his enemies! He
          blames it all on Heliodorus, abbot of
          Esaritsyn, whom Rasputin, by his inlluence,
          drove from the imperial court.
          Rasputin will live, he declares, in spite
          of Heliodorus; and he will take a terrible
          reckoning.
          Since the spring of this year keenest
          watchers of the Russian skies have
          taken a second long look at Gregori
          Rasputlin. This strange, quiet personality,
          unobtrusive and yet conspicuous,
          used to be the target mainly for scandal
          mongers and for the vast number
          of Russians who are disgusted at the
          character of the dominant intluence
          in the czar's household. Rut recently
          people of harder liber?ambitious men
          high in the councils of the empire?
          who are struggling and scheming
          against one another, and the ablest
          members of the foreign embassies, who
          are seeking to trace the motive springs
          for the working of the czar's will, tind
          in Rasputin their most absorbing problem
          The politically ambitious ay him
          court by sending their wives to the
          receptions arrangi d by his devoted followers.
          The diplomats must glean
          what they can from the outside, for he
          does not cultivate the acquaintance oi
          foreigners. None of them but would
          admit that the half illiterate Siberian
          peasant exercises greater sway over
          the mind of the czar and his sovereign
          decisions than did the austere and exalted
          l'obedonostzoff, procurator of the
          Holy Synod, over the stern policy of
          Alexander III.
          Middle sized, middle aged?he is
          about 48 years old?of spare, wiry
          frame, letting his light brown hair and
          beard grow freely in peasant fashion,
          Cregori Rasputin holds attention til
          lirst sight by his remarkable nose and
          eyes. His gait and his dress are those
          of the devout, humble lay brother and
          Scripture reader, which is the Russian
          social type to which lie approximates.
          Rut his large, strong, well-set nose is
          that of a man of commanding will and
          authority, and he has the large, bluegray
          eyes of the seer who will not be
          drawn into discourse on the plane of
          ordinary mundane affairs.
          Some men have a kind of magnetism
          other than that which manifests itself
          on the intellectual or spiritual side of
          the personality. It may be exerted,
          physically, in the form of animal magnetism,
          in the "laying on of hands" to
          allay nervous torture, and even in such
          healing processes as osteopathy or
          bone setting. The most competent objective
          psychologists who have studied
          Rasputin declare that he possesses this
          animal magnetism to quite an amazing
          degree, and that as a dynamic human
          organism he is a phenomenon.
          Much in Russian tradition favors the
          periodic appearance of some such wizard
          and soothsayer. These may be
          charlatans for the most part, but now
          and again they prove to be something
          more. To say that the world has outgrown
          them is quite erroneous as regards
          Russia.
          Among the scattered pastoral villages
          around Tomsk, where Rasputin
          lirst began to exercise his strange
          power nearly twenty years ago, the
          conditions of daily life and the vocabulary
          in which the people exchange their
          thoughts are not essentially different
          from what they were two or three centuries
          ago, nor so very different from
          the early ages when a Peter the Hermit
          could inspire a crusade.
          None of Rasputin's followers thus
          far, whether dupe or devotee, has come
          fooiirnivl in hie hniir of L'rcnlnpsS to de
          nounce him as an impostor. Such a
          one would assuredly run no risk if he
          did, for Rasputin is most cordially
          hated both by the police and the press
          censorship. To people familiar with the
          habits of Russian life it would have
          sounded incredible a year ago had they
          been told that the government bureaucracy
          and the radical intelligence
          would ever agree on anything. Yet today
          they are as one in their antagonism
          to Rasputin.
          In a recent Duma debate a much-respected
          leader of the Liberals, Mr.
          ICphremoff, declared "that the highest
          affairs are settled in the highest
          spheres by an obscene charlatan." The
          press censorship allowed this to be
          published broadcast, and the crown
          prosecutor has taken no action. The
          campaign against Rasputin is allowed
          to proceed publicly on lines which
          among decent Russians are far more
          Biilnrarolvn i,f povepencp fur t h*> throne
          than anything that is secretly circulated
          from the revolutionary printing
          presses.
          The political hatred directed against
          Rasputin is based on the fact that he
          is the incarnation of irresponsible, oneman
          power, the result being the absolute
          repudiation not only of constitutionalism.
          but of the actual administration
          and bureaucratic system, or indeed
          of any system at all. He has
          checked, nonplussed and baffled the
          clever men in the governmental machine
          and the wily men in the Holy
          Synod. In the duma, some weeks ago,
          Mr. HilinkofT read a letter of the present
          procurator of the Holy Synod, Mr.
          Tabler, in which the latter thanked
          Rasputin for allowing him to retain his
          high office! Tabler denounced this as
          malicious tattle, but he did not deny
          the specific allegation.
          The only minister of the czar who
          showed open enmity to Rasputin was
          Kokovtzoff, and Kokovtzoff had to go.
          Wandering about the corridors of
          Tsarkoe-Selo palace in felt slippers,
          like the most intimate member of the
          household, Rasputin waited for Prime
          Minister Kokovtzoff to come out from
          an audience in the czar's cabinet, and
          said to him quietly:
          "Well, how much hast thou stolen
          today?"
          KokovtzefT flushed angrily and moved
          off, but he could neither say nor do
          anything.
          A few weeks ago a governess of the
          czar's youngest daughters was standing
          at their chamber door at bedtime.
          Their father had gone into bid them
          good night. Rasputin was about to
          follow when the governess barred his
          way, saying that the young grand
          duchesses were retiring for the night.
          Rasputin made no reply, but forbore to
          enter. The czar, when he came out,
          thanked the governess for her watchfulness
          over his daughters, but in less
          than a week she was given notice that
          her services were no longer required.
          Each step of Rasputin's progress has
          been taken with the help of women
          devotees. He has a quiet, well-modu
          luted, "warm" voice, and uses at all
          times the archaic "thee," "thou"
          phraseology of the Bible?which sacred
          book, except for a few simple devotional
          works of the old Orthodox
          church, is the only literature he has
          ever read. First in western Siberia,
          and later along the Volga, he used to
          sojourn as Scripture reader in the
          houses of the provincial merchants*
          and others of the peasant class who
          had prospered in a worldly way. These
          men would often have money enough
          to be able to indulge their wives in any
          luxury, but the simple elementary
          life in those remote districts provided
          no means of relaxation. The women
          would frequently drop into the state of
          nervous depression which is the common
          malady of idle rich womankind
          the world over.
          'I'lw.n frnm htillsolinli] til household
          spread the rumRasputin.
          the Scripture reader, had the marvelous
          secret of dispelling this restless,
          nervous feeling. Kastward from Moscow
          he attained some fame as a "healer"
          anion? bourgeois religious circles.
          It was part of Rasputin's practice to
          use absolute patriarchial directness in
          his talk with his women followers, no
          matter what the subject discussed
          might be. The simple words he used
          in relation to the elementary facts in
          human life would sound coarse to cultured
          ears. He believed, moreover, in
          the "laying on of hands," and practiced
          it literally. This reputation proved
          nothing in his disfavor, and he advanced
          into the more select circles as
          the center of religious assemblages.
          A lady of the Karnovitch family,
          whose sister is now Countess Hohenfelsen,
          murgantic wife of the Grand
          Duke Paul, first brought Rasputin to
          St. Petersburg. There was not much
          pretense of religious pietj about her
          salon, but the "healer" was cultivated
          as a new diversion in a blase existence.
          In fact, the guests looked on
          him somewhat in the light of a spiritual
          medium, although Rasputin has
          always repudiated any suggestion of
          "seances" or of hypnotism. His absolute
          sway over many people, especially
          women, and notably the empress,
          and their passiveness under the spell of
          his personality undoubtedly partake in
          the broad sense, of hypnotism. Hut
          Rasputin practices none of the hocuspocus
          of the craft.
          Rasputin's enemies charge that he
          holds and makes silent use of certain
          ambiguous messages from the empress
          indicating his complete dominion at
          the palace of the czar. He was introduced
          there by iMme. Vyrbova, the wife
          of a naval officer and the most intimate
          of the empress' ladies-in-wait
          ing. He goes two or three times a week
          to the palace, remaining from morning
          till night, and is sent for by telegram
          whenever the court moves from one
          place to another. In every direction
          his influence is felt. The dowager em
          press, however, is an avowed antlRasputinite,
          and since the "monk's"
          sway set in she has rarely seen her son
          the czar, or her daughter-in-law except
          at public ceremonies.
          The crowning miracle of Rasputin is
          this: He has moved the empress, who
          for nearly twenty years that she has
          shared the Russian throne has cared
          for nothing outside of her domestic affairs
          and who has not shown the
          slightest intellectual curiosity about
          anything, into an ardor of political interest
          sympathetic to that in which the
          czar is acting and working, neither
          through his ministers nor the people,
          hut through a Siberian peasant who
          can scarcely write his own name?an
          avowed mystery man who represents
          absolutism incarnate. Neither the imperial
          bureaucracy nor the elected legislature
          has been able as yet to bring
          Nicholas II., into definite light as a
          reigning sovereign. And now, under
          the will of a human enigma, behold
          this same sovereign autocrat emerging
          and asserting the authority that bewilders
          alike the defenders and the
          enemies of his throne!
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058396/1914-08-15/ed-1/?sp=19&amp;q=Gregory+Rasputin+russian+czar+peasant+romanoff+alexis+guseva+yusupov+heliodorus+trufanoff+monk&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.309,0.003,1.496,1.496,0
        </id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          THE STANDARD MAGAZINE SECTION OGDEN, UTAH, AUGUST H
          TiW'.-C.ar of .,11 ih. Russia is
          onli-tlie first lieutenant in tho ruK-i -sKlp
          jot"K usui. i The ponor behind
          thlItCCn1' of the greatest of all ab-
          soqJejrL'ui opcan monarchies. Is a
          iSlberjan and that .Siberian Is only
          a fWWint monk who until l v.
          year a?u ministered t" the lowly
          of His. province and two women
          who .came under the spell of his re
          ligious teachings
          The story ot" this strand- author
          Hlty of the most despotic nation of
          the Cauca.cion o ld i a me out w Ih :i
          ia few weeks ago Czar Nicholas or
          dered his court physh Lan, I rof.
          Sergius. -Pet rov itch Kederoff to Tyu-
          men, Siberia, to attend the monk.
          On th $ame trnin rode the lad in
          waltinjj to the Lmpn The monk,
          t Gregory- Rasputin, is suffering from
          ft severe' wound inflicted by a wom
          an v hc tried to kill him.
          Till- (soman Gusc-va. the would-
          aas4fUnj declared to the police
          Lnd newspaper orrespondentl 1 1 I
          -ehe h.ul lout, uo dilated killing Ras
          Hputln and thus put an end to "the
          awful evil wrought by him In l:us
          Hsla by his Impostures under the
          jguise of a prophet."
          She declared "he hail shaken
          H Christianity, was sowin,- tempta
          tion anl was blasphemously mock-
          it is all that cursed Heliodprus,
          Abbot of Tsaritsyn. Hut to the on
          fusion of himself and all my ene
          mies I will live and they will h i
          nooses put around their necks.
          Heliodorus was a great rival of
          Rasputin in the Russian capital,
          whence he was reiently banished,
          owing tfi Rasputin's influence with
          the Emperor.
          Rasputin is recovering from his
          wound.
          CZ iRTN IMPRESSED
          Bl OCC1 Ut POM ERS
          It is a curious story, that of the
          monk Rasputin, and one which has
          been told only In scraps. Two
          years ago hi- bobbed up in sudden
          prominence because his prophecies
          and spiritualistic seances had
          ome to the attention of the Czar.
          Not only dlil Nicholas take much
          stock In him, but the Czarina was
          Impressed by his occult powers, ami
          uulte like the obscure hero of the
          Cairy books. Gregory Rasputin
          found grand dukes and cabinet
          mlnlateve kowtowing to him. He
          had free access to the royal fwmlly,
          and the Czar of all the Russia
          asked his, advice on all sorts of im
          portant affairs of State. So great
          is his Influence that he has been
          styled the real ruler of Russia.
          A .-k ten of the monk whi. h wa-
          prlntcd In the Novoc Vrcmya, the
          semi-official Russian newspaper.
          and suppressed before It rained
          general Circulation, aives an Inter
          esting insight into the man's char
          acter. T l;nw Rasputin," declared the
          wi id r, "and 1 can speak about! him
          from toy own Impressions. SasOtlOV
          brought this 'saintly old monk' to
          me at the height of his glory about
          two years ago. The old monk aiued
          with me and W bad a long discus
          sion. 'At flrt he appeared to me as a
          rather youthful peasant about
          10, neatly dressed His face was
          that of a drunkard and his Vest less
          Attempted Assassination
          of the Peasant Monk
          Rasputin, Reveals dBi
          the Fact the Czar P
          Goes to Him for Di- lfc-i-" m
          rection As to Affr
          ssfB? EasH
          V
          f y'-i log- trie most hob fi elln ;a of true
          nehesers." and she added that 'he
          v enjoyed a!. .-oii.t.' immunltj and had
          openly a nd 1 1 houi con ciencc
          i j rulin;,l II,.- lives ot ourin' girls."
          r I. as a simple Christian, could
          j, j not suffer this abuse of the church,
          l I vant'-d to kill him In I ea I
          fWent. to Yalta, bul could not ap
          l j proach him becausi In was so
          closely surrounded bj urlstoci itic
          women followers
          "I regret that I failed to kill him.
          n '-ll the same, he will not live. The
          Rusi-i.in peopb v.. ii nol end such
          1,1 Kdlsgracc
          jjB a-'-putln. In nn inter lew, said:
          JKisiaL cRviler
          e.N'es, his low voice, resembled those
          of a monastery servant or a psal
          mist. His speech win abrupt and
          he used at times mjflterlous expres
          sions. "At first i surprised lhat
          sinh a half suae peasant from
          Siberia could not only find his way
          to st. Petersburg, but that he could
          find a welcome reception at the
          homes of the very highest society.
          After having spoken t" Rasputin,
          i convinced mysell that he. knew
          how to produce an Impression. He is
          a natural philosopher, coming from
          th- depth.-, almost Illiterate, but
          well learned In Soripturei a man
          who a Iks about religion like a
          grn mophone record and endowed
          with natural enthusiasm.
          "Some of his rayinps Im
          pressed me for their orljrinalitv
          nnl -ven for their depth. Thus the
          oracles of old spoke in a stats
          of delirium there was some
          thing absurdly wise in his enig
          matic words. Some of Rasputin's
          ideas seemed to me to be near the
          ai etic and stole philosophy, and
          his hara terlxatlon of some priests
          and dignitaries struck me as very
          keen and correct. The first Im
          pressdon made upon me was a Kuod
          one I thought he was a cunning
          peasant, but naturally religious,
          capable of makinc: people wake
          from their lethargic sleep as far
          as faith was concerned. Rut I did
          not like so much his fancy boots
          and the fait that he was going
          from my house to call on a certain
          1 n d
          REQUIRED TO CAM,
          n t I KTAIN LADY.
          should very much like to re
          maln In mir house.' he said to me.
          but I hove been invited to go there
          a nd I must go.'
          "1 was also surprised that Ras
          pulln kissed ladles' hands ou bid
          ding them good-bye. A rathfr
          Strange saint. I thought, one of
          those that occasionally make their
          appearance in fashionable drawing
          rooms. 1 had heard some ot my
          friends praising Itasputln, but soon
          strange stories about Rasputin be
          gan to reach me.
          "Then Rasputin lost the confi
          dence ,,f ths Well known Bishop
          Toy fan win. bad hrst patronized
          him. A certain prominent lady
          even went to Siberia for the pur
          pose of Investigating the stories
          about his mode of life and found
          evidence to corroborate them. The
          Left newspapers branded him as
          a swindler and a tharlutun such as
          tho world had not seen before, and
          fit one time It seemed as though
          bin Influence had waned. Suddeuly
          he came back to me last summer
          from Jerusalem
          "This time he was no longer
          dressed quite so neatly as before.
          He told mo about a tree that Lot
          had planted and aided that tho
          cross upon which Christ was cruci
          fied was made from that same tree.
          "Gregory needed the legend of
          the tree of Lot to pro e to me that
          although Lot was a sinner, his sin
          w.i- lorgiven. as Christ was crucified
          for us and thus redeemed all of the
          Sins of the world Crcgory needed
          this in order to answer my ques
          tion: is it true. Gregory, that you do
          not lead a very pure life
          "He answered evasively, 'The
          people arc slandering me. They
          are telling many falsehoods ahou
          me.'
          lie added that perhaps he was
          a sinner, that all people were sin
          ners, but that It was necessary to
          understand things properly
          BISHOP C U.I.n IIIM
          ENUI T Vt 9ERPENT.
          ne day Bishop Oermogen said
          to ',regor Rasputin. So you know.
          Gregory, 1 used to look upon you
          as upon a holy man; now I regard K:
          you as an enticing serpent! I for- IS,
          bid you to enter the home of an IE
          orthodox family.' nf
          "Grecory felt offended at this.
          but paid no heefl to the nlshop's Blm
          word? When the question arost at
          the holy synod as to having 'ircsrory fig,,
          ordained as a priest Bishop Ger- fflfc"
          nioL-cn rose up against hltn, rnri it S.
          was at this point that the Bishop
          had his downfall. I
          "The almost Illiterate, dissolute I
          monk proved to be a great power in
          these days of the twentieth century. i-
          When we are entertalnlnR lords and I
          eentlemen. scientists and authors t
          in St. Petersburg''
          The monk's affairs with women
          seem to have been Innumerable. I
          and he wielded preat Influence over I
          the wives and daughters of nobles S
          and officials high in the Russian c.v
          court. Stories of midnight prayer Wy
          meetings, to which only young worn- EV;
          im
          en were admitted, are told, and now 11
          Kasputln turned out all the lights IH
          and the "services" continued until
          morning. Rasputin is said to have II
          been the avenging power behind the IM
          ritual murder'' case at Kief. nh n
          except for worldwide publicity, the J
          Innocent Jew Mendel Bellis. would
          in all probability have been done to HH
          death as a victim of religious HHJ
          hatred.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1916-12-03/ed-1/?sp=37&amp;q=Gregory+Rasputin+russian+czar+peasant+romanoff+alexis+guseva+yusupov+heliodorus+trufanoff+monk&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.197,0,1.393,1.393,0
        </id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          WHO IS RASPUTIN?
          O.v VT r? By LUCIAN SWIFT KIRTLAND K.
          LJIX niftnthsairn. tt'hnn \lr. kirthum J ?nnnur?. hi?? TKm?
          left for Russia, we asked him to
          find out and write for us the real
          truth about Rasputin, the mysterious
          monk who is said to be the power
          behind the Russian throne. Mr.
          Kirtland was granted exceptional
          facilities for securing information:
          we believe his article to be the first
          really authoritative statement of the
          facts published in America. It is a
          story of fascinating interest a figure
          out of the fourteenth century influencing
          the destinies of a twentiethcentury
          nation. We shall see in the
          next decade a mighty conflict between
          the forces of progress in Russia,
          strengthened by the present war, and
          the forces that in the past have been
          responsible for Rasputin and the
          medievalism which he represents.
          The Editor.
          I MISSISD having dinner with Rasputin
          by one day. Every intricate
          detail had at last been arranged. Although
          reported to lie visiting friends
          in Siberia, Rasputin had come to Petrograd,
          and was to have been motored in a
          closed car to a private apartment for the
          dinner. Since the attempt on his life, last
          spring, in one of the exclusive eating
          places of fashion, ho now never appears in
          a restaurant.
          For six weeks I had manceuvered,
          reaching for this wire and theu for that,
          ill U II T l__ 1I...1 T 1 J il. _ A
          uiuu iinany 1 Knew iiun i null me rigm
          one?for in Russia every one ean be
          readied by some wire. The point was,
          to find the man whom Rasputin could not
          deny, and then to find the man who could
          bring pressure on that man. Fortuitously,
          1 found that third man, and then I knew
          that I was well ou my way to Rasputin.
          And then, with the last detail completed,
          1 was called away t wenty-four hours too
          soon. By the space of that one day I
          missed meeting the most interesting character
          in Russia?the great, towering
          monk, Gregory Rasputin, who from behind
          the throne of Muscovy for the past
          decade lias held in the mercy of his
          power the dictation of the weal of the
          Empire.
          It is neither necessary nor discreet to
          say who my acquaintance was, nor who
          it was that knew Itaspntin. Emphatically
          it is necessary to omit tolling the intrigue
          of the pressure that was brought to
          hear. But the man who knows Rasputin
          1 is perhaps the only man who has ever
          really known the monk intimately, and
          who has ever been his confidant. He
          promised to toll me, as a prelude to the
          dinner, tho secret of just who Rasputin is,
          and to reveal the mystery of how he arose
          to his power.
          To get to my informant's house I was
          led from tho sunshine of the broad, roughly
          cobbled street into a court-yard, and there
          we found a door leading to a long tlight of
          dark stairs. We climbed until just under
          the roof, and nressed a hell. Ktons enme
          and a door was unlocked. Wo slipped in
          quickly, as if there were furtive eyes
          watohing. Where the trail of Rasputin
          reaches there is always clandestine slyness.
          The man himself came to thedoor.
          He pushed open a door and led us through
          some rooms until we came to an inside of
          f i i i
          I^Bmi
          ji..
          m
          mm
          flee, a musty place crowded with heavy, sa
          rich furnishings. as
          A hove the desk hung a picture of Rasputin.
          Our host reached up his hands to ar
          each side of the frame and looked into the kt
          eyes. yc
          "The eyes are of fire,'' he said, "living yt
          fire!" in
          Most men hate Rasputin, hut many or
          obey his commands, as do almost all sh
          women. ne
          "Look at those lips," he continued? in
          "the thin lips of a master. No; you see, be
          they are not thick, stupid, sensual lips.
          And now look at his eyes. Look deeply, di
          and maybe you will understand something ht
          of tlwi t?ni?
          Hp sat down at thp desk and talked th
          across it toward me. be
          "How eould a moujik," he began, "an wi
          ignorant peasant born in the heart of sw
          Siberia?how do you suppose that such sp
          a man could rise in proud Russia to be a 111
          1 >owpr greater even than the throne? I lei
          tell you again: it was his tire, his sensuous loi
          bursting passion of life. He can dissipate av
          the enn ni of a jaded court and not be ye
          drained. He has wits, but so have thou- rii
          """"I;
          HMMggraHr
          ^Hhh
          nds. His presence rekindles dea
          hes. They are subjugated by his powe
          "Yes, Rasputin was a moujik, a pea
          it. Everybody knows that; but tht
          low little more. They think he
          >ung. He is not. He was born fifty-tw
          >ars ago, born in the province of Tobols
          a little village, tie uvea in a nouse i
          le room, where they all slept in reekii
          eepskins on the stove in winter, and
          iw-cut hay above the cattle in the sur
          er. Was that a beginning for sleepii
          'tween silken sheets in a palace?
          "Rasputin was big and strong, but 1
          dn't like to work. He liked to talk at
          liked to quarrel, and he stirred up h
          spiration for talking and quarreling i
          e vodka shop. Are thinking heads
          found in such a village to match one
          its against? There was nobody to ai
          er his questions. And, in his hig
          irits, he rebelled and wrangled an
          ade trouble. Everybody for miles aboi
          trued who Rasputin was. including sue
          :'al noblesse as is mustered in such a fa
          ray province. At first he amused the:
          ikt'l aristocrats by his boisterous rove
          >s and strange moods, but they couldn
          iiuuugv U?1? iuuj nuuicu 111111 w uc a
          buffoon, but he was too much their master.
          He made a mockery of his superiors,
          and victims of the women. When the
          village grew too narrow a field for his
          adventures,howandered awayas a pilgrim.
          "Rasputin had never had a day of
          schooling, and he had the direst ignorance
          of anything that he might find in the
          outside world, except what his priest had
          told him of big cities with great churches,
          and of monasteries and convents and holy
          places. It was the betrinnine of an eduea
          tion to make his way from village to village,
          trying tho mettle and temper of strangers
          with his questions and high spirits. You
          can picture him when ho reached Moscow,
          tramping around and around the great
          churches and palaces with open mouth
          and staring eyes.
          "He saw that men had done bigger
          things in the world than he had ever
          dreamed of. He docided that reading and
          writing must have had something to do
          with this power. A Rasputin does not
          have to look long in this world for teachers.
          He has had many. Amidst various hotblooded
          ud ventures he found time to watch
          fair fingers point out the letters of the
          alphabet.
          "Rasputin's development seems always
          tn hnvfi nrlvnnpoH inmnc Maoaaw ?_
          ceived him uncoutli, uneducated, and
          untamed. He had had only the most
          shadowy ideas of the power and organization
          and the dogma of the great Russian
          Church. Something in the refinement of
          the city and the art of the wonderful
          churches began to smooth away the outside
          of his uneouthness. The paradox of
          it all was that Moscow was now a disappointment
          to his new moods. Incredible
          ?yes; but this central Siberian moujik
          was demanding something from the great
          Moscow churches that they could not
          give. Rasputin told his friends that the
          church lacked passion. Their answer
          was that the materialism and commercialism
          of a great city had engulfed the church
          ?that he should go to Kief if he wished to
          finH linlinpsa iinonntA?ninnt.AH
          "Again he picked up his pilgrim staff.
          At Kief he found another great city; but
          the atmosphere was narrow and bigoted.
          For a time he thought that this bigotry
          meant life. But a man of Rasputin's keen
          senses can not long be fooled by the specious,
          and he was soon angered by the
          corruption that he found. Possibly?who
          d can deny??this hot-blooded, intemperate,
          r. riotous, desirous wanderer was honestly
          s- seeking some unfaltering purity of relig>y
          ion as a salvation outside himself against
          is the raging fires within, the very fires which
          o later were to carry him to the pinnacle
          k, of power and might,
          of "He heard of Holy Mount Athos, and
          lg again he took up his wanderings. Again
          in he found pettiness. Pilgrims were going
          t ?f
          11- liU UWUSttlClU. Xi.%3 JUIUCU IUOI11. a oaiu
          lg that Rasputin was impressionable. Xow
          came the second great evolution in his
          lie life. It came from the sea. To this child
          id of the steppes, the expanse, the colors, the
          is storms, the peace, the majesty, the power,
          ?t and the mystery affected him as someto
          thing new and revolutionary from Qod's
          i's hand. The effect upon his life was treii
          mendous. He ceased being a simple
          ;h mottjik upon a quest, he himself not half
          i,l L-nnu'inor whnt ho u-whod to find. He had
          it been struck with the conviction, the reve h
          lution. that if lie could feel this inspiration
          r- of the sea, which others could not feel
          so until his words and his fire discovered the
          1- treasures for them, he must then l>e |>os't
          sessed of powers which they did not
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1917-01-03/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=Gregory+Rasputin+russian+czar+peasant+romanoff+alexis+guseva+yusupov+heliodorus+trufanoff+monk&amp;r=0.063,0.042,0.346,0.453,0
        </id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045211/1917-01-03/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=Gregory+Rasputin+russian+czar+peasant+romanoff+alexis+guseva+yusupov+heliodorus+trufanoff+monk&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.02,0.195,0.632,0.632,0#
        </id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          RASPUTIN'S DEATH
          ENDS INTRIGUES
          Slaying of Monk Closes Life
          of Conspiracy and
          Mystic Power
          NOBLEMEN ASSASSINS
          Act Believed to Be Connected
          With Treachery of Pro-
          Germans
          LONDON, Jan. 3.
          All detnlla contlnuo tn romo Hi from I'd
          ..fcgrad nbout tho vlolrnt tlonth of the Tttis
          Han monk Haniiutln. tlioy wpnvr HipmRPlvM
          Into a tnlo which rivals the moat fantastic
          f-lcco of fiction.
          Uasputln, who Is pnlil to bp Iho ennfoxnr
          of both tho Hii'sl.in ("inr nml Ui Cznrinn,
          li now reported to have boon ulnln by n
          Kusslan notilemnli to hide rt ncnriitat In
          VolvltiB powerful members of the UMIntt
          ccurt.
          The body win hidden In tlit Nnva tllvcr
          tut was later recovered
          On Friday night two young men, both
          members of the highest circles of Husslnn
          tioblllty. accompanied by another, whoso
          r.amo Is said to be notorious throughout
          tho nusslan Kmplre for his Intrlguos. drovo
          In n limousine to a house owned by Prince
          Yusupoff-SuninrokofC IJIston. About 3
          o'clock on Saturday morning shots were
          lieard in tho garden of tho house. Soon
          rftcrward two big motorcars drove up to
          tho house, one pnsslng into tho gnrden.
          Tho authorities, having been Informed of
          2
          tho shooting, went to tho pln.ro anil upon in
          vestigation found blood upon tho snow. No
          body wns found, hnwever.
          Another version stated that two men were
          seen entering ono of the automobiles sup
          portinr a Ubii-p between them that was
          wrappid In a fur coat.
          Prlnro Yussupnff Is married to a second
          cousin of the I'zar. Ills wife. Princess
          Irene. Is a daughter of Urnnd Diitto Alex
          ander. WIKLDKD OURAY POWHIl
          Kasptitin. who regarded himself a mystic
          with divine powers, wielded greater Influ
          ncc al tho itusalsin court than any other
          man. Ho was feared even by the most
          powerful nobles. It has been Bald that lie
          was consultnl by tho f'zar on matters of
          lato and that he was In the highest coun
          cils on th.! evo of war.
          This is tho third time that report has
          coma out of Itussla announcing tho as
          sassination of the notorious mystic and
          adventurer, flrcpory Rasputin, who Is sup
          posed to have exercised such an Intluenco
          for evil upon the mind of tho Czar of
          Itussla. The first time was In July, 1911.
          when, exiled from Petrograd. he wns
          stabbed by Julia Humva at Tyumen, Si
          beria; then on May 11. lUlfi, his death wus
          reported from Iiucharst.
          It has been stated by those who have
          been In a position to penetrate tho do
          mestic surroundings or the Russian Im
          perial family that the Interest of tho I'znr
          In Rasputin wus purely that of an In
          vestigator, who used the mnk us a means
          to gather information from and at times
          to communicate with the m.iss of the people
          from whom his exalted birth and rank
          separated him. Kruni Itasputln. It Is said.
          Nicholas learned of the horrors of vodka,
          and Immediately set about to eliminate
          them.
          When Rasputin lay wounded In Tyumen
          In 1914 his Majesty sent to him the court
          physician, Professor Serglus Pctrovltch. It
          was then that Rasputin mudo this startling
          accusation against Illlodor, "the mad monk,"
          who Is now In Now York:
          "It Is all that cursed Illlodor. Hut, to
          the confusion of hlmsolf and my enemies,
          I will live, nnd they will have nooses put
          round their necks."
          When Interrogated, the Gusevu woman
          declared that she had attempted to kill
          Rasputin because ho had spread tempta
          tion among the Innocent. No connection
          could be established between her and
          Illlodor.
          SUSPECTED AS PRO-GERMAN
          The attempted assassination of last
          spring Is supposed to have been duo to
          political causes. Rasputin had been well
          autualnted with lit-neral W. A. Souk
          homllnoff, who was Russian Minister of
          War during the fatal campaign In East
          Prussia, when traitors were believed to
          have betrayed the Russian armies In the
          field anil left them without reserves of
          munitions at home. In Juno, 116, Souk
          homllnoff resigned and was later arrested
          end lodged in the fortress of Peter and
          Paul.
          Among the witnesses sought was Ras
          putin, who wus known for his pro-German
          sympathies. It was said that he
          had been discovered by the secret po
          litical police and would create u Bensu
          tion at the trial. Ueforo lie had a chanco
          to tesllfy, however, ho disappeared. Then
          came tho news of his assassination from
          Bucharest, which, however, proved false.
          His long immunity from arrest as a wit
          ness Is said to have been duo to a certuln
          clique of the Ministry, who, if not actually
          pro-German, were nevertheless working for
          a separate peace looking to a desertion of
          Kngland and France and a subsequent
          treaty with Germany.
          The completo reorganization of the Min
          istry under pressure of the Czar nnd'-'Duma
          alike, a month ago. changed all that. The
          trial of SoukhomllnolT was ordered, nnd
          Itasputln waa brought to Petrogrud. whero
          he lived under police surveillance, ready,
          It has been reported, to tell all he knew.
          Tho Czar first met Rasputin in 1805
          through tho Countess Ignatieff, wife of a
          former Governor of Hlberla, and much In
          terested In tho cult of the Chylsty's sect of
          flaggellants. which Rasputin was trying to
          revive. In the Countess's circle, where tho
          Czar waa then an occasional visitor, wcro
          the Montenegrin Princess Mllitza, wife of
          the Grand Duko Peter N'ikulalevltch Prlnco
          Putjatln. Court Marshal Count fieticken
          dorff. Prince Orloff, and. finally, General
          Soukhomlinoff.
          It has been said that when tho wur began
          the genuine Muscovites gradually droppt.il
          away from tho rlrrlii, leaving only Ilaltto
          Russians, with German IdeaB, behind, nnd
          that the circle then became the center of
          German propaganda to which tlrussilux re
          ferred in April. 19 m, when he took com
          mand of the southern Russian armies und
          said to the war correspondents:
          J I "Not a line can you wrlto from here
          vj.uct a message will go forth till something
          vfiappens- In Petrograd they have a switch-
          board with connections with lierlln."
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038411/1917-03-26/ed-1/?sp=9&amp;q=Gregory+Rasputin+russian+czar+peasant+romanoff+alexis+guseva+yusupov+heliodorus+trufanoff+monk&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.011,-748.822,1.021,1499,0
        </id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          RULED RUSSIA BY
          SUPERSTITION
          Mystic Monk Made Imperial
          Family Believe Heir's Life
          Depended on Him
          By Associated Press
          Petrograd, March 26. The super
          stitious belief that the health and even
          the life of Grand Duke Alexis, the young
          heir apparent, depended on the pres
          ence gf Rasputin, the mystic
          monk—a notion which is generally
          known to have accounted for Rasputin's
          tremendous influence over the Imperial
          family—ls explained In the following
          extraordinary manner by the Russky
          Slovo:
          Rasputin, according to the news
          paper, stated in confidences to friends
          at convivial moments that he was able
          to fortify this sunperstltlon with the
          help of Madame Virubova, lady-ln
          waiting to the Kmpress, and M. Bad
          maef, court physician, until the Em
          press absolutely convinced that the
          life of her son depended on the monk.
          Whenever Rasputin was absent for any
          length of time from the court, Madame
          Virubova, according to the monk's
          story as given by the newspaper, ob
          tained poisonous powders from the phy
          sician and placed them in food
          brought to Alexis. The result was that
          during Rasputin's absence the delicate
          health of the young heir apparent grew
          steadily worse until Rasputin was sum
          moned back to the court, when the
          powders were stopped and Alexis be
          came immediately better.
          Rasputin always announced that forty
          days after his death Alexis would fall
          ill. Tills prophecy came true with
          startling accuracy being caused, the
          newspaper declares, by Madame Viru
          bova administering another powder to
          the little Grand Duke in the hope of
          continuing the tradition of Rasputin's
          inHuence over the imperial family and
          oreparing the way for a successor to
          him.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85053058/1917-02-24/ed-1/?sp=13&amp;q=rasputin
        </id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          RASPUTIN, NOTED RUSSIAN MONK,
          WORKED FOR PF ACE WITH GERMANY
          AND HE WAS MYSTERIOUSLY SLAIN
          San Francisco, Feb. 24. Rasputin, n
          low-born peasant in the world's moat
          autocratic country, was a man of mys
          tery.
          He rose to wield a power that made
          ministries totter and which threw a
          shadow across the very' throne oi the
          Almost fanatically religious, his
          morals were of the lowest.
          Gregory Rasputin was horn in the
          little Siberian village of Pokrovsky, in
          Tobolsk. His father was wealthy, but
          a peasant -what in Russia is called
          "moujik." As a boy he was quarrel
          some, he would not work and did nut
          got an education.
          Most of Gregory's time was spent
          in the vodka shop, where he talked*
          much and loudly and picked us many
          quarrels as lie could. However, tin
          wits of the vodka shop in his native
          town soon became too dull to make it
          amusing for Rasputin to entangle
          them.
          He started on a pilgrimage. In
          every village lie drank vodka, mort
          than was good for him. At last he
          reached Moscow, where he found those
          i w ho could make him, with his ln« k of
          learning, seem ridiculous. He began
          I to learn to read and w rite.
          J Religion was his passion religion
          and women.
          He delved into the lore of the Rus
          sian church, journeyed to Kieff, to
          Mount Athos, to Jerusalem, then went
          to sea. Once back in Russia he be
          came a moujik priest, an unordained
          monk.
          salons of a
          rograd at w
          ter.«, sclent
          bled. At r
          with
          introduced him in the
          Countess Ignatieff in Pet
          hose receptions men of let
          e anti the church assent
          At once he began his Intrigues
          women, and, although he still
          miserable clothing and his man
          were at best uncouth, «tune of the
          beautiful women of Petrograd showed
          him marked favor, and more than one
          husband threatened him. Rut every
          thing Rasputin did was under cov er of
          religion.
          It la said by men who know that
          more than one woman of Petrograd,
          who could turn the hearts of the finest
          manhood of the city, washed the feet
          and kissed the hands of this shaggy,
          boorish monk in their religious fervor
          only sometimes the religious side
          was outgrown.
          Then came his first real opportunity
          for political power. The emperor was
          still without an heir. He was dis
          satisfied. There was talk of a di
          vorce, and the emperor and empress
          were seldom seen together.
          For the first time in many weeks
          they rode in the same carriage during
          a public ceremony. Suddenly above
          the thousands of cheers a «»ice boomed
          out
          "Thou shalt bear a son!
          It was Rasputin's vol» e.
          The c/.arinu half rose and then sank
          back in her carriage. Rut later she
          received the monk at the court in
          Petrograd. In less than a year alter
          his prophecy an heir was born to the
          czar. Rasputin's name was on every
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025316/1918-01-21/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=rasputin&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.697,0.428,0.198,0.508,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          Mat Rasputin.
          Before he could operate on the lielr
          to the Russian throne. Dr, Downer,
          who is an orthopedic surgeon, had to
          prove to the Russian royal surgeons
          that he was skilled in his practice. To
          do this he was assigned to the Imperial
          hospital nnd given soldiers lo treat.
          Due day he was summoned Io I he gen
          eral hospital and told to select Ids pa
          tients. The pnllents never arrived at
          the Imperial hospital. Instead, other
          wounded men who had passed the
          stage of recovery nnd who were injured
          In tlielr heads Instead of their arms
          nnd legs, as were the crippled soldiers
          the dorior selected, were sent to the
          Imperial hospital. Dr. Downer re
          fused these patients beennne he knew
          they were out of his line of treatment.
          But, he said, this move was tnndo by
          an opposing clique to discredit him
          with the empress.
          80011 after his arrival In the royal
          palace. Dr. Downer met Rasputin.
          Rasputin was the official lighter of the
          tallows at tin 1 altars In the rooms of
          the palace. That was his position ns
          known to the people. But in reality
          he was the czar of Hunsln. Whenever
          an act was wanted from the czar, Ras
          putin was called If other means failed
          to have the ruler sign desired orders.
          Rasputin Last Resort.
          These other means consisted of two
          things: Vodka and the wrath of a
          woman. When a pro-Oermun action
          was wanted from the Russian ruler
          the empress had tho papers ready for
          the czar's signature. Then shn would
          npply vodka In large quantities When
          thoroughly Intoxicated he would lie
          presented with the pa per* and asked to
          sign. Most times this syst« m worked,
          but occasionally It went wrong. Then
          the empress would fly Into a terrible
          rage nnd remain In n state of Intenso
          fury for a week or two weeks, after
          which time she again would approach
          her husband with the papers. Falling
          the second time, she would summon
          Rasputin. The papers would then be
          signed.
          Had Many Girls.
          Rasputin never moved about the pal
          ace but what, he had an escort of from
          1C to 20 young girls with him. One
          princess evaded him- It was lier
          husband who decided that the rule of
          Rasputin was reaching a too unbear
          able stage. This prince had his wife
          decoy the Black Monk to her home.
          When he arrived there Rasputin was
          met by the prince and a few followers
          and killed.
          Members of the Russian cabinet
          were so pro-German that they began
          starving the people In Petrograd and
          other places. The students began com
          plaining. Even the girl students aged
          between 18 and 20 joined the plots.
          80 when the officials of the govern
          ment began holding back shipments of
          supplies to the Russian armies the.
          women began stealing these supplies
          and hiding them in garrets and cellars.
          Arsenals and armories were robbed
          and the weapons obtained were hid by
          the plotting students.
          As the bread supply began to be cut
          down more nnd more, th
          the people rose to wrathful protests.
          Students who protested loudly were
          sent to the front. Here they preached
          I
          to
          murmurs of
          ---------------until
          day to day until said property is dis-
          posed of.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045211/1917-10-24/ed-1/?sp=23&amp;q=rasputin</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          CHAPTER II (Continued)
          T"THE time this incident took place Rasputin was already living
          V In St. Petersburg, whither he had repaired on the invitation of
          Ii&amp;ieof his admirers and protectors, who had the opportunity to listen
          to his prcacninga m ncu uuu uuier missian towns. Among them
          fi&amp;ired the Countess Sophy Ignaticff, a woman of high standing.
          Hrreoroachable reputation and great influence in some circles of the
          rMpital, where her salon was considered the center of the consciva
          .the orthodox pany. oisnops ana priests ngurcu among her daily
          victors, and it was among her habitues that the most important
          ecclesiastical appointments in the Empire were discussed. Often it
          K-.. ka c-iTirli'dntes whom she honored with Viir nrntnerinn Vi
          I g fclv f.... ..v. f ,.w (,VS tHIV
          Hchosen for a Bishop's place? or for that of a superior to one of those
          rich monasteries uiu neuus 01 wmca are quite personages in the
          lUte.
          The Countess was already an old woman, widow of a man who
          had been murdered duiing the 1 evolution of 1905, and, moreover,
          Incapable of being even suspected of any frailties of conduct. She
          .s the mother of a large family, and though by no means brilliant,
          was yet clever in her way, with a slight propensity to intrigue. She
          was extremely devout, with a strong tendency to exaltation where
          religious matters came into question, and was continuall lamenting
          twhatahc called the relaxation of modern society in those practices
          f strict church discipline which Russians belonging to the higher
          Ll.u.. linitn lofal.. (ltfM i r T rtV ref 1 1 r r Ct.n ...ai.1.1 fc I....... 1
          CUM" liaC ll.J tunwi ill lUi(V.UIII,i .jiiu vtuuiu IIUU 11UVC IIUSECll
          ffjitendine any of the long church services, sometimes so tirino- in
          f the Orthodox faith, which are celebrated on Sundays and many feast
          f. day?, and she strictly fasted at piescn'oed times. Indeed, her whole
          existence was, as regards its daily routine, more that of a nun
          than of a woman of the world. But for all that, she liked to keep
          herself well informed as to all that was going on around her, and
          politics was her especial hobby.
          Among those who frequented her house were Mr. Sabler, then
          Procurator of the Holy Synod, together with his future successor,
          jr Mr. Loukianoff; a good sprinkling of ministers she was distantly
          -.1.1. J AT- ol. r--t .1... 1 1 !J t.1 .t
          reiaieu iu .m. oiuijjhh.-, .1 jiiti, iuul uuu consiuurauiy anaea To licr
          Importance during the latter's lifetime and a few influential dames
          belonging to the immediate circle of friends of the imperial family.
          'AH this constituted n coterie that had gradually assumed perhaps
          I pore' importance than it really deserved, but that brought into St.
          I Petersburg society an clement with which it would not have been
          wise to trifle and which it was impossible to overlook, for any one
          fearing to concern himself or herself with the course that public
          tuairs were uiKing ana assuming.
          Illiodore and Rasputin
          A few years before the time I am referring to. that is about
          1903 or 1909, a good deal of interest was excited not only in St.
          I merDurg, out in tnc whole ot itussia, by a monk called Illiodore,
          Who also preached a new gospel to those willing to listen. There
          toas, -however, about him none of the peculiarities which distin
          guished Rasputin, nnd no one had ever found one word to say against
          Us morals. But he tried also to found n religion of his own in the
          sense that he attempted to develop on a higher scale, and with
          I certain Protestant leanings, the feelings of fervor of the people.
          At aaraton, where he uvea, he did a great deal of good, and he
          had built there a large church, orthodox, of course, which soon
          became a center of pilgrimage to which flocked thousands and
          thousands of people desirous of hearing him aid of listening to his
          Inflamed speeches. They reminded one of those crusades that in the
          E Middle Ages had stirred whole nations to rise and rush to deliver
          the Holy Sepulchre from the yoke of the infidels. He was far more
          a Peter the Hermit thun Rasputin, and had, moreover, education,
          which the other lacked.
          But ecclesiast.cal authorities in St. Petersburg did not approve
          f his teachings, and ho soon came into conflict with them, together
          rith the Bishop of Saratoff, who had all nlong supported him and
          who considered him as being really a good and pious man. Thi9
          conflict led to a quarrel, the result of which was that Iliiodoro was
          fonfined in a monastery, whence, however, with the help of his
          disciples and adherents, he 'contrived to make his escape. There
          was also a whole seiies of lawsuits, into the details of which it is
          pselcss to enter here. At last the monk was unfrocked for rebellion
          to hls superiors, by a decree issued from the Holy Synod, and com
          JHed to take back his secular name of Traufanoff. He became
          fearful of further annoyance and managed to get hold of a false
          passport, with the help of which he made his way into Norway,
          (Copyright. 1017. Pub lie Ledger Company. All rlcfcts rctcrted
          "Rasputin and Illiodore, Russia's two greatest mystics of the twentieth century,
          were in time to become mortal enemies; but at first a great friendship united them,
          and when Rasputin was sentenced to enter a convent Illiodore took up his cause most
          warmly.
          alalaSiiaflGBa5BH.H iJK'SL'9
          aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaalxaaalkf KHaal 'I taaaaaaH tHxaaa. xHft' lUl B
          aaaaaaaaaaHaaaaaaHHaaaaaaaVlM$i3Hl)flaanlxlHl Vo5Hk JaRfeeCX'.f
          raaaaaaaaaHHau3HlaaKSfcmakCr&amp; 4'T JAilrtB&amp;ik- JwlTaBWVa"aKBaaaaaaaHaaab -BaaafTaV.
          ktiW
          naaaaaaaaaaaHaaaaWDHaaaaaaUEiiBMTOMtJn AflSakPK xaaflaaHaVWaaaaaOaaaBaaaW. .JaaaaaKHaPJ
          'Jl
          laaaaaalllllHBaHaaasHaaVaaa9aHaSalO!lBflxaii?ii
          J'VAxa&amp;rNjCnfClx&amp;UDPaBIaaaaaaNaaaai&amp;l aaaaaaaaH fLXo ETa?
          raaaaaaaaaaaaaaJBlaaaaBBgaaWMaMS StfWWWji-lJjglgiryaHK 0 ,jW f
          aaaaaWaiMaHllaaaaaaaaBlftaaaaaWBKcPftMa 'sfrR
          EiPIliiii llllii ill 1
          m&amp;!bmI VtlM lm
          RASPUTIN, MASTER OF CORRUPTION, AND "SAINT"
          'if.
          wit
          where he is still residing, and where we shall find him presently
          mixed up in a most extraordinary adventure with which Rasputin
          was concerned. But before all this had occurred there was a brief
          period when Illiodore was quite an important personage in Russia,
          and the salons of the Countess IgnatietF and of other ultra-devout
          ladies used to see a lot of him whenever he happened to be in
          St. Petersburg. These feminine listeners were very fond of him,
          and did their best to spread his reputation all over the capital.
          During Rasputin's wanderings he had come across Illiodore at
          Saratoff, and the latter, like so many others before and after him,
          had succumbed to the hypnotic spell which "Gricha" was casting all
          about him. He had believed him to be a real servant of God, and
          ho had engaged him to come to St. Petersburg and to preach there
          before some of the people who had already listened to his (Illio
          dore's) sermons.- He had introduced him to tho celebrated Father
          John of Cronstadt, this saintly priest who was so famous for his
          virtues and his good deeds. And, strange as it may appear, Father
          John also had been struck by Rasputin's eloquence and had believed
          him to be really inspired by the Lord. In older to explain the state
          of mind prevalent at the time among thj orthodox clcigy one must
          say that this clergy, or at least some important members of it, were
          trying to bring about a levival of religious fervor in the Orthodox
          Church, especially among persons belonging to the upper classes,
          who had, during the last twenty-five years or so, become moie than
          indifferent in regnrd to spiiitual matters, and who had considered
          religion more a qjestion of "convenience" than anything else. Since
          the religious eensorship had been suppressed and books to any
          amount treating of every conceivablo subject had been allowed to
          circulate freely in the country, the former attachment to Mother
          Church had waxed fainter and fainter, until this Church appeared
          In the eyes of many as simply n question of good breeding, to which
          it was necessary to conform when ono belonged to good ooclctyj
          but which, beyond this, wns treated entirely as a matter devoid of
          importance.
          In view of thi3 fact, those prelates nnd dignitaries of the Church
          who Inmcntcd over this state of things were not sorry to find that
          there were still In the world people capable of arousing in tho mlndn
          of others nn interest in religion and religious matters. This explains
          partly why tho craze which seized some persons 'In regard to Illlo-'
          (lore nt first nnd to Rasputin later on wns not viewed with the
          dissatisfaction one might hnve expected by tho Russian ecclesiastical
          authorities. They nrgued that surely it was better for people to
          pray in the way these two so-called "saints" told thcirf to do than
          not to pray at all. It was only much later, after Illiodore'a rebellion
          to the orders of his superiors, nnd Rasputin's ever-growing personal
          influence had begun to alarm them, that there were found some
          bishops in Russia who made n stand against both, until at last a
          cntnstrophc removed these two men from the scene of their previous
          labors and successes.
          Rasputin's "Exile" Begins
          Rasputin nnd Illiodore were in time to become mortal enemies,
          but nt first a great friendship united them, and when Rasputin was
          sentenced to enter n convent in tho manner already related Illiodore
          took up his cause most warmly nnd telegraphed to one of the for
          mer's admirers, nn ecclesiastic of high rank in St. Petersburg, In
          the following terms: "Neither Bishop Feofane nor Archimandrite
          Serge has behaved fairly in regard to tho 'Blessed Gregory.'"
          Illiodoie's efforts, however, did not nvnil and Rasputin was ordered
          to leave the capital immediately. But instead of being compelled to
          enter the convent whither they had wished to confine him at first, he
          was allowed to return to his nntive village of Pokrowskoie. Before
          doing so he bethought himself of calling on his former patron,
          Bishop Feofane, but the latter mot him with the exclamation, "Don't
          approach me, Satan! Thou art not a blessed thing, but only n vulgar
          deceiver!" At Pokrowskoie Rasputin surrounded himself with twelve
          sisters, of whom the oldest was barely twenty-nine years of age.
          They all lived in his house, which was extremely well arranged and
          lichly furnished. Rasputin's wife, together with, her children, was
          also there nnd occupied a suite of five rooms, whilst each of the
          sisters had n separate room to herself.
          People wondered that tho woman who ought to have been the
          sole mistress in the place had consented to share her authority with
          all theso girls, nnd some even thought that she was just as bad as
          her husband. In reality, the "Prophet's" consort had done all that
          she could to persuade her husband to gitc up the "mission" which he
          declared had been Imposed upon him by the Almighty and to return
          to his former life of a simple peasant. Her efforts had remained
          fruitless, and Rasputin had replied to nil her entreaties that his past
          existence had come former to an end nnd that he knewjiia star was
          about to shine in n wonderful way within a short time. He com
          manded his wife not to attempt to interfere in the matter of his own
          personal relations with the "Sisters" lhing under their roof. Though
          she tried to submit to his will, yet there were occasions when terri
          ble scenes occurred between husband and wife. Then tho latter
          would attnek violently tho girls, whom she accused of all kinds of
          dreadful things, nnd would then fall on the ground in attacks of
          strong hysterics, screaming so dreadfully that people heard her from
          tho street. But tears nnd submission were equnlly of no avail and
          Rasputin did not trouble about his wife's rage or grief any more than
          he had troubled in general with any other impediment he had found
          in his way. As concerns tho kind of life which the '"Sisters" wero
          leading at Pokrowskoie this is how one of them describes it:
          It is now nlrcady six months since I am here, living in n
          kind of nightmare. I do not know to this day whether the
          "Blessed" Gricha is a saint or the greatest sinner the earth has
          ever known. I cannot find a quiet place in this miserable village.
          I w ould like to run away, to return to St Petersburg, but I dare
          not do so. I nm so afraid, so terribly afraid of the "Blessed" one.
          His lnrge, gray, piercing eyes crush me, enter into my very soul
          and absolutely terrify me. At n distance of 5000 worsts I feel
          his presence near me. I feel that he has got extraordinary
          powers, that he can do e cry thing that he wishes with me.
          For two whole years Rasputin was not allowed to show himself
          in the Russian capital, but tho influential friends he had there never
          left off trying to get the decree of banishment rescinded. Among
          others, the Archbishop of Saratoff, Hermogene, nnd Illiodore worked
          most actively in his favor, and the latter in ono of his sermons did
          not hesitate to call Rasputin the "greatest saint which tho modern
          Russian Church had ever known." At last the efforts of his friends
          proved successful and Rasputin, toward the end of the year 1912,
          reappeared in St. Petersburg, where this time his progress was far
          more rapid than it had been formerly, nnd here his reputation of a
          latter-day saint grew with every hour, until nt last he came to be
          looked upon as a real manifestation of the Divinity upon earth.
          It was about that time that he wns seen more frequently nt
          Tzarskoio Selo, where the poor Empress was eating her heart away
          in anxiety over tho health of her only son, tho little heir to the
          throne, whose dayh seemed to bo numbered. Rasputin, who had
          been introduced to her as a pious, good man, whose prayers
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045211/1917-10-27/ed-1/?sp=21&amp;q=rasputin
        </id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          Rasputin Became the Instrument of the Reac
          tionary Party, Which He, in Turn, Contrived
          to Make Instrumental in Carrying Out His
          Own Views and Aims, and There Are Many
          Indications That He Was Working in the
          Interests of the German Government
          SVNOrBIS or IMIKCKUIXCl IN8TAI.I,MnNTS
          4r ThePjriricfossRad'ziwiiL
          "When one reviews all one has heard concerning this personage on,e is tempted
          to ask the question whether his appearance in St. Petersburg had not brought along
          with it an epidemic of madness among all those who had come in contact with him."
          The carrrr of Urorr llaaputln. the "Itlark Monk of RuaMa
          can be compared to the life of n comer, both In Ita iihrnlcal fllclit
          acromi the aky and In Ita effect upon u childlike people nhoia ffultla
          I. bound up In nij.tlcl.m and tuurrMitlnu. Out of the ..I.IUlun of
          Hie amiill Mlberlij town l'okrnw.kole. Itnuputln nppeared on the
          horlion of nollllcnl Kunla and wielded nn Influence over the State
          and tliurih audi na liaa never been duplicated by a Chilian and a
          aman,
          There are man? atorlra conrernlnc the relationship exlMlnr
          brtneen Itanputln and the Kmprcta of Huaaln, but the author aava
          that the latter regnrded the 'nonk" merely aa a peraon ulio could
          ,r thy life of the alllns Tiarevltcli. That the Tropliet." or
          "lllraaeil tlreKory," an hla uetotera lalird him, d d wlelil a power
          fill Influence oier the Allnlatera and Court la emphonlred In
          example "ft" example. The time npell which he tact orer the
          moujlka" of hla natlte town brought the aoplilatlcatrtl ltuaalan
          noblhty under hla power. Dc.plte Ida fllthj, unkempt nnd revolt.
          lug appearance, they. In company with the unedututrd million,
          of pniMinta aiui tunpeopir. i.ecu.ne In lrol nwera,
          Itimputlii'a "creed" contained precept objectionable to the
          Orthodox Church and to the peroon not blinded hv III imMlrNm
          and after many unaucceaaful attempt, he waa finally "exiled" to
          bin old home. After two eor he returned to the capital, where
          he continued IntrlRUlnB again.! hla cnemlea. He hklllfully turned
          the mlnlaterlal crl.la BriiwliiB unt f luiuan Mar Into a
          i'uim aunjecieu ins women followera to
          Ihe deepe.t humiliation, but they nor.hlne.l I.I... il. m.I i.
          l!" i. I...... '""'""i among them ITmce l.wiff, former
          i rmaini .pi inn 1'uum, iieiiounceil lie "monk" Iilttrrli. TI..I.
          were quoted by the author.
          testimonial"
          I
          CHAPTER III Continued
          HAVE reproduced this tale because it seems to me that it helps one
          to understand the personality of Rasputin, and because it de
          scribes to perfection the manner in which ho used to treat the people
          with whom ho dealt. Personally, when I interviewed the "Prophet,"
          I had tho opportunity to convince myself that the impression which
          he had produced on Prince Lvoff was absolutely a correct one, and
          I made the same remark which the latter had done in regard to the
          total absence of this magnetic strength which Rasputin was supposed
          to possess over those with whom he entered into conversation. The
          man was a fraud and nothing else. He had been deified by the group
          of foolish people whom ho had persuaded that he was a messenger
          from Heaven, come to announce to Holy Russia that a. new Christ
          had arisen. But his pretended fascination existed only in tho imag
          ination of the persons who asserted its existence. To the impartial
          observer he appeared what he was an arrogant and insolent peas
          ant, who, knowing admirably on which side his bread was buttered,
          exploited with considerable ability to his personal advantage the
          stupidity of his neighbors.
          Rasputin "a Fraud and Nothing Else"
          I have already related that his house had become a kind of Stock
          Exchange in which everything could be bought or sold, where all
          kinds of shady transactions used to take place, and where the most
          disgusting bargaining for places and appointments was perpetually
          going on. Gifts innumerable were showered upon him which he
          pretended that he distiibuted to the poor, but which in reality he
          carefully put into his own pocket. This peasant, who when he had
          arrived in St. Petersburg for the first time had hardly possessed
          a shirt to his back, had become n very rich man. He had bought
          several houses, gambled in shares and other securities, and had con
          trived to accumulate a banking account which, if one is to believe
          all that has been related, amounted to several millions. Fiom time
          to time, however, he used to come out with some munificent offering
          to some charity or other with which he threw dust in people's eyes.
          They thought that it was in this manner that he employed all the
          money which was showered upon him by his numerous ndmirers. It
          was in this way that he built in St. Petersburg, not far from the
          jpot where by a strange coincidence h'is murdered body was found,
          a church which was called the Salvation Church, which adjoined a
          school for girls. There he used to go often. Whenever he went he
          was always met by the clergy in charge with great pomp, ns if he
          had been a bishop or some great ecclesiastical dignitary, and was
          awaited at the door with the cross and holy water. This church was
          placed under the special protection of the Metropolitan of Petrograd,
          Pitirim, who often celebrated divine service in it, nt which Rasputin
          always made it a point to be present. But instead of awaiting the
          Metropolitan, as he ought to have done, he had the habit of arriving
          after him. Mgr. Pitirim, however, awaited his arrival just as he
          would have waited for the Emperor. Indeed the submission which
          the official head of the clergy of ihe capital affected in regard to Ras
          putin is one of the most extraordinary episodes in the latter's wonder
          ful career.
          In fact, when one reviews all one has heard concerning this per
          sonage one is tempted to ask the question whether his appearance in
          St. Petersburg had not brought along with it an epidemic of madness
          among all those who had come in contact with him. It hardly seems
          possible that bishops, priests, ministers, high dignitaries, statesmen,
          even, or at least men having the 'pretension to be considered as such,
          should have thought it necessary to go and seek tho favor of this vul
          gar, ill-bred, dirty Russian mougik, devoid of honesty and of scruples,
          about whom tho most disgraceful stories were being repeated every
          where, and whose presence in the houses where he was a daily visitor
          used to give rise to the worst kind of gossip. This gossip was of
          such a nature that decent persons hesitated before repeating it, let
          alone believing it. Like an insidious poison it defiled all whom it
          touched. One fails to realize by what kind of magic grave men like
          Mr. Sabler, for instance, who for some time had occupied the highly
          responsible and delicate functions of Procurator of the Holy Synod,,
          one of the most important posts in the whole Russian Empire, could
          be made so far to forget himself as to prostrate himself before Ras
          putin in his eagerness to become entitled to the latter's good graces
          and prptection. And that he did so is at least not a matter of doubt,
          If we are to believe the following letter which the monk Illiodore
          wroto from his exile on tho fifth of May, 1914, to n personage very
          well known In tho political circles of St. Petersburg.
          "I swear to you with tho word of honor of an honest man
          that the letter in which I called Sabler and Damansky the instru
          ments of 'Grlcha' (Rasputin) contained nothing but the solemn
          truth, and I repeat it once more, that according to what Rasputin
          told to me on the twenty-eighth of Juno, 1911, at 3 o'clock in the
          afternoon in my little cell, Sabler really kts3cd the feet of Gricha,
          who, in relating this story to mc, showed me with an cxprcsshc
          pantomime In what way he had done so. I consider as utterly
          falsc and as a barefaced lie the declaration of Mr. Sabler that
          he had never prostrated himself before any one, except before
          the sacred images. Respectfully yours,
          S. M. TROUFANOFF, formerly the monk Illiodore."
          It is difficult to say, of course, how much rclianco can be placed
          creign the poison of their cnom and to represent us to those
          who do not know ut in n light which, thanks be rendered to
          God, is an absolutely false and untrue one.
          Russia is fnr too great for such things to touch her. That
          Germany rejoiced nt every tale which reached its ears in regard
          to Rasputin is evident if one reads its newspapers. That it was
          in understanding nnd nccord, if not directly with him, nt least
          with some of those who were his immediato friends and habitual
          confidants, has been proved to tho satisfaction of all impartial
          persons. And that ho worked continually towards establishing nn
          understanding between tho Tzar and the Kaiser is nnothcr fact
          of which more than one man in Russia is aware. Whethtr ho
          did so intentionally or whether ho wa3 the unconscious instrument
          of others cleverer and more cultivated than he over was or would
          become, is still n point that has not been cleared tip to tho
          "How daro you disobey my orders?" cried out an angry voice. "Thou pig and son of n pig, I
          have said I wish to see this person
          and no one else! Thou idle creature! Chuck him out of the room, that pig who dares to
          contradict mc and that comes in here!"
          on those assertions of Illiodore, nnd whether Mr. Sabler really
          thought it necessary to fall on the ground before Rasputin. But out
          of this letter one can infer that the influence of the latter was con
          sidered to be important enough for people to trouble themselves about
          relating stories of tho kind to show it up. Altogether, one may safely
          conclude, out of the very spare material which so far has come to
          light in regard to the activity of Rasputin, that wo have not yet
          heard the whole truth about the circumstances which have accom
          panied his sudden rise and fall, and that there must have been in both
          events things which perhaps will never come to light. But all of
          them point out to some dark intrigue in which ho was but one of
          the pawns whilst believing himself to be the principal actor.
          Rasputin became the instrument of the reactionary party,
          w hich he, in his turn, contrived to make instrumental in carrying
          out his own views and alms. His head had been turned by the
          unexpected position in which he had found himself. It is not sur
          prising that he lost his balance and that he ended by considering
          himself as being what he had been fold by so many different
          people that he was a Prophet of the Lord, having the right to
          say whatever he liked, to calumniate whom he liked, to make
          use of whateer means he found at hand to eliminate from his
          path any obstacles he might have found intruding upon it. His
          name became synonymous with that of this ultra-conservative
          party which was leading Russia towards its ruin, and which al
          ways contrived to reduce to nothing all the good intentions of the
          Tzar. Rasputin was a symbol and a flag at the same time; the
          symbol of superstition, and the flag of dark reaction. It is im
          possible to know to this day whether he was not also what every
          thing points to, that is, an agent of the German Government
          who had entered into German interests, and who had during the
          last months of his life been working together with Mr. Sturmer
          nnd the latter's private secretary, the famous Manassowitsch
          Maniuloff, towards a separate peace with the Central Powers, the
          conclusion of which would have dishonored forever the Tzar, to
          gether with his Government, and which would have provoked
          such discontent in the country that the dynasty might hare col
          lapsed under its weight.
          There exist at least indications that such a thing was within the
          limits of possibility, and, if so, those who put an end to the evil career
          of this dangerous man deserve well from their country, and the
          leniency which has been shown to them is but the reward for an act
          of daring which, though unjustifiable from the moral point of view,
          is nevertheless to bo condoned by the circumstanco that its patriotic
          aim was so great that it was worth while risking everything,
          even remorse, in order to accomplish it.
          In a certain sense, Rasputin was the curse of Russia.
          Thanks to him, the purest existences were subjected to a whole
          series of base attacks and of vile calumnies. Thanks to him,
          our enemies were given the opportunity to pour out upon us,
          upon our institutions, our statesmen and cen upon our sov-
          general satisfaction. But that his so-called influence only existed
          over certain weak people, and that the Tzar himself never know
          ingly allowed it to be exercised in matters of state, is a fnct
          about which there can exist no doubt for those who know the
          rare qualities of heart and of intellect of the sovereign.
          CHAPTER IV
          T HAVE quoted the impressions of Prince Loff in regard to
          Rasputin, and have remarked that I have had personally the oppor
          tunity to convince myself that they were correct, nt least in their
          broad lines. The interview which I had with Rasputin in the course
          of tho winter of 1913-14 left me with feelings nkin to those experi
          enced by the. Prince. This interview took place under the following
          circumstances: I had been asked by a big American newspaper to
          seo the "Prophet," whoso renown had already spread beyond tho
          Russian frontiers, and who was beginning to bo considered ns a
          factor of no mean importance in tho conduct of Russian state
          affairs. This, however, was by no means nn easy matter. For one
          thing, he was seldom in St. Petersburg. Ho spent most of his time
          at Tzarskoie Selo,' where his headquarters were the apartment of
          Mme. W. He used to mnke only brief and flying visits to the
          capital, where he possessed several dwellings. One never knew in
          which one he could bo found, as he used to go from one to another,
          according to his fancy. Ho gave audiences like a sovereign would
          have dono, and before any one was allowed to enter his presence
          that person had to bo subjected to a course of cross-examination so
          as to make quite sure that no malicious or evil designs were harbored
          by him in regard to the "Prophet."
          At last, after a succession of unavailing efforts, I chanced to
          light on a certain Mr. do Bock, with whom Rasputin had business
          relations, and for whom he procured when the war broke out an
          important contract connected with the supply of meat for the troops
          in the field. It was this personage who finally obtained for me tho
          favor of being admitted into the homo of Rasputin. The latter was
          living at tho time in a very handsome and expensive flat in a house
          situated on tho English Prospokt, u rather distant street in St.
          Petersburg, whoso proximity to the quarters of the working popula
          tion of the capital had appealed to the Prophet's tastes. When I
          arrived there, at about 4 o'clock in the afternoon, I was, first of all,
          stopped by the hall porter, who wanted mo to explain to him where
          and to whom I was going. Upon hearing that it was to Rasputin
          he insisted on my taking off my fur coat downstaiis, and then
          examined me most carefully and suspiciously, surveying with special
          attention tho size and volume of my pockets, so as to make suie that
          I was not carrying any murderous instruments hidden in their
          depths.
          Interview With Rasputin
          Upstairs the door was opened by an elderly woman with n red
          kerchief over her head, who, I learned afterward, was one of th
          "sisters" who followed the "Prophet" everywhere. She asked for
          After Several Futile Attempts to Be Granted mm
          Audience by the "Prophet," the Princtm
          Radziwill Obtained an Introduction Whltk
          Gave Her the Opportunity She Long Desired.
          She Found the t(Monk" Surrounded by a Uoat
          of Admiring Lackeys f
          my name, and then ushered me into a room, sparely but ricl
          furnished. There some half-dozen people were waiting, in' w3f
          seemed to mc to be extreme impatience, for the door of tho next
          room to open and admit them. Voices were heard through the doer
          angrily discussing something or other. Among tho people present I
          recognized n lady-n-wnlting on tho Empress, an old general i
          possession of an important command, two parish priests, three
          women belonging to the lower classes, one of whom seemed to be i
          great trouble, and n typical Russian merchant in high boots and
          dressed in the ong caftan which is still worn by some of those whe
          have kept the traditions of the old school. Then there was a little
          ahm ?Ut itC1 yCar8 ld' p0orly cUld' wh0 was "ytoff bitterly.
          u fCJVPe kpt S'lcnt' but 0,e caer "Passion on their face
          showed that they were all laboring under an intense agitation and
          emotion. When I entered the apartment n distent look of disappoint
          ment appeared on all their faces. At last tho old general approach!
          mo and asked me in moro or less polite tones whether I had a special
          card of admission or not, vmu
          "What do you mean?" I inquired.
          "Well, you see," ho said, "we all who are in this room have got
          one, but there"-and ho pointed with his finger to the adjoining
          door- then, jit the people who have come hero on the chance, just
          to try whether Gregory Efimitsch will condescend to speak to them.
          Some have been sitting there since last night," he significantly added.
          And as he spoke he slightly pushed ajar tho door he had mentioned.
          I could see that n room, if anything smaller than tho one we were in.
          was packed full of persons of different ages nnd types, all of whom
          looked tired. They were sitting not only on the few chairs which
          the npartmcent contained, but also on the floor. Thero were women
          with children hanging at their breast, military men, priests, monks,
          common peasants and two policemen. The lost named were seated
          by the window leisurely eating a piece of bread and cold meat, which
          they were cutting into small slices with a pocketknife. They had
          evidently made themselves nt home, regardless of consequences or
          of the feelings of other people. Suddenly we heard another door
          slam, and a strong step resounded in the hall. A man began to speak
          in a loud voice. He said: "You just go to see and here the
          jiamo of one of tho most influential officials in the Home Office was
          mentioned, "and you tell him that Gricha has said he was to give
          jou a place, and a good one, too. It does not matter whether there
          is none vacant, ho must find one. There, take this paper, and now
          go, and don't forget to show it when you como to the Home Office."
          The door slammed again, nnd all remained silent for a few
          minutes. Then the elderly woman who had admitted mo came into
          the npartment where we were sitting and beckoned me to follow
          her. But this proved too much for the feelings of tho old general
          who had accosted me on my entrance, and he pushed himself for
          ward in front of mc, exclaiming as he did so:
          "I have been here a longer time than she has been," pointing
          nt me with his finger, "and I must get in first."
          "You cannot do so," replied the woman; "my orders are to let
          this lady in first."
          "Do you know who I am, woman?" screamed the general at the
          top of his lungs; he was evidcntily in a towering passion. "Go at
          once, nnd tell Gregory Efimitsch thnt I must see him at once, I have
          been waiting here for more than an hour."
          "I cannot do so," replied the woman, "I must obey the orders
          that have been given to me."
          "Then I shall do it myself," exclaimed the general, and ho
          rushed toward the door, which he opened, when he was stopped
          by a whole torrent of invectives coming from the next room.
          "How dare you disobey my orders?" cried out an angry
          oicc. "Thou pig and son of a pig, I have said I, wish to seo this
          person and no one else! Thou idle creature! Chuck him out
          of the room, that pig who dares to contradict me and that
          comes in here!" And the tall. figure of Rasputin appeared on
          the threshold of the room. He rudely pushed aside the general
          and, seizing my hand, pulled me into another apartment, which
          seemed to be his dining room.
          It was a rather large corner room with three windows, in
          which stood a quantity of flowers and green plants. A round table
          iiccupieu mc miauie, on wnicn was laid a striped white-and-red
          tablecloth. A samovar was standing on it, together with glasses
          on bluc-and-white saucers, slices of lemon, sugar in a silver sugar
          basin and quantities of cakes nnd biscuits. Chairs were placed,
          on one of which Rasputin sat down, facing the tea urn, after having
          mado me a sign to do likewise. I noticed that thero was a large
          writing table in one corner littered with books and papers.
          The "Prophet" himself did not at all strike mc as being
          tho remarkable individual I had been led to expect. He must
          have been about forty years old, tall and lean, with a long
          black beard and long hair, falling not quite down to his back,
          but considerably lower than his cars. The eyes were black
          singularly cunning in their expression, but did not produce, t
          least not on me, the uncanny impression I had been told they
          generally made on those who saw them for the first time.
          Tho hands were the most remarkable thing about the man!
          They were long and thin, with immense nails as dirty as dirty"
          could be. He kept moving them in nil directions as he spoke,
          sometimes folding them on his breast and sometimes lifting
          them high up in the air. He wore the ordinary dress of the
          Russian peasant, high boots and the caftan, which, however,
          was made of the best and finest dark-blue cloth. What could be
          seen of his linen was also of the best quality.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026925/1914-08-14/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=rasputin
        </id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          IS RUSSIA'S REAL RULER
          Illiterate Siberian Monk Said to be
          Power Behind the Throne in Czar's
          Realm.
          While Rasputin was visiting his
          family recently in his native town of
          Krekovksy, province of Tobolsk, Si
          beria, a woman named Guseva plunged
          a dagger into his abdomen. She wished,
          she said, to put an end to the awful
          evil wrought by this man in Russia by
          his impostures and intrigues under the
          guise of prophet.
          Rut Rasputin will recover. And when
          lie does, woe to his enemies! He
          blames it all on Heliodorus, abbot of
          Esaritsyn, whom Rasputin, by his inlluence,
          drove from the imperial court.
          Rasputin will live, he declares, in spite
          of Heliodorus; and he will take a terrible
          reckoning.
          Since the spring of this year keenest
          watchers of the Russian skies have
          taken a second long look at Gregori
          Rasputlin. This strange, quiet personality,
          unobtrusive and yet conspicuous,
          used to be the target mainly for scandal
          mongers and for the vast number
          of Russians who are disgusted at the
          character of the dominant intluence
          in the czar's household. Rut recently
          people of harder liber?ambitious men
          high in the councils of the empire?
          who are struggling and scheming
          against one another, and the ablest
          members of the foreign embassies, who
          are seeking to trace the motive springs
          for the working of the czar's will, tind
          in Rasputin their most absorbing problem
          The politically ambitious ay him
          court by sending their wives to the
          receptions arrangi d by his devoted followers.
          The diplomats must glean
          what they can from the outside, for he
          does not cultivate the acquaintance oi
          foreigners. None of them but would
          admit that the half illiterate Siberian
          peasant exercises greater sway over
          the mind of the czar and his sovereign
          decisions than did the austere and exalted
          l'obedonostzoff, procurator of the
          Holy Synod, over the stern policy of
          Alexander III.
          Middle sized, middle aged?he is
          about 48 years old?of spare, wiry
          frame, letting his light brown hair and
          beard grow freely in peasant fashion,
          Cregori Rasputin holds attention til
          lirst sight by his remarkable nose and
          eyes. His gait and his dress are those
          of the devout, humble lay brother and
          Scripture reader, which is the Russian
          social type to which lie approximates.
          Rut his large, strong, well-set nose is
          that of a man of commanding will and
          authority, and he has the large, bluegray
          eyes of the seer who will not be
          drawn into discourse on the plane of
          ordinary mundane affairs.
          Some men have a kind of magnetism
          other than that which manifests itself
          on the intellectual or spiritual side of
          the personality. It may be exerted,
          physically, in the form of animal magnetism,
          in the "laying on of hands" to
          allay nervous torture, and even in such
          healing processes as osteopathy or
          bone setting. The most competent objective
          psychologists who have studied
          Rasputin declare that he possesses this
          animal magnetism to quite an amazing
          degree, and that as a dynamic human
          organism he is a phenomenon.
          Much in Russian tradition favors the
          periodic appearance of some such wizard
          and soothsayer. These may be
          charlatans for the most part, but now
          and again they prove to be something
          more. To say that the world has outgrown
          them is quite erroneous as regards
          Russia.
          Among the scattered pastoral villages
          around Tomsk, where Rasputin
          lirst began to exercise his strange
          power nearly twenty years ago, the
          conditions of daily life and the vocabulary
          in which the people exchange their
          thoughts are not essentially different
          from what they were two or three centuries
          ago, nor so very different from
          the early ages when a Peter the Hermit
          could inspire a crusade.
          None of Rasputin's followers thus
          far, whether dupe or devotee, has come
          fooiirnivl in hie hniir of L'rcnlnpsS to de
          nounce him as an impostor. Such a
          one would assuredly run no risk if he
          did, for Rasputin is most cordially
          hated both by the police and the press
          censorship. To people familiar with the
          habits of Russian life it would have
          sounded incredible a year ago had they
          been told that the government bureaucracy
          and the radical intelligence
          would ever agree on anything. Yet today
          they are as one in their antagonism
          to Rasputin.
          In a recent Duma debate a much-respected
          leader of the Liberals, Mr.
          ICphremoff, declared "that the highest
          affairs are settled in the highest
          spheres by an obscene charlatan." The
          press censorship allowed this to be
          published broadcast, and the crown
          prosecutor has taken no action. The
          campaign against Rasputin is allowed
          to proceed publicly on lines which
          among decent Russians are far more
          Biilnrarolvn i,f povepencp fur t h*> throne
          than anything that is secretly circulated
          from the revolutionary printing
          presses.
          The political hatred directed against
          Rasputin is based on the fact that he
          is the incarnation of irresponsible, oneman
          power, the result being the absolute
          repudiation not only of constitutionalism.
          but of the actual administration
          and bureaucratic system, or indeed
          of any system at all. He has
          checked, nonplussed and baffled the
          clever men in the governmental machine
          and the wily men in the Holy
          Synod. In the duma, some weeks ago,
          Mr. HilinkofT read a letter of the present
          procurator of the Holy Synod, Mr.
          Tabler, in which the latter thanked
          Rasputin for allowing him to retain his
          high office! Tabler denounced this as
          malicious tattle, but he did not deny
          the specific allegation.
          The only minister of the czar who
          showed open enmity to Rasputin was
          Kokovtzoff, and Kokovtzoff had to go.
          Wandering about the corridors of
          Tsarkoe-Selo palace in felt slippers,
          like the most intimate member of the
          household, Rasputin waited for Prime
          Minister Kokovtzoff to come out from
          an audience in the czar's cabinet, and
          said to him quietly:
          "Well, how much hast thou stolen
          today?"
          KokovtzefT flushed angrily and moved
          off, but he could neither say nor do
          anything.
          A few weeks ago a governess of the
          czar's youngest daughters was standing
          at their chamber door at bedtime.
          Their father had gone into bid them
          good night. Rasputin was about to
          follow when the governess barred his
          way, saying that the young grand
          duchesses were retiring for the night.
          Rasputin made no reply, but forbore to
          enter. The czar, when he came out,
          thanked the governess for her watchfulness
          over his daughters, but in less
          than a week she was given notice that
          her services were no longer required.
          Each step of Rasputin's progress has
          been taken with the help of women
          devotees. He has a quiet, well-modu
          luted, "warm" voice, and uses at all
          times the archaic "thee," "thou"
          phraseology of the Bible?which sacred
          book, except for a few simple devotional
          works of the old Orthodox
          church, is the only literature he has
          ever read. First in western Siberia,
          and later along the Volga, he used to
          sojourn as Scripture reader in the
          houses of the provincial merchants*
          and others of the peasant class who
          had prospered in a worldly way. These
          men would often have money enough
          to be able to indulge their wives in any
          luxury, but the simple elementary
          life in those remote districts provided
          no means of relaxation. The women
          would frequently drop into the state of
          nervous depression which is the common
          malady of idle rich womankind
          the world over.
          'I'lw.n frnm htillsolinli] til household
          spread the rumRasputin.
          the Scripture reader, had the marvelous
          secret of dispelling this restless,
          nervous feeling. Kastward from Moscow
          he attained some fame as a "healer"
          anion? bourgeois religious circles.
          It was part of Rasputin's practice to
          use absolute patriarchial directness in
          his talk with his women followers, no
          matter what the subject discussed
          might be. The simple words he used
          in relation to the elementary facts in
          human life would sound coarse to cultured
          ears. He believed, moreover, in
          the "laying on of hands," and practiced
          it literally. This reputation proved
          nothing in his disfavor, and he advanced
          into the more select circles as
          the center of religious assemblages.
          A lady of the Karnovitch family,
          whose sister is now Countess Hohenfelsen,
          murgantic wife of the Grand
          Duke Paul, first brought Rasputin to
          St. Petersburg. There was not much
          pretense of religious pietj about her
          salon, but the "healer" was cultivated
          as a new diversion in a blase existence.
          In fact, the guests looked on
          him somewhat in the light of a spiritual
          medium, although Rasputin has
          always repudiated any suggestion of
          "seances" or of hypnotism. His absolute
          sway over many people, especially
          women, and notably the empress,
          and their passiveness under the spell of
          his personality undoubtedly partake in
          the broad sense, of hypnotism. Hut
          Rasputin practices none of the hocuspocus
          of the craft.
          Rasputin's enemies charge that he
          holds and makes silent use of certain
          ambiguous messages from the empress
          indicating his complete dominion at
          the palace of the czar. He was introduced
          there by iMme. Vyrbova, the wife
          of a naval officer and the most intimate
          of the empress' ladies-in-wait
          ing. He goes two or three times a week
          to the palace, remaining from morning
          till night, and is sent for by telegram
          whenever the court moves from one
          place to another. In every direction
          his influence is felt. The dowager em
          press, however, is an avowed antlRasputinite,
          and since the "monk's"
          sway set in she has rarely seen her son
          the czar, or her daughter-in-law except
          at public ceremonies.
          The crowning miracle of Rasputin is
          this: He has moved the empress, who
          for nearly twenty years that she has
          shared the Russian throne has cared
          for nothing outside of her domestic affairs
          and who has not shown the
          slightest intellectual curiosity about
          anything, into an ardor of political interest
          sympathetic to that in which the
          czar is acting and working, neither
          through his ministers nor the people,
          hut through a Siberian peasant who
          can scarcely write his own name?an
          avowed mystery man who represents
          absolutism incarnate. Neither the imperial
          bureaucracy nor the elected legislature
          has been able as yet to bring
          Nicholas II., into definite light as a
          reigning sovereign. And now, under
          the will of a human enigma, behold
          this same sovereign autocrat emerging
          and asserting the authority that bewilders
          alike the defenders and the
          enemies of his throne!
        </text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-1904-presidential-election</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87093407/1904-06-21/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Republican+Convention+Theodore+Roosevelt&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.06,0.171,0.632,0.632,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          REPUBLICAN CONVENTION
          GETS DOWN TO BUSINESS
          O. P. LEADERS ORGANIZE THE 810 LOVE FEAST AT CHICO
          CO— ROOSEVELT'S NAME OR EETEO WITH TREMENDOUS AP
          r*LAUSE
          (By Betlie. New* Assn.)
          CIUCAOO. Jun* IL—With Hag*
          flying, ban-is playing and amidst a
          i-rfci t din of hurrahing th* He pub*
          llean natl"iwl conventlun ctuivnied
          in th* Coliseum shortly after noon
          today.
          Till eovetillon hall presented
          brim*tn seen* of color. Hanging
          a sort .1 canopy abov* Ihe single
          gallery long featonned strips of red.
          whit* and blue bunting atrrtchett
          from en,l to end on ii *ld* ef the
          vast ainplthaater Prom point
          wh.ie the tin..' was caught up
          w.i* suspended a tars* hanging Baa-
          Bet filled with graceful ferns. Abov*
          every second —a* there waa taste
          fully arranged a group of five Amer
          ican flags ii Ihe bosom ef who**
          folds reposed picture of President
          •nusri.it between these stand* of
          flaga bough* of trees w*re placed.
          Ul* green foliage affording plea*
          ant relief to the ry*.
          Ta* steel t; t |*rs on the way to
          the roof were entwined with green
          foliage an l each gtrder bore anothrr
          portrait of the preatdenL
          At the south end of th* hall on a
          temporary stand was the First regl
          sej,, po,Mmt,, At th* north *nd wss
          strung a large placard announcing:
          "t'nder thla banner Harrlaoß snd
          Klnlt r were twice nominated."
          Aa turner oil painting of the
          Ist* Senator ltanna. lighted from
          abov* by •lextrtclty and draped
          TUB .TEMPORARY CHAIRMAN OP THfl RK!*L*RtrtGAN CONVKN*
          TIUN IH l.*(-M.i:i.|-TAII V OK Wall 1.1.i1l RuOT.
          HAS TROUBLES OF HIS OWN
          U. S. Senator John C. Sjiooncr.
          with flags, was suspended directly
          over the speaker's pint form, In. Ii
          was finished In dark flemish oak,
          .Hi the exception of the chair an.
          desk of the presiding officer, whit
          was mahogany.
          Vice Chairman Payne waa *up
          plscd with two gavels, one great
          mullet time im In* In -meter an 1
          six Inches lung a "storm gave!."
          and th* other for ordinary condi
          -1 tions, a handsome little affair of
          rt'-.i-»eHi.l. decorated with a gold
          band and bearing the name and ti
          tle, similar to the gatrl provided for
          Temporary Chairman Hotel and
          Permanent Chairman Cannon.
          The officers of Ihe convention
          matte it" appearance on the
          platform at I* In o'clock it telle
          very few prupl* w*r* in th*
          hall. About i I o'clock th* Coli
          seum began to tiii. Ih* eartteat
          arrivals being four women alter*
          natr* from Idaho, Utah and Colora
          do, Half an hour later not nmri
          than 'ii delegates were In their aeala
          The first full delegation to appear
          a** that from Delaware, under Ad
          dicks' Irat'erahlp,
          The Oklahoma men with tin.
          breroa came nesL
          The first applause of Ih* day from
          the galleries ..in. with the advent
          ef a party nt iowait* with Bcnator
          Altlaon al Its head,
          sen ,i>.i. |r, vt *nd Cullon wer*
          the recipient* of applause, which
          doubled few minute* later when
          LEADING FIGURES IN THE LIMELIGHT AT THE BIG G. 0. P. BLOW-OUT AT CHICAGO
          The Seattle Star
          IKAI M I VVASIUNQTON.TUI.SDAY, JUNK $8, 1904
          Uncle Jo* I'allium *nteied with t'or
          neltu* ltlUs.
          At 11:41 o'clock 1.-tin e-t. r tleti
          eisl Pa>ne, presiding officer, until*
          111. Wat/ In the |.l.it fin 111, iii.i.tti
          lieiii.il by Trni iMirnry I'ti.lrmnn
          Itttot and every ott* lit th* hall Joined
          Vn greeting them with cheers.
          The Mr!, gules now cam* In droves
          and In in minute* nearly all were
          present, but th* galleries tsete nut
          half full. K»w i. 11. wer* pt**ent
          compared with previous run vent Inn*.
          '1 tie first real enthusiasm cum*
          when Sen4ll.l Pair banks with the
          Indian* delegation entereil the hall
          The people howled and clapped, but
          It v. 1. ail over In a few second*
          ijuiet reigned again.
          The prellniliiatle* had been so
          mild that this enthusiastic aliening
          Is hailed as good ton. 11 Unci* Jo*
          I'.inn.ni »or* an expan.lve stiill*
          when the che«r swelled up fnr Men*
          Btor 1iii1..!..' II made 1 1 .in Ihe
          tact that th* delegatee had boarded
          ititie I'.iiil'.itihs wagon.
          Ma tea I handed bung
          starter Chairman Payli* rapped for
          erd*r.
          Th* .tinientlnn MMA railed to or
          der 12. it p. m. He. J P. f-'ruat.
          pastor of th* Methodist Episcopal
          church at Kvanstnn. 111., aa. Intro
          duced and he pronounced a short
          Invocation.
          At th* conclusion Of th* prayer
          Senator Hcott prr**nted Chairman
          Pays* with a gavel on behalf of the
          Chicago committee. Th* ebslrman
          expressed his th.ite.lt and John R
          Mall. of Ohio, the reading clerk,
          then read lb* tall for th* tout en
          tion.
          At i: *7 p. m »hen the late
          Sen.- Hsnna's tine ws* read as
          signing the call an outburst of ap
          plause «re. ted It
          At 11:11 Chairman I'.ine Intro
          dured EHho Hoot. form*r seeretsry
          of »»r. as temporary airman
          Gov, Odell. of New York, moved
          th* approval of (h* selection of Mr.
          Root s* temporary chairman and
          the vol* unanimous fur ap
          arrival
          Mr. Root was greeted *lth en
          thusiastic applause In M,» midst
          Ot this a picture ot President !t--..»e.
          velt was displayed from tlie plat
          form without stirs, tine murh at
          tention It was promptly removed.
          Chairman Hoot then began hi*
          speech In a tow voir* aad h* ws*
          Interrupted with calls of "Loader
          'er
          Chairman Root was frequently la
          terrtipted with applaaat Itts de
          scription of ihe splendid flnsnctal
          condition of th* country brought
          out volleys of cheers. Ills reference
          to lb* benefit result nf the oc
          cupation of the Philippine* was
          wildly cheered as was th* Psßsma
          paragraph
          At I:4S Root concluded, but Jutt
          bsib** finishing hi* address th*
          former •erretary brought th* con-
          vention to Its reel with a beautiful
          tribute to th* memory of th* lata
          President MrKlntey snd Senator
          Harms saying:
          "And with M. Kinley we remem
          ber Hanna with affection aad sor
          row—bit great lieutenant They are
          nether again.**
          Ills I tiding remarks a pretty
          compliment to President Roosevelt,
          called forth deafening applans*.
          Root ssld: "Com* what may here
          come what mar In November. Ood
          grant that thus* qualities of brsv*
          true manhi-nd shall hay* honor
          throughout America, shall b* held
          for an example In every home, and
          that the youth of generation* to 1
          com* my grow tip to feel that it Is
          WANTS 'EM TO FORG ET MORMON ISM
          ■_.
          U. S. Senator Reed moot.
          I Hi: COLISEUM. CIIICAOO. IN Vt 11.l I HOOSEVELT WILL UK NOMINATED,
          Bit thousand .even hundred parsons grllßaied In th* Coliseum today to participate In anil
          wll-
          B*aa th* opening of the Q. O. P. ix.***_liaa There would bate turn twlc* i.at many pcopl*
          in at*
          teintait. r. but for th* .ttlit regulatloaa promulgated by the city gover ntnent since thl
          Irot-uols disaster.
          The Coliseum will people and only that many But Inside a* a rasulL Bpectator's admis
          sion ttrkets ar* st a premium, lime si* MS delegate* and a* many alternate* In seats on
          Ih* floor.
          I m formed messenger* deliver r-'iutvi from th* twelve lout distance telepbon* booths and
          th* tele
          graph offtr* under th* stag* floor. itafctßtl th* sp**ker*a .tail Is th* division allotted
          to the dlttln
          gulshesl tne»t« and m. in litis that ar* th* seals of 100 newspaper correspondent*
          Twnitv five stenographer* snd '"legraad. OBSsTßlof* la th* *ervlc* of various news bureau*
          snd pre**
          -_.-- it. are seated st tables just b*lo* the ipesker's tabls. Th* hand Is elevated on a
          stand abov*
          th* s~ mid gallery.
          Adjoining th* auditorium Is sn Bert, i that was built from .m mat-rial* In th* old Utihy
          prison. In
          thla annes are th* room* of th* national rsißimllte*- an subcororattt**-.. Retiring rooms
          for ladles snd
          smoking rooms for en are appreciated convenience-. "Hplrltual comfort" for th* thirsty Is
          not to
          be had anywhere shout the building, ail efforts on th* part of liquor reader* to sarure
          concessions st enor
          mous prtr** hsvlei failed. Not *v*B the lo«ly 'am aandwl. may be obtained within th* walls
          better than wealth, or offle*. or
          power, lo bale th* ille.lv th*
          purity, *nd th* courage of Theodore
          It. ..nil H."
          At lilt P m. the teml-nrsry of
          fliers elected by Ihe nattonsl coin*
          mill** w*r* approved on.lh* mo
          lion of -senator Hick of Ohio. Th*
          rule* of the last eonvenllun were
          adopted mi the motto* of Carter of
          Montana.
          At lilt **t. m- oa the" mot Inn of
          Srt.it. r Ptirsh»r of Ohio, r 1
          by ***n.t..t lleyhurn of Idaho Ihe
          convention agieed to Ih. l'orto
          It:- 1 I'l Hi. .in* delegate*.
          On motion of -tenatnr Mc-foma* af
          Maryland the roll call wa* taken and
          th* announcement of standing com*
          ii.inees mad*.
          Al 3 10 IX m. th* lemtlilil ll*t
          of commitl*** read ad th* east*
          v. I-*nn ,i tj -_iree.i until tomorrow.
          ALL FOR TEDDY
          CriUCAOO. 111. Jun* 21. It Is B
          Hiei.evrM convention now Th*
          i haua* Baa com* with the arrival
          of the (real Bin of delegates snd
          thousands of hostllng Republican*.
          Ob (his. th* opening day of th*
          convention. Roosevelt badge* gator* j
          adorn th* coats of men to he seen
          on th* streets the met not r**is
          tered among th* leaders In parlor
          conferences
          t'litll Monday th* leader* held
          full away. They were of th* old
          guard of the ma.hine urgantis
          who** on* great purpo** ana to
          p*ri-a-i na'e their rule. Some of them
          wer* nti Roo**v*N men and la
          their eye* th* ;-re*ldent was a i«.
          litic*! at. Idi nt. Bibs had to It*
          given Baa rmMMMMMMUAA by fore* of
          circumstances.
          The. threw cold wster on RctCise
          vslt wtUnMt whenever It appear
          ed snd Ignored lb* president tn con
          v.ntt. srrsngemrnts snd evea hsd
          not a thought of him In plaoalng
          th* dttcorstlons. Mutt Important of
          sIL they*decided thst one of their
          own en*, t i"ns should 1. th* new
          chairman of the rational rommltte*
          leader of th* party.
          Th*o It ass thst Hie president*
          friends on th* ground mad* the
          determined stand. la*'. that
          r-'e, nisiv Cortrlyotl should hay*
          th* ptac*. Thrse Itoottev«lt men
          held their fir* until the srmy of
          delegate* began flocking In Hun-lay
          nlrht.
          Monday the eatlr* force arrived
          and th* old guard 'ni hi Be poll*
          HrISBS routed
          Talk to one of them today and yon
          get th* nieek statement that Cortrl
          yotl will b* chairman They sr* for
          hist They hay* heard from th*
          llttl* fellow* who r*pre*ent the
          district* sad who arc direct from
          th* pen*-!*. They find a mighty
          •er.ttrn.ait aiming th* tna** Re
          publicans la favor of Room- I
          Th* latt of the old organltatloß
          displaced oa lit* national committee
          by new mea lud* Kerens, of
          MtSBOttH Sheldon, .f New York:
          Stewart, ef Illinois, nd Haw:. of
          Texas.
          The old machine has been shat
          tared. Ron.*..!! Is the leader H
          pi- 'tire bow hangs In all public
          pis anil looks forth from badge*
          snd his .me figure* in tb* roaver
          aatlon of sump* of ann and always
          brines he.— among 'I. crowd*
          Th* rebellions talk sgslnst th*
          eeleetlna* of ("ortelyoti for th* na
          tional i halrataaahtp has almost en-
          HE HAS NOTII ING TO SAY
          U. S. Senator 1 li.ti lea Fairbanks,
          ttrely it... it. -I nor Is there longer
          talk of compromise, looking either
          to Cortelyou'l selection or subse
          quent resignation to srrrpt th*
          postmaster generalship or luoklog
          to the selection of Cortrlyotl ss
          ■■I.airman of the executive commit
          tee, and the choice of tomt tfa* els*
          ill,
          to preside over the national rom
          mltte* Itself.
          Cortrlyotl It detained in New
          York on sceount of the investiga
          tion of the Hloeum disaster, but he
          Is etpts-ted here Wednesday. Ilia
          coming, however, will bar* little
          effect on th* sltuatlo n
          FAIRBANKS IS
          SURE TO GET IT
          CHICAGO, 111. Jun* IL— If there
          «ii say doubt about if.' noralna
          tloti of Senator Falrtanks for vice
          president Ist* development* have tet
          It at re*t When I'enney It an.a fell
          Into line the other ->.ralrt. ii. not
          hay* a leg to stand on
          Cannon's forceful and picturesque
          expressions on th* subject of his
          esndtdscy settled th* matter, *o far
          ss th* v. York scheme to nom
          inal" hint was concerned.
          Roosevelt kept hi* hand* ont of
          the fight, bnt Cornelius Hits*, who
          represent* the president, was .on
          sulted snd scqtilt-sced to the Fair
          hanks program.
          Thar* will be no fight in the con
          vention, although there m*y be
          complimentary vote* for a number
          of others, whose enthusiastic friends
          VOL. 6. NO. 104,
          WHY HARRIMAN
          WANTS TO GET
          INTO SEATTLE
          UNION PACIFIC MAGNATE WANTS PART OF THE RICH NORTH
          WESTERN TRADE AND HOPES TO EXTEND HIS MERCHANT
          MARINE AND SECURE DEEP WATER HARBOR
          Railroad men who know E. 11.
          Ilni i limit: In i.t any he Is not one to
          leave .i de-alrable and valuable field
          opt-n to hi* t oiiipi titoie any longer
          than Is mi'men lit I* quick st
          perceiving just «here be can
          strengthen bl* position and It not
          backward In making Die necessary
          moves. Por this reason they are
          ready to believe that the recent
          flurry 111 Heattle tide lands la due
          ti. his plan to gain terminal grounda
          tn Heattle before atartlng work on
          his new line fit. Portland to Pugt-t
          Hound.
          Km yearn Mr. Harrtnian has real
          ised thst better bsrbor f*. III! In
          tbe P.it if!. Northwest sre what he
          needs. Portland cannot accommo
          date the big ocean liners he desire*
          to still to hit. already in no tin- trans
          portation system, snd, for thla rea
          son, be must w-ek a harbor else
          where. It Is necessary to have a
          basis of opera' on the oust sad
          refit*. to permit a withdrawal of
          their names.
          PLATFORM TALK
          CHICAGO, June ZL—Th* hope* of
          tariff adjusters for s tariff revision
          pistil, In the platform are doomed 1
          to disappointment. Hut little talk
          la heard foreshadowing the slightest
          roncesslona on the part of the stand
          patter*. Th* Western delegates
          continue the agitation again-' the
          antl p .it g-tt.v plank, a matter on
          which th* delegate* from I'tah.
          Idaho, Colorado, Wyoming aad
          other inter-mountain states are
          standing together.
          Another fruitful topic for the
          Westerner la the Statehood ques
          tion. Though the last two Con
          rtoi-s refused to carry out the
          platform pledge*, looking to the ad
          mlaalon of Oklahoma, Arizona and
          New Miilro. the ststehood boom-'
          I era have not lost hop* and the
          struggle Is to be renewed before a
          committee on resolutions.
          (Continue'! on lag* I)
          I MHO'S
          mam
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99063957/1904-06-21/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Republican+National+Convention+Vice+President+Fairbanks+Roosevelt+Delegations</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          NATIONAL
          REPUBLICAN
          CONVENTION
          Fairbanks for Vice President
          Is Now a Foregone
          Conclusion
          Opening and Organization of the Great
          Roosevelt Ratification Meeting
          Root Wildly Cheered
          Chicago, Juno 21. If there was
          doubt about the nomination of Fair
          banks, of Indiana, for vlco-presldent,
          We developments have set It at rest
          When Pennsylvania and New York
          fell Into line, the other boomlets did
          tot have a leg to stand on. Cannon's
          forceful and picturesque expressions
          on the subject of his own candidacy.
          I settled the matter, so far as the New
          York scheme to nominate him was
          concerned. Roosevelt kept his hands
          out of the fight, but Cornelius Bliss,
          ho represented "the President, was
          consulted, and acquiesced in the pro
          gram. There will be no fight in tho
          con?entlon, although there may be
          complimentary votes for a number of
          others, whose enthusiastic friends
          refuse to permit tho withdrawal of
          their names. Rebellious talk against
          the selection of.Cortolyou for the na
          tional chairmanship has almost en
          tirely iubsided, nor Is there longer
          tilt c a compromise, looking either
          to Oortolyou's .selection, his .subse
          quent resignation, to accept the post
          master-generalship or looking to" the
          selection of Cortelyou as chairman, of
          tie executive committee and choico
          of some one else to preside on the na
          tional committee Itself. Cortelyou is
          detained in New York on account of
          the Slocurm disaster, but is expected
          tere Wednesday. His coming, how
          erer, U11 have" little effect on the sit-
          tatlon. The, hopes' of tho tariff re
          idjusters for a revision plank in tho
          platform are doomed to disappoint
          ment, but little talk being heard fore
          shadowing the slightest concessions
          on the part of the "stand-patters."
          But Western delegates continue tho
          sjitation against an anti-polygamy
          Pbnk, a matter In which delegates
          from Utah, Idaho, Colorado, Wyoming
          ud other intermountain common
          wealths are standing together. Anoth
          er fruitful topic for Westerners is" the
          .statehood question, the last two con
          gresses having refused to carry out
          tho platform pledges looking to tho
          admission 'of Oklahoma, Arizona and
          New Mexico. The statehood boomers
          have not lost hope, and tho struggle
          will bo renewed before tho commit
          tee on resolutions.
          Roosevelt In the Saddle.
          Chicago, June 21. It is a Roosevelt
          convention now. Tho change has
          come with the arrival of tho great
          mass of the delegates, and thousands
          of hustling Republicans. Roosevelt
          badges galore adorn the coats of men
          to be seen on tho streets, men not reg
          Istered among the leaders and in the
          parlor conferences. Until Monday the
          anti-leaders held sway. They were
          tho old guard of the machine organi
          zation, whose own great purpose was
          to perpetuate their rule, some of
          whom' were antl Roosevelt, and In
          whoso eyes tho President Is a politic
          al accident, and who bad1 to be given
          a renomination by force of circum
          stances. They threw cold1 water
          wherever Roosevelt sentiment ap
          peared, ignoring tho President in the
          convention arrangements, and had not
          thought of him in planning the decor
          ations. Most important of all, they
          decided, that one of their own selec
          tion should bo the new chairman of
          the committee, andi national leader of
          the party. Then it was that the Pres
          ident's friends on the ground made a
          determined stand, Insisting "that Cor
          telyou should have tho place. These
          Roosevelt men held their guns until
          tho army of delegates began flocking
          In Sunday night.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85052116/1904-06-23/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Republican+Republicans+Convention+Roosevelt+Fairbanks</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          Convention Hall Chicago Juno 23
          This the third sad hut II the great
          el day of the Republican national
          convention
          y r Theodore Roosevelt was nominated
          I a to suooetxl bluirelf in the white house
          ObarlcH W Fairbanks United
          States renator from Indiana was
          named for vloo president It was n
          i day of oratorical pyrotechnics and
          the attendance was tho largest of the
          salon
          ustlonThe
          The roll call for nominations for
          president wan prdered Alabama tho
          first on the list relinquished the place
          of honor to the state oj Now York
          4 Former Governor Black proceeded to
          tho platform and nominated President
          i Roosevelt land I wa greeted with wild
          choeflI
          cheers
          I Governor Black mado a mutely
          I speech and when ho mentioned the
          a name of Roosevelt and closed the en
          II I
          thusiasm was uproarons
          A delegation marched through tho
          I hall waving flags and banners men
          tobeorttl t and women waved handker
          t chiefs
          It was twenty throo minutes until
          c order was restored When Benatofc
          t Bemldgf of Indiana advanced to
          r a second the nomination the cheering
          was renamed
          r Senator Bevorldgoa talk enthused
          I f the convention and was frequently
          Interrupted by applause When ho
          concluded there was another brief
          demonstrttlon at the mention of
          noollQVeltEIGoornnrBradley
          EsGovornnr Bradley of Kentucky
          t f hnext 1 spoke making a speech which
          aroused tho convention He was in
          r r trounced by Speaker Cannon as com
          t log from She pinto where Republicans
          V Utako politics like whiskey straight U
          At 190 President Roosevelt was
          declared nominated receiving every
          Tote Then began another demonstra
          tion neUV jwh Vv I0llom witnessed in
          public gatherings
          h r BX BULLETIN
          ii Oouventloavgrfall Chicago 10 a
          mTho t Convention lull rapidly
          filled up vlfatyrr i scat filled
          102V th0 wovontlon was called
          to order 1 Up 1JInn Cannon
          f 10SonThldtleo E Solnly
          f opened the convention with prayer
          l 1041The olerk called the roll
          f j f of states for presentation of names of
          candidates Alabama yielded to New
          York ExGovernor Black came to
          tho platform and Chairman Cannon
          introduced him nmld great applause
          1 Jf 1044 BxGovornor Black of Now
          York in a spirited speech placed
          then name of President Roosevelt in
          nomination1100Chairman
          1100 Chairman Cannon is I on the
          platform with tstterod flag the band
          f js playing delegations are on their
          feet and a missive picture of Theo
          lore ftoosevelt is I shown on the plat
          form bringing forth renewed applanro
          Jltll Delegates of New York aro
          making a oiroult of the ball while
          M
          G
          t Pabtuab ttU
          t I VOL XVI NO 150 PADUCAH KY THURSDAY JUNE 23 1904 10 CENTS PERWEE
          j ROOSEVELT ANDF FAIRBANKS
          1 1 I 11 th HONORED ByT t HEIR PARTI
          ltt 1
          h tCli Rent the t Air When
          y 1 Roosevelts Name Was
          Mentioned
          1ft
          I 1 1 9Opposition to the Distinguished Standard
          Bearers of Republicanism
          1t 1
          FaUNEQUALLED ORATORY MARKED SESSION
          the band is i playing Star Spangled
          Banner Chairman Cannon loads in
          singing the Star Spangled Banner
          Band now playing U Hot Time in the
          Old Town Tonight It
          1116 Convention still sbontlng
          to Roosevelt Chairman Cannon
          again appear on the platform with
          the tattered flag which brings forth
          renewed cheering Convention still
          in an uproar
          1110 Entire audlcDCi singing Star
          Spangled Banner No sign of order
          Delegation with rod white and blue
          umbrella taking circuit of tho ball
          1128 Chairman Cannon II using
          gavel to bring the convention to Oder
          113The 1 1 convention delegates nre
          taking their scats
          1182 Senator Bovoridgc of In
          diana seconds Roosevelt nomina
          tion1157George
          1157 J George A Knight of Cull
          torah seoocds Roosevelts nomina
          tion
          1220 p mHarry Btlllwoll Ed
          wand of Georgia seconds President
          Roose volt nomination
          1235 Governor Bradley of Ben
          tucky seconds the nomination of
          President Roosevelt
          112AI1 the states from Alabama
          to Indiana baTe cast their entire vote
          for President Roosevelt
          1 21noll call ended with no name
          mentioned but that of Roosevelt get
          ting the total of 094 votes of the con
          vention124Senator
          124 Senator Charles W Fair
          banks of Indiana was nominated for
          vice president by Senator Dolliver of
          Iowa129donator
          129donator Depow seconds noml
          nation of Fairbanks for vice president
          147 Senator F L Foruker of
          Ohio seconds the nomination of Fair
          banks 3S2
          2 11SA resolution was paused nam
          ing Joseph G Cannon chairman of
          tho committee to notify Theodore
          Roosevelt of his nomination on July
          27th and Ellhu Root chairman of the
          committee to notify Senator Falrbankn
          ot his nomination for vice president
          on August 3rd
          FREEMAN SOLDf
          it I
          WELL KNOWN PITCHER GOES t t1
          TO NASHVILLE ON TRIAL
          1
          Jim Freeman PadnoAhs star
          twirler hss been sold to Nashville on
          trial Fisher of the Nashville team
          has been after him for some time and
          Fraeman will doubtless make good
          lbe sale was completed today and
          Freemen leaves at once If he suits f i
          the price demanded for him which is e
          not made public will bo paid If not t t
          the deal will be off
          j
          Marshal Jim Munal of Metrop I
          oils is i improving from an attack ofI
          blood polBoalug resolting from a pim 11 t
          plo on the hand t
          k
          PRESIDENT THEODORE ROOSEVELTI I
          tOM JOHN S SAnQENVS POHTIIA1T1 1 e
          iJ F j SENATOR CHARLES W FAIRBANKS t1 11
          TEXAS FOR PARKER
          San Antonio Texas June 23The
          State Democratic Convention finished
          its business One of the strongest
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99063957/1904-06-23/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Roosevelt+Fairbanks+Republican+Convention</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          ROOSEVELT AND FAIRBANKS
          Republican National Convention Unanimously Names Stand-
          atd Beaes Enthusiastic Sessions
          Correspondent Reported Shot
          New York, June 23. The World to
          day received from Shan Halkwan a
          cablegram that its Far Eastern corre
          spondent, Edward Emerson, was re
          ported to have been shot by a Russian
          miner.
          SHOES I
          With Goodyear Welt Soles Mean
          OMFORTi
          QWQJi
          WHITE HOUSE
          JSHOES
          avwaSAv
          v irtai m
          Wher with our extremely low
          The Insole Is smooth, and en
          tirely freo from nails and thread
          Thoy are more floxlblo than tho
          ordinary "sowed soles," and
          gives bettor service. If you
          want to know moro about a welt
          shoe, let us show you one that
          la sawed in two to show how
          they aro made inside. Wo can
          supply you with Goodyear
          Welts, in Patent Colt, Vlcl Kid,
          Volur Calf, Box Calf) and
          Genuine Kangaroo, in great va
          riety of now and stylish lasts.
          Tho quality of our shoes, to
          prlcos makes our business grow.
          9
          The New York Racket
          m
          DRY GOODS, CLOTHING
          Ok
          "and Men's furnishings. Salem's cheapest ono-prico cash
          ttore.
          Chicago, June 23. The last and
          greatest day of the Republican na
          tional convention was the apothesls of
          the big show, the climax to which tho
          events of the past two days have been
          the Introduction. Today Theodore
          Roosevelt was nominated to succeed
          himself as President, and Charles W.
          Fairbanks, senator from Indiana, was
          named as vice-president. With tho
          candllates of the party selected' tho
          convention adjourned, tho delegations
          dispersing1 to spread into every re
          mote section of the country a conta
          gion of enthusiastic fever which has
          been enthused into them at this great
          gathering by the leaders of the grand
          old party of protection.
          This was a day of oratorical pyro
          technics. Somo of the finest speakers
          In the Republican organization were
          heard in common chorus in praise of
          the men who aro to lead the hosts to
          battle. Elated by tho ovents and the
          speeches of the last two days, and
          eagerly anticipating -the intellectual
          treat in store today, tho delegates be
          gan to assemble in tho convention hall
          early this morning. Becauso of im
          portant workin hand the convention
          was called to assemble at 10 o'clock.
          Half hour before the floor presented
          an animated scene. Many delegates
          brought flags with them to assist in
          the demonstration which they were
          prepared to make when Roosevelt was
          placed in nomination. An increased
          interest in the convention was also
          shown In the galleries, which began to
          fill ns soon as tho doors opened at 9
          o'clock. By tho time Chairman Can
          non called tho assembly to order near
          ly every seat was occupied, and short
          ly after standing room was at a pre
          mium. There was a larger proportion
          of ladies present than at either of the
          previous sessions, and their summer
          costumes lent a touch of color to the
          otherwise sombro rows of black coats.
          The first outburst of applause was
          ovoked by Margaret Elizabeth Plum
          mer, national organizer of the Ameri
          can Flag Asosciation, who was
          dressed in a stunning gown of cream
          colored silk, who surprised Chairman
          Cannori' by presenting him with a
          great bunch of calla lilies, after mak
          ing a graceful little speech. Secretary
          Cortelyjpu was on the platform. As
          soon riS he mado his appearance many
          prominent leaders pressed forward to
          shake hands and assure him of their
          loyalty and assistance in the great
          work he is about to undertake as
          chairman of the national committee.
          Every membor of tho New York
          delegation, under instructions from
          Senators Plat tand Depow, was sup
          plied with fine silk flags, and their
          eritranco was greeted with loud ap
          plause Everybody arose while the
          band played "America."
          Tho convention hall filled rapidly at
          an early hour, and every seat was
          filled when Chairman called it to or
          der at 10 o'clock.
          Rev. Thaddius E. Snlvely opened
          the convention with prayer.
          Alabama yielded to New York on
          the call of states. Chairman Cannon
          then introduced ex-Governor Black
          amid great applause.
          At 10:41 a. m. tho clerk called tho
          roll of states for the presentation of
          the names of candidates.
          When ex-Governor Black finished
          speaking there was great applause,
          and the delegates were on their feet.
          Chairman Cannon stood on tho plat
          form with a tattered battloflag. The
          bands were playing, delegates were
          on their feet, and a massive picture of
          Theodore Roosevelt shown on tho
          platform brought forth renewed ap
          plause. The delegates of New York made a
          circuit of the hall, while the band
          played tho Star Spangled Banner.
          Chairman Cannon lead in singing
          the Star Spangled Banner, and the.
          band played "A Hot Time in tho Old
          Town Tonight."
          Senator Boveridge, of Indiana, sec
          onded Roosevelt's nomination with a
          stirring speech, and the enthusiasm
          is on tho Increase.
          Chairman Cannon was compellod to
          use tho gavel a number of times to
          bring the convention to order.
          The entire audience is slpging "Tho
          Star Spangled Banner," and' there are
          no signs of order. Delegations with
          red, white and blue umbrellas are
          making a circuit of the hall.
          Tho convention was still shouting
          for Roosevelt when Chairman Cannon
          again appeared on the platform with
          tho tattered flag, which brought forth
          renewed cheers, and tho convention
          was in an uproar, and pandemonium
          reigned for somo time.
          Geo. A. Knight, of California, sec
          onded Roosevelt's nomination on be
          half of the coast states.
          Harry Stilwell Edwards, of Georgia,
          seconded the nomination with a bril
          liant speech.
          Ex-Governor Bradley, of Kentucky,
          made a seconding speech.
          Hary S. Cummlngs, tho colored ora
          tor of Maryland, and Jos. B. Cotton,
          of Minnesota, followed with short
          speeches seconding the nomination.
          When New Jersey was reached
          they asked for unanimous consent for
          tho convention to dispense with furth
          er roll call and nominate Roosevelt by
          acclamation, but the Idea did not moot
          with favor.
          When tho roll call was ended no
          namo had been mentioned but that of
          Roosovelt, and ho received tho total
          994 votes of tho convention.
          In his characteristic stylo Senator
          Dolllver, of Iowa, placed Fairbanks in
          nomination'. He paid a glowing
          tribute to tho policies of tho Republi
          can party, and to the leaders respon
          sible for tho exposition of these poli
          cies. Gradually hut adroitly he led
          up to his eulogy of tho Indiana
          statesman. Dolliver's peroration was
          In the following werdB:
          "While ho has not sought to con
          strain tho Judgment of tho conven
          tion, directly or indirectly, he lias
          kept himself free from affectation
          which undervalues tho dignity of the
          second ofilco within the gift of tho
          American people, and I do not doubt
          that his heart has been touched' by
          tho volunteer expression of universal
          good will, which already has choson
          him a one of tho standard bearers
          for tho Republican party of tho United
          States. Tho ofilco has sought tho
          man, and ho will bring to the office
          the conmnding personality jot a states
          man equal to any of Jth'e groat1 respon
          sibilities which belong to our public
          affairs.
          "A leader of the senate and a cham
          plon of all great policies which constl
          tute tho invincible record of the Re
          publican party during tho last 10
          years, his namo will become a towor
          of strength to our cause, not only in
          his own state, but ovorywhoro
          throughout tho country. A man of af
          fairs, the wholo business community
          shares tho confidence which his polit
          ical associates have reposed in him
          from the beginning of his public life.
          Quiet, undemonstrative, and popular
          opinion, which has given tho Republi
          can party a platform upon which all
          Republicans stand, with no dissent
          ing voice hero or anywhere, has long
          since anticipated1 tho action of this
          convention in adding to tho national
          Republican ticket tho namo of Bona
          tor Chns. w! Fairbanks, of Indiana,
          and I take pleasure in presenting this
          namo honored everywhere throughout
          tho United States as our candidato
          for vice-president."
          Fairbanks was nominated by unan
          imous voto aftor tho announcement
          of tho withdrawal of the other candi
          dates. A resolution was passed1 naming
          Jos. G. Cannon as chairman of tho
          committee to nptify Theodore Rooso
          velt of his nomination on July 27th,.
          and Elihu Root chairman of tho com
          mittee to notify Senator Fairbanks of"
          his nomination for vice-president on
          August 3d.
          Convention adjourned sine die at
          2:35 p. m.
          Republican Platform.
          Fifty years-ago the Ropuhlicarr
          party came into existence dedicatod,
          among other purposes to tho great
          task of arresting tho extension of
          human slavery. In 18G0 it elected its
          first president. During 24 of tho 44
          years which have elapsed since tho
          election of Lincoln, tho Republican
          party has hold complete control of tho
          government. This long tenure is not
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1904-06-24/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Republican+Convention+Roosevelt+Fairbanks+Running+Mate+President#</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          ROOSEVELT WILL LEAD PARTY TO VICTORY;
          HIS RUNNING MATE THE POPULAR FAIRBANKS
          ContiOT>3d on Fftge 2, Column 3.
          Continued on Pace 2, Column 4,
          Continued on Pago 2, Oohma 4,V;
          PARIS, June 23.— The Foreign Office
          has been- advised -that -the Porte 'has
          ylelde'd; completely to the demands of
          the powers for redress as a result of
          the Armenian persecutions. Evicted
          "Armenians -.will be returned t to their
          homes, indemnlOed I for, losses and pro
          tected jforLthe j future.
          Vlhe -Sultan,- '.however.- has thus 'far
          declined* to; ratify the Porte's decision.
          .The concessions followed a definite in
          timation that 1 the powers were pre
          paring to make a naval demonstration
          in-Turkish' waters, rvtv 3§SE9 r E£t
          EVICTED ARMENIANS
          v TO BE INDEMNIFIED
          Porte Yields to Demands of the
          j£ Powers and Will Redress the VIc
          ;;-tinis of; Persecution..
          A telegram' received yesterday from
          dent he sent' to him a telegram "of con
          gratulation, and' shortly afterward re
          ceived an answer' expressing apprecia
          tion of the distinction conferred by, the
          nomination. __ ._-
          Among Khe. telegrams received was
          one from a few of ROoseyeTt's Long"Isl
          and neighbors^- as follows:
          GARDEN' .CITY.-N'. T.'.'.Tune'23.T. 19OC— The
          President. Whlt« Honse, Washington, D. .C—
          Your. Nassau netghbors send .greetings and
          congratulations," wishing you all prosperity, and
          a continued career of usefulness to the nation.
          A triumphant election 'will be:but:your ¦well
          merited reward. LEWIS.
          CHESHIRE.
          V i JOHNSON,
          ...YOUNGS^.'.'.
          A party, of the. famous Rough Riders
          sent this message:'
          CONVENTION HALL; CHICAGO, June 23,
          1804.— Colonel. Theodore* Roosevelt, Washing
          ton- Your comrade* of '9S,, delegates to this
          convention,"" congratulate-, you on this, j one of
          the greatest events In American history. Every
          soldier of your regiment will be on duty, from
          now. until you- are elected- President:. May 'God
          bless you. O. BROD1E.
          W. H. II. LLEWELLYN.
          v :t.-j..-.leahey.-
          E.DAME; i~
          >:;w.- s. Simpson. '\->c "7
          During the late afternoon and' the
          early evening telegrams from all parts
          of. the country poured Into the White
          House offices by the score, each. bearing
          its words of cheer and good wishes.*
          OOXGRATIJLATES. FAIRBANKS.
          As soon as the President recelve'd
          news of the r nomination' of Senator
          Fairbanks as candidate for Vice "Presi-
          Aside from Secretary Loeb. -Assistant
          Secretary, of State Francis B. Loom is
          was the first official of the administra
          tion to extend his congratulations.
          Later in the day. however, other of
          ficials called at the White House to
          felicitate Roosevelt upon' his nomina
          tion.
          as the standard-bearer of a great po
          litical party, but as Theodore_Roosevelt,
          the man and friend. Wlttr genial rail
          lery he chatted with one, exchanged
          comments on men or events" with* an
          other, laughed heartily at a cartoon of
          himself to which attention was drawn,
          sketched in a free-hand way Incidents
          of the convention, recalled some Inter
          esting situations, personal and political,
          end in conclusion again thanked his
          friends for expressions of their con
          gratulations.
          :CHICAGO. June 22. 1904.— Pre«ident Roose
          velt; White House. Washing-ton. Several Tale
          men awaiting, wjth Joyful anticipation .to-mor
          'row's Just recognition of your cervices to coun
          try" and party. CARTER.
          HKFFELFINGER,
          SHEFFIELD.
          -WILLIAMS.
          Governor Carter of Hawaii, and others
          equally well known. follows .-.vr»
          1858— Born October 27, in New York City.
          1 880— G raduatcd at Harvard University: f
          1882-83-84 Served in the New. York Leg-
          islature. A
          1884— Chairman of the New York delega-
          tion to the Republican National Con-
          vention.
          1886 Defeated as Republican candidate Tor.
          Mayor of New York.
          i$89-95-MJnited States Civil Service ,Com-
          missioned.
          1895-97 President of the :Board of Police,'
          Commissioners of New -York.
          LIFE STORY OF THEODORE ROOSEVELT
          1897-98— Assistant Secretary of -the Navy.
          1 SpSV-I-ieu tenant colonel and colonel of the
          First Vdlunteer. Cavalry ("Rough
          .Riders")' .Regiment^ in the war witfi
          Spain:.- r' r
          1899— Elected Governor, of New- York.
          190'0^-Electcd Vice President of the United
          v States.
          1 90 1— -September 14,^ succeeded to the'Presi
          dency on the death of "William Mc
          1904—^Nominated for -President b*y the Re
          publican National- Convention.
          REPUBLICAN PARTY'S UN AN I MO US CHOICE FO R STANDARD. BEARER.
          Sitting tilted back in a big armchair
          at his desk the President chatted freely
          and frankly with those about him. AH
          were his personal friends, and the Pres
          ident realized perfectly that the little
          confidences of the "executive session,"
          as he himself termed It. would be held
          as Inviolable. He talked and acted not
          as President of the United States, not
          President Roosevelt rose from his
          chair to receive the affectionate con
          gratulations of those about him. He
          was the most unconcerned, seemingly,
          of all. He chatted animatedly a few
          minutes with Mrs. Roosevelt, Miss
          Carew and Loeb, and then accom
          panied his secretary to the executive
          offices.
          ATTENDS. TO ROUTINE WORK.
          Outward indications that Theodore
          Roosevelt was to be chosen unanimous
          ly as the standard-bearer of his party
          absolutely were lacking at the White
          House in the morning. The President
          appeared at his desk at the usual hour
          and began" immediately to transact rou
          tine executive business with Secretary
          Loeb. The important subjects disposed
          of, he received several visitors .for
          «hom engagements had been made.
          No members of the Cabinet called dur
          ing the early hours of the business
          day. The President was kept In close
          touch with the situation at Chicago
          through the press bulletins and private
          messages from the convention hall,
          which were received over a special
          wire at the White House.
          On his return to the executive offices
          after he had been informed of his
          nomination. President Roosevelt greet
          ed cordially a number of newspaper
          men. He expressed his pleasure at re
          ceiving the warm congratulations of
          those who. In the performance of their
          duties, are kept constantly" in touch
          with the President and his work.
          CHATS WITH FRIENDS.
          WASHINGTON, June 23.—Surround
          ed by members of his family. President
          Roosevelt received the announcement
          that he had been nominated unani
          mously by the Republicans at Chicago.
          The news was received by telephone at
          the White House by a press repre
          sentative In advance of its receipt over
          the special telegraph wire running from
          Chicago to the executive offices.
          At 1i:lZ p. m. the bulletin was given
          to Secretary Loeb. Some time previ
          ously the President had left his offices
          in the executive building and had gone
          to the White House for luncheon. Sec
          retary Loeb immediately conveyed the
          news to him there. Seated on the
          veranda of the White House, chatting
          with Mrs. Roosevelt, his sister-in-law.
          Miss Carew and other members of his
          family, tjie President received Loeb's
          announcement.
          Chairman Parker of the Missouri del
          egation presented to the committee an
          A resolution was adopted authorizing
          the chairman to appoint an executive
          committee of nine, with such other of
          ficers as are necessary for ther'manage
          ment of the campaign. The chairman,
          secretary, treasurer and sergeant-at
          arms are to-be officers of the executive
          committee. Under this resolution the
          chairman is given absolute power in
          the conduct of the campaign.
          INVITATION* FROM FRANCIS.
          After Cortelyou's remarks Elmer Do
          ver. of Ohio was named as secretary by
          Senator. Scott. Cornelius N. Bliss of
          New York for treasurer by Governor
          Murphy and William F. Stone of Mary
          land for sergeant-at-arms by Senator
          Mi Comas. All of these officers were
          unanimously re-elected.
          ¦No 'vice chairman will be appointed,
          and the new chairman will divide his
          time between the New York and Chi
          cago headquarters, although some
          members of. the committee no doubt
          will be designated to take charge of
          the headquarters In this city. Head
          quarters will not be opened in either
          city until l the latter part of July.
          Meanwhile Cortelyou expects to select
          the executive committee and make his
          preliminary arrangements for the cam
          paign.
          s As soon as the committee was called
          to order, Postmaster General Payne, in
          a complimentary speech, nominated
          Cortelyou- for chairman, and the elec
          tion was made without a dissenting
          voice. Clayton of Arkansas, Murphy of
          New Jersey and Yerkes of Kentucky
          were appointed a committee to notify
          the new chairman and bring him be
          fore the committee.
          CHICAGO, June 23.— George B. Cor
          telyou was chosen chairman of the
          Republican •National Committee at a
          meeting held to-day, just after the ad
          journment of the national convention.
          2n thanking the committee for the
          honor, he told the members that, whHe
          he would be glad to have the benefit
          of their, advice and counsel, he in
          tended to be chairman in fact, and
          would accept no dictation from any one,
          high or low. He told them that the
          friends of the late Chairman Hanna
          were his friends, and he asked for
          the same measure of confidence and
          support that had been given to the
          late chairman. In conclusion, he
          sought the advice of both old and new
          members.
          Cortelyou made «S formal statement
          of his plans. He had resigned as Sec
          retary of Commerce and Labor as soon
          as he was elected chairman, the resig
          nation to take effect as soon as bis
          successor qualifies, which will be about
          July 1. Secretary Cortelyou will nor
          give any active time to political mat
          ters until he retires from the Cabinet.
          XO VICE CHAIRMAN.
          Bearer of Tidings Finds Him
          Chatting With Members
          of His Family.
          New National Committee Se
          lects the Manager for
          the Campaign.
          MR, ROOSEVELT
          UNCONCERNEDLY
          AWAITS RESULT
          HANNA'S PLACE
          NOW OCCUPIED
          BY CORTELVOU
          When the convention was called to
          order to-day the galleries were filled'
          for the first time. Tiers of people
          wer standing in the aisles and back
          of the rows of seats. Former Gover
          nor Black's introduction to make the
          Roosevelt nominating speech was the
          fcignal fop the first outburst of ap
          plause. Black led ud to the nomina
          tion by gradually defining: the type of
          man best suited for the party's color
          bearer. As he named Theodore j
          CROWD PACKS COLISEUM.
          When Senator Fairbanks had been
          nominated for Vice President there was
          no diminution in the demonstration.
          The voices were hoarse, but the shout-
          Ing was as general as it was for the
          head of the ticket.
          The delegates in their eagerness to
          exhibit approval of the nomination
          accepted every signal for renewed
          -cheering. A little colored boy from
          Georgia, and later a pretty little girl
          dressed in a dainty frock of white, were
          lifted to the platform, where they
          waved flags vigorously.
          At the conclusion of every seconding
          speech the outburst was repeated, and
          the speakers themselves were generally
          applauded.
          The chairman tired and his place was
          taken by a young man, who grasped
          the flagstaff firmly in one hand and
          with a megaphone led the yelling. He
          started to yell, "Roosevelt, Roosevelt,
          Roosevelt," repeated over a^d over
          over again, with the system of a college
          yell. It was taken up by the throng,
          and the cry of "Jioosevelt" rolled over
          the hall in volumes so great and so ter
          rific that the screeching of a hundred
          steam whistrw v/ouid have been
          dwarfed in comparison.
          LIKE A COLLEGE YELL.
          When Governor Black of New York
          made his speech nominating President
          Roosevelt to succeed himself as Presi
          dent, the delegates in the Republican
          Convention proved there was no ab-
          Fcnce of enthusiasm in their ranks
          when occasion Justified an exhibition
          cf that Quality. For twenty-five min
          utes the great throng told its approba
          tion of the convention's choice for
          President. The name of Roosevelt
          came from every mouth. The New
          York delegates paraded the hall, shout
          ing at the top of their voices. Other
          delegations joined the procession, and
          the- weJ! ordered body of a half hour
          before was a shifting mass, every
          eemblance of organization gone.
          While the demonstration was at its
          height Chairman Cannon stepped to
          the front of tne stage. He held in his
          hand the banner which was waved in
          1SG0 when Lincoln was nominated, and
          •which fcas been used in every conven
          tion since. The flex showed the wear
          and tear of many similar contests.
          "Uncle Joe" wa\-cd It vigorously and
          kept time with his body. Soon the
          ¦whole convention was swaying in exact
          measure.
          1 rfiii^'i by a resounding demonstration
          vbich attested the candidates' great
          popularity. The charing was l=d by
          figures known through the breadth of
          the land and echoed by a mighty
          throne of enthusiastic men and radiant
          vomen assembled in the Coliseum to
          witness the crowning feature of the
          convention, as well as the close of th*
          rational meeting that marks the semi
          centennial of the Republican party in
          the United States.
          No less than 10,000 men and women
          participated in the ratification of the
          party programme and the consequent
          roar of cheering and handclapping was
          de&amp;feninp. The band, stationed high
          among tho girders of the hall, was
          browned by the tumultuous, unbounded
          demonstration. Hats were tossed into
          the air, State emblems were waved
          and flags beautiful, tri-colored, shim
          mering, silktn flags fluttered from
          every hand, as though stirred by a
          RIOT OF ENTHUSIASM.
          Rpjrardkss of the fart that th«> nomi-
          nation of one had b«*en assured for
          months and the other for day». the an- I
          naiirf-riieni of the choice was accom- j
          CHICAGO. June 13.— Th« swift, sure
          current Qf public opinion for the sec
          ond time in thp history cf Republican
          conventions to-day resulted in the se
          lection cf a national ticket without a
          dissenting vote. Theodore Roosevelt
          for President and Charles W. Fair
          banks for Vice President received every
          vote in the convention.
          Henry T. Oxnard will go to New
          York" to-morrow. Oxnard dined with
          Senators Lodge and Penrose, Mayor
          Weaver of Philadelphia, Mr. Aldrldgs
          of Chicago and Judge Van Fleet of San
          Francisco at the Chicago Club this
          evening.
          Joseph Steffens will visit Eastern
          cities before his return home. George
          W Reed will start west in a day or
          so. W. I* Crooks will visit relatives
          in Indiana. M. A. Gunst and family
          Delegate A. Rucf will go to New
          York. Philadelphia and Washington
          and then to St. Louis. George A.
          Knight will leave to-morrow for New
          York. He ¦will return home by %vay of
          St. Louis. B. H. Reymers and daush
          ter will go to Europe for an extended
          tour.
          Governor Pardee. his wife and two
          pretty daughters left on to-night's
          train for St. Louis. To-morrow Judge
          McKlnley and wife of Los Angeles will
          leave for the exposition city and prob
          ably will have as company on the train
          Delegates John H. Norton, F. K. Rule.
          Oacar Lawler, Judge Van Fleet. Frank
          H. Short. J. G. Priestly. Mitchell Phil
          lips and wife. C. L» Clinch, E. D. Rob
          erts and A- D. Porter.
          Jacob Steppacher will visit his sis
          ter In Philadelphia before departing
          for home by way of St. Louis.
          Of the other Callfornlans in the city.
          Colonel Kowalsky will start for Eu
          rope to-morrow, accompanied by "Hon
          est Bob." his colored valet, who won
          distinction on the delegation's special
          train by finding and returning .to its
          owner a handful of diamond-set jewel
          ry- Fulton G. Berry of Fresno will
          spend a month at Lake Beulah visiting
          his talented daughter, Maud Lillian
          Berry. He will return to Chicago on
          Sundays, he says, to enjoy yachting on
          Lake Michigan.
          "Geography counts but little with the
          sentiment and enthusiasm that is to
          day apparent in favor of one who is to
          be given all the honors anoTduties of
          an elected President of the United
          States," Knight said when silence was
          restored. Continuing in epigramatic
          style he thrilled the convention for
          many minutes. His voice never fal
          tered. His name was spoken in terms
          of congratulation on every side. When
          he had ceased, and with waving ban
          ners the California delegation marched
          to the platform to escort him to his
          seat, the great Coliseum rocked with
          the cheers of the multitude.
          California's headquarters were in
          darkness to-night. The wines and fruits
          had been distributed among the fortu
          nate friends cf the delegates and the
          last toast had been drunk. Several of;
          the delegates have departed already,
          and more will go to-morrow. "Within
          three days the last California delegata
          will have departed from Chicago.
          PARDEE GOES TO -T. LOUIS.
          Again the tempest broke. Out of the
          wilderness of silence had come a
          human voice. It had been heard and
          understood. The convention was over
          joyed: its enthusiasm must find vent.
          THRILLS THE CONTENTION.
          Knight's voice reached to the farthest
          pillar and echoed back from the giant
          arches. With a howl of delight the con
          vention arose, and the waving flags
          with their crimson stripes were like a
          sea of flame. Speaker Cannon, with
          the gavel in his left hand pounding for
          order and his right uplifted command
          ing silence. wa3 ignored. For minutes
          the uproar continued. "When silence
          came again Knight continued:
          ••Geography counts
          HEADQUARTERS CALIFORNIA
          DELEGATION*. CHICAGO. June 23
          California's triumph came to-day In the
          national convention. Her triumph was
          that of George A. Knight, th« eloquent
          lawyer of San Francisco. From 10:3*
          o'clock until long after noon the per
          spirins delegates had been listening to
          the*disiineuished men of the East. Ex-
          Governor 'Black of New York had
          placed Mr. Roosevelt In nomination,
          and Senator Boveridge of Indiana had
          delivered the iirst seconding speech. To
          those in the rear galleries and side
          seats their efforts were nausht but
          mere pantomime. No sound strayed
          from a direct line in front of the plat
          form until Knight opened his masterly
          address.
          "Gentlemen of the convention—"
          Staff Correspondent oi The Call.
          BY FREDERIC W. BISHOP,
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1904-06-24/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Roosevelt+Fairbanks+Republican+Convention+Vice+President</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          ROOSEVELT-FAIRBANKS
          Republicans Nominate Them With
          Boundless Enthusiasm.
          CHICAGO CONVENTION'S GOOD WORK
          For President THEODORE ROOSEVELT, of New York
          For Vice President CHARLES \V. FAIRBANKS, of Indiana
          This ticket was presented 1W live suffrages of the American people
          by the Republican National Convention which concluded its work in Chi
          cago yesterday.
          The nominations were unanimously made, and the proceedings were
          marked by a spontaneity of enthusiasm and heartiness of sentiment that
          augur the certainty of election.
          The nominating speeches by ex -Governor Frank S. Black for the
          President and by Senator Jonathan P. Dolliver for the Vice-President,
          with the seconding speeches by Senators Bereridge, Depew, Foraker and
          others, were received with every demonstration of approval.
          When ex-Governor Black had named the President to succeed him
          self the enthusiasm was unbounded and the tumult of applause could not
          be stayed for twenty-three minutes by the clock.
          The same exhibitions of delight marked the presentation of the name
          of Senator Fairbanks for the second office in the #it't of the nation.
          Secretary Cortelyou was unanimously chosen a.s chairman of the
          National Committee, resigning as the head of the Department of Com
          merce and Lahor immediately after his election.
          The President received the news at the White House, and con
          gratulatory messages were interchanged between him and Senator Fair
          banks.
          The Committee on Notification, headed by Speaker Cannon, will
          officially inform the President at Oyster Bay on July 27. Another com
          mittee, headed by ex-Secretary Root, wiU wait on Senator Fairbanks in
          Indianapolis on August 8. f
          LEADERS CHOSEN WITH NO DISSENTING VOU'K.
          SUMMARY OF PROCEEDINGS.
          Convention called to order at 10 o'clock
          by Chairman Cannon.
          Prayer by the Rev. Thaddeus A. Snively.
          Call for nominations for President.
          Name of President Roosevelt presented by
          ex-Governor Frank S. Black; seconding
          speeches by Senator Beveridge and others.
          Roll of States called and President Roose
          velt nominated unanimously.
          Call for nominations for Vice-President.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045366/1904-07-06/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Democratic+Democrats+Convention+Alton+Parker+Turner+Ticket+Nomination&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.162,0,1.324,1.324,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          hf"
          W%KmW^rW^
          11**
          1 JnLHi
          PRICE TWO CENTS.
          23st Compiled From Prepaid
          Ticket Numbers by the A. E.*"
          Johnson Company.
          SOME OF THE NAMES
          IN LIST OF RESCUED
          Several Whole Families Bound for
          Minnesota Wiped Out by the
          Disaster.
          Of the total passenger list of the
          steamer Norge 451 tickets we re sold by
          the A. E Johnson agencies In this
          country the remainder abroad. Pas
          sengers for the northwest numbered
          126. Immediately after news of the
          disaster, Mr, Johnson, at the head
          office In New York, set a
          force of clerks at wo rk pre
          paring from the ticket numbers as
          complete a list as possible of prepaid
          passengers who sailed in this vessel.
          The tremendous task was quickly a c
          complished and to-day the list of
          northwestern passengers reach ed the
          Minneapolis office.
          This list will be read with great in
          terest in the northwest, where so many
          of the ill-fated passengers were bound.
          The list, giving name, age and des
          tination is as follows.
          Northwestern Passengers.
          Anders Person 26, Cottonwood, Minn.
          Fr. J. Holmqulat, 18 Grove City, Minn.
          Kersten Hurd, 20, Llndstrom, Minn.
          Hanaluo L&amp;ngaan, Jttcknon, Minn.
          UUwaul Bonn, 34, Madison, S. D.
          Ole JenseD, 28, Willniar, Minn.
          Jens Danleluon, 18, Gerh Dnnlelson, 18, Weta
          klwin, Canada.
          Johiimiu Arneson, 17, Wlllmar, Minn.
          Rolf Vaagaasen, 17, OlTar Vaagaasen, 18,
          Richaidton, N
          Knri Larson, 22, Fosston, Minn
          Mrs. Anna England, BO. Anton, England. 9
          Earold England. 7. Hedvlg England, 4, Anna
          England, 2, La Moure, N. D.
          Anton Alitad, Mayville, N. D.
          Mrs Elma Vlk, 36 John Vlk. 18. Hriga Vik,
          11, Hans Vik, 10, \lbln Vlk, 8, Thoiolf Vik.
          6 Selmu Vlk, 4, Dallas, Wis.
          Karl Englund, 18, La Moure N. D.
          Lasse Ophflm, 18 Meckinock, N. D.
          Jorgen 0. Berkeland, 17, Kersten Berkeland.
          10 Fisher. Minn
          Margaret Aaihus, 20, Lanesboro, Minn.
          Karon Hanson, 20, Pelican Hapids, Minn.
          Karl Mathjeson, 27 *Mr. Mathiewa and
          two childien Devflbr Lalce? ~N I
          Hehner Batten, 21. Denbigh. N. D.
          '4 Lisa Hagen, IT, Denbigh, N.
          Jens Jonannesen, SO, Mrs J*nannesen, 60
          Elnei Johannesen, 17, Albert Johannesen, 14,
          Ellsworth. Wis
          Hans Olson, 18, Brandt, S H.%.
          i Bernhatd ArneSen. 28, Sioux Fans S. D.
          Emma Pedersen, 20, Sioux Falls, 3. D.
          Ingeborg Oiaa*. 27, Sioux Falls, S D.
          Johanna Kodset, 20, Mllaca, Minn.
          Johanna Jesperson, 10, Cummings, N. D.
          Anton Holderson, Dalton, Minn
          Andrew Krestenson, 47, Mrs Thea Krestenson,
          40, Karen Krestenson, 17, Theodor Krestenson,
          12, Thora Krestenson, 8, Hedvlg Krestenson, 4|
          Johan KiesteuSon, 2, one Infant, Dallas, Wis.
          Kniit Hanson. 21, Walcott, N. D.
          Helmer Olson, Devils Lake, N D.
          Herman Post, 18 Hutchinson, Minn.
          1 Jorgenson, 17, Mlnot, N D.
          Justin M. Wedin, 85, Martin Wedln. 10, Jo
          tan Wedln, 17, Alma Wedln, 14, Fridlot Wedln,
          11 Frlda, 0, Frans, 7, Thune, 4, Hugo, 8, onO
          Infant, Little Falls, Minn.
          Olga Jeremlason, 21, Elbow Lake, Minn.
          Sivert Boe, 20 Gary, Minn.
          Johan Toreerson, Spring Grove, Minn.
          Jonas O Nilson, 20, Sandstone, Minn.
          Johan Larson, Horace, N. D.
          John Stromberg, 23, Mora, Minn.
          Johanna Bergemoen, 38, Bertha Bergemoen, 9
          #fai'la Bergemoen, 7. Andreas Bergemoen, 4
          Anna Bergemoen, 3, Bottineau, N.
          Hans O.
          Olson,Hokanson,
          18,
          1
          1
          Clarkfield,Edna
          ^f^m^jm
          Minn.
          Mr Mathild a 87. Hokanson,
          1largretr
          1 Iva Hokanson, 10, Mathilda Hokanson, 9
          a Hokanson, 7, Sine Hokanson, 4, Johan
          Hokanson, 3. one infant, Parker's Prairie,
          Minn
          Thorborg Cornelluson, Ounvald Corneliuson,
          Herman Cornelluson, 14i Ella Corneliuson, 10,
          Arthur Corneliuson, 8, Henrlk Corneliuson, 8,
          .West Superior, Wis.
          Ole Moen. 26. Vienna, S D.
          i- Aalln P. Severtson, 20. Baldwin, Wis.
          Hans H. Wing, 48, Doroethea Wang, 45, Shell
          I Lake, Wis.
          I Mrs. Katjirlne Bratnstedt, 34, Enghardt Bram
          ftedt, 11 Jennie (0) Gerda (4), Guetaf (3), one
          infant. Hendrurn, Minn
          Katnrln .Svenson, 21 Lauris Svenson, 3, Mar
          taus Svenson, Wllmot, S.
          Lam Is R. Laursen, 20, Vermillion, S. D.
          i Sigurd Amundsdatter, 43, Ingeberg Amunds*
          'flatter, 17, Torger Amundsdatter, 15, and three
          Children, Thompson. N. D.
          Asblorn Bjerge, 10, Bryant, S. D.
          Karl Varhaug, Fosston, Minn.
          Nils O Nelson, 10, Honeyford, N D.
          Ludvig Bettolfaan, 23,'Glenwood, Minn.
          Selma Osbeck. 20, Dunnell. Minn.
          Sofia O Anderson, 05, Anna E. Karlson, 16,
          acy, Minn,
          ugust Rystrom. 28 Westboro, Wis.
          'istaf II Johann^son, 17, Kensington, Minn,
          ir.Jls D. Nelson, Windom. Minn.
          Anton Olsen, Northv%ood, N. t.
          Erik Nelson, Wells, Minn.
          Pernllle H. Berven Portland, Ore.
          Name appears In list of rescued.
          MORE SURVIVORS FOUND
          Another Boat Lands After Six Days of
          Privations.
          Aberdeen, Scotland, Ju ly 6.Anot h
          boat, containing seventeen survivors
          of the Danish steam er Norge, which
          foundered off Rochall reef June 28,
          h'-was landed at Aberdeen, Scotland, last
          flight by the steam trawler Largo Bay.
          The contingent now being cared for
          rat" Aberdeen consists of twelve pas
          sengers, the third mate of the Norge,
          the quartermaster, a steward, a lamp
          {.trimmer and one of the crew. They
          drifted at the mercy of the Atlantic
          .for six days. When both water and
          food were gone, and when the occu
          pants were almost too exhaust ed even
          to hope, the trawler hove in sight on
          .Ju ly 4. They had eked out an exist
          ence on two biscuits a day.
          When the survivors we re dragged on
          boa rd the trawler the fishermen we re
          i obliged foroibly to prevent them from
          eating and drinking too much.
          The third mate says that three other
          boats started with that rescued by the
          Largo Bay. One of those contained
          thirty-two persons, including several
          women and children. Another boat
          had fifteen men, with the second mate
          \in charge. The third boat had ten
          men on board. The survivors parted
          company with the three boats on
          July 3.
          For these boats the British gunboat
          Leda, the government fishing cutter
          Jackal, the steamer chartered by the
          t)anish consul at Glasgow and several
          xi other vessels are diligently searching.
          Partial Idst of Survivors.
          New York, Ju ly 6.A partial list of
          J- the survivors has been giv en out at
          Continued on Sixth Page,
          f*n
          REPUBLICANSHAVE
          BIRTHDAY PARTY
          Secretary Hay Orator at Semicen
          tennial of Party at Jack
          son, Mich.
          Jackson, Mich., Ju ly 6.Five thou
          sand people assembled in Loomls
          park here tod ay to celebrate the fif
          tieth anniversary of the birth of the
          republican party "under the oaks" in
          this city July 6, 1854. It was here
          then that the first state convention,
          acting under the name of "republi-
          can," was held. The state ticket
          nominated on that day went thru a
          heated campaign to election day suc
          cess.
          Secretary of State John Hay, who
          was private secretary to Abraham
          Lincoln, the first republican president,
          was the orator of the day. Other dis
          tinguished guests present weie Speak
          er Cannon of the national house of
          representatives, Senators C. W Fair
          banks of Indiana, republican candi
          date for vice president, and United
          States Senators R. A. Alger and J. C.
          Burrows of Michigan.
          James O'Donnell of Jackson pre
          sided at the morning exercises. Mayor
          William H. Todd of Jackson wel
          comed the visitors, and Governor
          Aaron T. Bliss responded. Attorney
          General Charles A. Blair of Jackson
          read a paper on the history of the
          republican party. Thomas J. O'Brien
          of Grand Rapids, the next speaker,
          was one of the participants in the
          original "under the oak s" convention
          of 1864.
          An interesting feature of the exer
          cises was a body of Fremont voters,
          for whom 1,000 prominent seats had
          been reserved. Grand Army uni
          forms, crutches and silvered locks
          were conspicuo us among them.
          The distinguished guests attended a
          reception at the Hotel Otsego at noon.
          Address of Secretary Hay.
          Soon after p.m. the program at the
          grove was resumed. Senator J. O.
          Burrows of Michigan introduoed Sec
          retary John Hay, the orator of the af
          ternoon.
          Secretary Hay reviewed the record
          of the republican party since its be
          ginning with the ability of a states
          ma n, a historian and an orator com
          bine(W* Perhaps he, as no other man
          In the country, knows the history of
          the party. When it Is said,-therefore,
          that his review of the party's past was
          masterly, the word "masterly
          all that it an mean as -so applied.
          Mr. Hay, passing from the history of
          the party to the present and imme
          diate future, said, in part:
          W are not claiming that we monopo
          lize the virue of the patriotism of the
          country There are good men all par
          ties, I know far better men than I am
          who are democrats. But we are surely
          allowed, in a lo\e feast like this, to talk
          of what has been done by the family and
          at least to brag a little of the democrats
          who have helped us. We come before the
          country in a position which cannot be
          successfully attacked in front, or flank,
          or rear. What we have done, what -we
          are doing, and what we intend to doon
          all three we confidently challenge the
          verdict of the American people The
          record of fifty years will show whether as
          a party we are fit to govern the state of
          our domestic and foreign affairs will
          show whether as a party we have fallen
          off," and both together will show whether
          we can be trusted for a while longer.
          7 means
          The 1004 Platform.
          Our platform Is before the country.
          There is certainly nothing sensational
          about it It is substantially the platform
          on which we won two great victories in
          the name of McKinley, and it is still
          sound and serviceable. Its principles have
          been tested by eight years of splendid
          success and have received the approval
          of the country. We stand by the ancient
          nays which have proved good.
          It would take a wizard to guess what a
          dainty dish our adversaries will set before
          the sovereign people tomorrow. One thing
          is reasonably sure: They will get as near
          to our platform as they possibly can and
          they will by implication approve everything
          McKinley and Roosevelt have done In the
          last four years. They will favor sound
          finance and a tariff which will not disturb
          business rigid honesty in administration
          and prompt punishment of the dishonest
          the Monroe doctrine and an isthmian
          canal. To be logical they ought to go on
          and nominate the republican candidates
          who are pledged to all these laudable poli
          cies.
          Roosevelt as an Issue,
          But they will not be logical. They an
          nounce* their plan of campaign to be not
          pro-anything, but anti-Roosevelt.
          Even on this issue they will dodge most
          of the details. Ask them, has the presi
          dent been a good citizen, a good soldier, a
          good man in all personal relations? Is
          he a man of Intelligence, of education?
          Does he Know this country well? Does he
          know the world outside? Has he studied
          law, history, and politics? Has he had
          great chances to learn, and has he im
          proved them? Is he sound and strong in
          mind, body and soul? Is he accessible and
          friendly to all sorts and conditions of
          men? Has he the courage and the candor,
          and the God-given ability to speak to the
          people and tell them what he thinks?
          To all these questions they will answer
          yes Then what is your objection to
          him? They will either stand speechless or
          they will answer with the parrot cry
          which we have heard so often: He is un
          safe!
          In a certain sense we shall have to ad
          mit this to be true. To every grade of
          lawbreaker, high or low to a man who
          would rob a till or a ballot box t$ the
          sneak or the bully to the hypocrite and
          the humbug, Theodore Roosevelt is more
          than unsafe he is positively dangerous.
          Coefficients of Safety.
          But- let us be serious with these good
          people. What are the coefficients of safety
          in a chief of state? He should have cour
          age the wisest coward that ever lived Is
          not fit to rule. And intelligence we wa"nt
          no blunder-headed hero in the White
          House. And honesty a clever thief would
          do infinite mischief. These three are the
          Continued-on Sixth Page,
          firr^hfU^d^

          PASSENGER LIST OF THE WRECKED STEAMSHIP NORGE
          SHOWS MANY NAMES OF PASSENGERS BOUND FOR NORTHWEST

          NORGE HAD 126
          FOR NORTHWEST
          J. W. BAILEY,
          Texas Senator, Who Will Be Per
          manent Chairman.
          BAILEY OF TEXAS
          TO BE CHAIRMAN
          Four Hundred Tammany Braves
          Make Vain Appeal for
          Seats.
          St. Louis, July 6.Senator Hill a n
          nounced this morning that United
          States Senator Joseph W Bail ey of
          Texas had been agreed upon for per
          manent chairman of the convention.
          Outside of this announcement there
          was little doing about New York's
          headquarters this morning except a
          vigorous demand by 400 Tamany
          braves for seats in the convention
          a demand which National Committee
          man Mack could not gratify. Sena
          tor Grady of New Yo rk appealed to
          Senator Hill, but the latter told him
          he could not assist him.
          Then Senator Grady accused the
          Hill people of bad faith, and said that
          th ey were purposely keeping out the
          Tammany people to prevent applause
          Jtpr ftny, othe*^&amp;>n *!Mq$w)Mft
          BBITONS STORM AND
          TAKE TIBETAN FORT
          Gyang Tse, Tibet, July 6.An as
          sault by a British storm party of
          Ghurknas and fusiliers on the Jong
          (fort) here was successful. The fort
          was captured. The Tibetans fiercely
          resisted. Lieutena nt Gordon of the
          Thirty-second Sikhs is among the
          killed, but the British casualties were
          not great.
          WILD RIDE DOWN MOUNTAIN.
          Denver, Col July 6.Two persons were
          killed and forty-seven injured yesterday
          afternoon in a car which broke loose from
          a t"aln and dashed down the mountain
          side near Cripple Creek.
          WEDNESDAY EVENING, JULY 6, 1904.
          DEMOCRATS MEET IN NATIONAL CONVENTION.SQOICTY
          PARKER AND TURNER, THE PROBABLE TICKET
          **f
          HEARST MEN RIDE
          OYER JOHN LIKD
          Congressman Thrice Beaten in
          Apportioning of Honors by
          Minnesota Delegation.
          From a Staff Correspondent.
          St. Louis, July f.The Hearst
          squadron rode roughshod over John
          Lind in the Minnesota delegation
          meeti ng last night A a result, Min
          nesota's most distinguished democrat
          is witho ut a place of a ny kind in the
          organization of the convention. None
          but Hearst men 4yere put on guard.
          Mr. Lind himself is disposed to be
          philosophical, and laughs at the three
          hour squabble, but he to ok a most
          active part in it while it lasted. A
          for is friends, they are bitter in de
          nounci ng the Hearst men for turning
          down their old leader. The mildest
          term applied to the Hearst delegates
          is that they are ""crazy."
          The discussion' la st night ranged
          over every Incident of the recent state
          campaign, which was fought over
          aga in in every gory detail. Frank
          Larrabee and H. L. Buck, who led the
          debate for the Hearst men, plainly
          said they did net, consider Lind a
          proper representative of the delega
          tion, because fce^as a Parker man
          and in work on tfi(e platform commit
          tee would followpthe dictates of his
          candidate.
          Mr. Lind resen^l this. said he
          had no desire for a. place of any kind,
          but did not wajafcUo.
          plac ed in a
          false position-
          It would make |*f difference to him
          in shaping the plsMtform what candi
          date was to be nominated, except that
          he would fa#or a^more conservative
          platform if Hearst shou ld be named.
          expressed himself quite satisfied
          with Mr. Bryan's platform, and said
          he would like to jSJee it presented by
          Bryan himself. once more stated
          his determination 4 .retire from pub
          lic office. A,.
          Pleas for Iftod Futile.
          C. t. O'Brien watf T. D. O'Brien
          pleaded hard for raoognition of Mr.
          Lind on accounti of Ills record, his in
          fluence and his Standing, in the^,j?arty,
          but their pleas wete* in vain^ The
          Hearst men who 3*fd lost B Duluth
          had a chance to getf^evenge and final
          victory*j. and did not propose to be
          -Tftey put thU slate thru just as It
          was tt^f&amp;'W&amp;? fWfB**- 9JM* exception.
          They hacVslated Lind for\chairman of
          the delegation &amp;nd when the caucus
          met proposed his name. declined
          flatty and H. L. Buck was then named.
          This started a dlscussion,\ which
          lasted for an hour, ending In a, test
          vote, on Which the anti-Hear st 'men
          voted for Rosing. Buck was elected
          by the following vote: For Buck
          Mayo, Craven, Larrabee, Corrigan,
          Vasaly, Mealey, Evans, Q'Hair, Saf
          ford, D'Autremont, Ny e, Buck, 12.
          For RosingLind, O'Brien, Rosing,
          Virtue, Day, Taylor, Gress, Armsott,
          O'Connor, Thompson, 10.
          Mr. Llnd's name was then presented
          for member of the committee on reso
          lutions by C. D. O'Brien. Frank Lar
          rabee named C. B. Vasaly of Little
          Continued from First Page.
          SOMETHING WRONG,
          ^MX-m%*&amp;s$sm Hypnotist Bryan seems to bare lost control over bis patient.
          JOHN SHARP WILLIAMS,
          Temporary Chairman of Democratic
          National Convention.
          PARKER SEEMS TO
          BE FAR IN LEAD
          Nomination of New Yorker Prob
          able, Tho Opponents May
          Defeat Him.
          From a Btaff Correspondent.
          St. Louis, July 6.The opening day
          oil the democratic national convention
          sees the situation as to the presiden
          tial nomination unchanged. Parker
          Is far in the lead and is nomination
          seems likely. A the same time,
          however, his prospects are no more
          favorable at this time than tho se of
          many a defeated candidate for the
          nomination have been before him and
          it may yet be possible for his enemieB
          to concentrate against him and defeat
          hi m. The fact that thjy are as actively
          at ~woric tod ay as at any previous
          time, and profess to be hopeful of,
          success, makes confident prediction
          that Parker will certainly be nomin
          ated somewhat unsafe.
          The trend of even ts is so distinctly
          toward Parker, however, as to indi
          cate his early nomination, possibly by
          the second ballot. If it were a betting
          proposition, I shou ld say the chances
          were at least seven out of ten in Park
          er's favor.
          Tammany is now acting as it did in
          1892, when it counseled against their
          renominati on of Cleveland, saying he
          could not carry New York. A form al
          statement of the Tammany position
          was giv en out in Chicago when the
          convention was in progress. The con
          vention disregarded the opposition ot
          Tammany and renominated Cleveland.
          It looks as if it would again disre
          gard this same opposition, and nomi
          nate Parker.
          MNESOTA
          HISTOH1CAL
          PAIR TONIGHT AND THURSDAY COOLER TONIGHT
          14 PAGESFIVE O'CLOCK.
          EIGHT MINUTES OF
          CLEVELAND CHEERS
          Row Develops in Demonstration Evoked by
          John Sharp Williams and Brooklyn Deler
          gate Is Ejected from Hall by the
          Sergeant-at-Arms.
          St. Louis, Ju ly 6.Exactly at noon
          Chairman J. K. Jones of the national
          committee called the democratic na
          tional convention to order. His ap
          pearance on the platform and the
          sou nd of his gavel brought forth a
          cheer from the floor and galleries.
          Chairman Jon es directed the ser
          geant-at-arms to secure order.
          continued belaboring the table with
          his gavel but it was some time before
          quiet reigned.
          the time the hall was one-third
          filled the heat had begun to increase
          to a noticeable degree. The great ma
          jority of the delegates and visitors had^
          provided themselves with fans and the'
          auditorium viewed from the speaker's
          desk was one yellow flutter, as th?
          palm-leaf fans bobbed back and forth.
          The delegates lost but little time in
          removing their coats, and the com
          plexion of the lower part of the hall,
          black at first, became lighter and
          lighter, as the ooats disappeared and
          the shirtsleeves became evident.
          The first ripple of applause that
          went across the convention came
          from the galleries when the Texas del
          egation marched In bearing their flag
          of red, white and blue, with the single
          star.
          A white silk banner beari ng the in
          scription* "Florida democracy safe and
          sound," was borne into the hall short
          ly after the Texans had arrived, and
          was also greeted with applause.
          This was five minutes, before 12,
          and up to that time not a handolap
          had been offered to a ny man who had
          entered the hall. The platform was
          crowded with members of the national
          committe e, but the crowd paid no at
          tention to them.
          The Fhilippino delegation came in
          with their banner, which was not
          floating free like those that had
          tered before it. It was an American the cheers and cries fell, there would
          flag of Bilk wrapped closely arou nd
          the staff and tied hard and fast. This
          was done, aocordlng to one of the
          Philippine delegation, "with deliber
          ate intent," as if to show that the
          democratic convention did not recog
          nize the Philippines as part of the
          nation.
          Chairman Guffy of Pennsylvania
          strode in closely behind t*ie Philippine
          flag' and,"WKs~1*eiR*trry
          -cheered.
          California's appearance with a huge
          silk bann er mad" -sttk- ^Asnscrican flags
          and a' yell "California, California?
          Hearst, Hearst, Hearst," caus ed cheer
          ing.
          Bryan Rose for a Cheer.
          Just as the California delegation
          reached its reservation after march
          ing up and down the center aisle, Wm.
          J. Bryan, who had come in unnoticed,
          arose in his place and was giv en a
          cheer. Then an enterprising member
          of the Montana delegation created a
          diversion by vigorously ringing a cow
          bell.
          Again Chairman Jones demanded
          that the conventi on be in order and at
          once directed the secretary to read the
          call for the convention.
          Applause followed the readi ng of
          the call. After quiet was restored,
          Chairman Jones announced that the
          convention would be opened by prayer
          by Rev. John Cannon, pastor of
          Grand Avenue Baptist church of S
          Louis.
          During the invocation the conven
          tion stood. Dr. Cannon's voice was
          entirely inadequate to reach even the
          oenter of the hall. The prayer occu
          pied several minute s.
          Enthusiastio cheering greeted the
          chairman 's announcement that he was
          directed by the national committee to
          appoint John Sharp Williams tem
          porary chairman and C. A. Walsh
          temporary secretary, and John Mar
          tin, temporary sergeant-at-arms.
          The chairman appoint ed Colonel J.
          M. Guffey of Pennsylvania and M.
          Harper of California to esoort Mr.
          Williams to the chair. A the plat
          form was inclosed by a railing, it
          was necessary for the committee
          and Mr. Williams to climb over the
          railing. The committee lifted Mr.
          Williams safely over and the entire
          conventi on burst into cheers as he
          ascended the platform.
          "I have the honor to introduce to
          you John S. Williams as temporary
          chairman," said Chairman Jones, and
          again the convention cheered.
          Williams Speaks.
          Mr. Williams was attired in a light
          gray suit and a'white waistcoat.
          delivered his address calmly and with
          out gestures. Several cries of "louder,
          louder," interrupted Mr. Williams as
          he began, his clear but not powerful
          voice at first failing to reach parts of
          the hall.
          A Williams proceeded, is
          voice increased in volume and the
          delegates listened attentively.
          Convention Amused.
          The convention appear ed consider
          ably amused at Mr. Williams' humor
          ously sarcastic references to the "mu-
          tual admiration society" of Mr. Roose
          velt and Mr. Root, and when he read
          a eulogy by the president on Mr.
          Root, the delegates laughed and ap
          plauded.
          Mr. Willjpms spoke in an ironical
          tone that caught the fancy of the
          convention, and he was interrupted
          time and time aga in by laughter.
          Cheering was evoked by the speaker's
          statement that Mr. Rooseve lt had
          found praise for only three presi
          dents"Geor ge Washington, Abraham
          Lincoln and himself"and when he
          asked if the "hell-roaring Jake
          Smith" order was a sample of the
          moral sentiment for which the repub
          licans stood, a lusty cheer broke forth.
          A great part of Mr. Williams'
          speech was delivered under great dif
          ficulties, for the speak er and tho se
          of his heare rs who were suppos ed to
          be most directly interested in is re
          marks. The aisles leading past the
          delegates we re packed by dense
          throngs, who kept up a constant hum
          of conversation that smothered Mr.
          William s' voice. Policemen who we re
          in the space arou nd the
          1stationed
          platform to keep others away, did it
          by occupying the space themselves to
          the exclusion of all others.

          times the speaker stopped and asked
          that the talking cease in order that
          he might make himself better under
          stood.
          Mr. Williams mentioned the name
          of Mr. Bryan in discussing the price
          of wheat during the first Bryan-Mo
          Kinley campaign. The utterance of
          the name called forth a little applause
          and some cheers. A second later
          mentioned the name again and the
          applause was not repeated.
          Cheer lor Cleveland.
          A mention of the name of Grove*
          Cleveland was cheered lustily. A mo~
          ment later the first scene of the ses-,
          sion occurred. Mr. Williams declared I
          that it was a brazen effrontery for the'
          republican party to attempt to seize
          the laurels of Grover Cleveland. A
          genuine outburst of applause fo l
          lowed.
          Cheer after oheer rolled thru the
          hall, and altho the chairman used the
          gavel vigorously the convention was
          soon beyo nd his control. New Hamp
          shire delegates climbed upon their
          seats and yelled vigorously. One Iowa
          man of the Hearst-instructed delega
          tion from that commonwealth, stood
          up and waved his hat frantically, and
          a wild chorus answered him.
          "Three chee rs for Grover Cleve-
          land," shouted an Alabama delegate,
          and they oame with genuine power
          and enthusiasm. N cry came from
          Nebraska, where Mr. Bryan and is
          friends sat. quietly, without taking
          part in the noise. Again and again
          the cheers came in dense volume, de
          spite numerous cries of "order," and
          the strenuous pounding of the ohalr
          man's gavel.
          Then Mr. Williams sat back and
          watched the sce ne he had created. As,
          be a renewed outbreak and the dem
          onstration lasted eight minute s. f/^
          Brawl in Center.
          r&amp;
          Tim Murphy of St. Louis, standing'
          in the center aisle and encouraging
          the demonstration, was first requested
          to take his seat and then ejected from
          the hall by John I. Martin, sergeant
          at-arms. Murphy wa^jrushed towarde
          the platform byr Martin thru a railing
          and down a narrow-stairway leading
          omder th* ^tage. i
          Another "encounter between Murphy*
          and Martin to ok place in the passage
          way under the stage. Murphy then
          permitt ed himself to be taken from
          the hall by two officers.
          Murphy said that he endeavored to
          assist in securing quiet, but his efforts
          were misunderstood, a,nd at the direc
          tion of Sergeant-at-Arms Martin he
          was forcibly ejected from the floor by
          a policeman, and landed among the
          newspaper men. Here he endeavored
          to explain that he had been acting in
          the interests of quiet and order, but
          his explanations fell on a deaf ear,
          and despite his expostulations and
          threats, he was finally taken from the
          building by the police in charge of
          Captain Schroeder.
          For several minutes after the Mur
          phy incident the demonstration con
          tinued. Finally, In desperation, Mr.
          Williams threaten ed to discontinue is
          speech.
          "You have placed me here, I am
          your servant. If you don't want me
          to continue, it is your pleasure," he
          oried.
          This announcement was effective
          and Mr. Williams secured control, the
          demonstration that his mention of
          Cleveland had caused, dying slowly
          out.
          When he said that he had heard
          that Dewey, Schley and Miles were
          democrats, that a .republican admin
          istration had snubbed the first, tried to
          disgrace the second and insulted the
          third, the convention aga in broke out
          into shouts and applause.
          William s' Voice Falling.
          this time Mr. Williams* voice
          was failing. It grew weaker and he
          was heard with difficulty even by
          those very near the platform.
          Mr. Williams' flow of oratory was
          uninterrupted for some time. A re
          sponse of applause followed his de
          nunciation of the republican claims of
          prosperity because of the tariff. Cries
          of louder were again heard in various
          parts of the hall.
          "I wish I had the lungs to speak
          louder, but I cannot," answered Mr.
          Williams.
          "What did you say?" came a voice
          from the gallery.
          So rapidly did the noise Increase
          that Mr. Williams began to address
          himself directly to the persons on the
          platform. This brought forth from
          the galleries loud cries of "time" and
          "louder." Mr. Williams, with all the
          voice left, turned to the audience and,
          with considerable feeling, took up the
          race question. When he referred to
          the incident at the republican con
          vention when a colored child and
          white child were both on the plat
          form waving flags during one of the
          demonstrations, there we re cries of
          "This is a white man's country!" "~$0&amp;
          Police Tried to Clear Aisles. g|
          So great did the noise become that
          the sergeant-at-arms went down into
          the hall and ordered the aisles
          cleared. But the police had difficulty
          in carrying out these instructions. Mr.
          Williams had by this time been speak
          ing an hour and twenty-five minutes.
          "Now, a few words in conclusion,"
          said Mr. Williams, "and if you are as
          pleased to hear that conclusion as I
          am to conclude, this will be the most
          delighted audience that ever existed."
          Wiliams closed his speech at 2:05
          p.m.
          Mr. Williams devotes most of his
          speech to an arraignment of Presi
          dent Roosevelt, ex-Secretary Root and
          the republican party, chiefly by as
          sailing Mr. Root's speech as tempo
          rary chairman of the republican na
          tional convention, which, he says,
          was largely historical. Mr. Williams
          continued:
          It was to draw away attention from
          Rooseveltism and its volcanic, eruptive
          and reckless character by dwelling upon
          Several the fact that at some period of its history
          W3
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045555/1904-07-06/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Democratic+Convention+Parker+Turner+President+Running+Mate+Democrats</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045366/1904-07-09/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Parker+Nominated+Democratcs+Democratic+Convention+President+Running+Mate+Harmon#</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045366/1904-07-09/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Parker+Nominated+Democratcs+Democratic+Convention+President+Running+Mate+Harmon#</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>


      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014248/1900-11-07/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=roosevelt+elected</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86079068/1904-11-10/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=roosevelt+elected</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          ROOSEVELT OUR NEXT PRESIDENT.
          A Sweeping Victory for the Republicans.
          Every Doubtful State Carried. Dem
          ocrats Elect Governors in
          Massachusetts, Minnesota and West Vir
          ginia----Republicans Retain Control of
          "-House of Representatives.
          Special to The Times-Democrat.
          New York. Nov. .--Theodore
          Roosevelt was elected President
          yesterday for the term beginning
          March 4 next by an overwhelming
          majority in the electoral college and
          by a majority of the popular vote
          greater than that of any President in
          recent years.
          He carried every Northern and
          Western State, every doubtful State
          and everything but the so-called Solid
          South.
          He will have 325 electoral votes to
          151 for Judge Parker. Electoral
          majority for Roosevelt 174.
          His greatest plurality is in his own
          State- New York. At midninht the
          higures in hand indicated that he will
          have 2: ).si votes more than Parker.
          His vote in Illinois. in Massachusetts
          and in most of the Western States
          was larger than that of McKinley in
          lipi. In every State.-that he carried
          he ran tylly as well as McKinley did
          four years ago.
          On the other hand. Judge Parker
          did not get as many votes in New
          York as Bryan did four years ago.
          and seems to have run behind the
          Bryan tote in all parts of the country.
          In 1872 the electoral vote was:
          Grant 292. Greeley (and other Demo
          crats) 74: Grant's plurality 218.
          In 1892 it was: Cleveland 277. Harri
          son 1a5. Weaver (Pop.) 22: Cleve
          laud's plurality 112.
          In ln4i6 it was: McKinley 271. Bryan
          176, McKinley's plurality !g5.
          The Republicans retain control of
          the House of Representatives by an
          increased majority. The indications
          at midnight are that they will have
          from '20 to 230 members. They now
          have 210 members.
          It was apparent within an hour
          after the polls closed that Roosevelt
          had received a tremendous vote. As
          early as 61 o'clock it was seen that his
          election was certain unless there
          should be some tremendous change.
          The returns at midnight indicate
          that about the bnly successes the.
          Democrats have had in the country
          are in West Virginia, Massachusetts
          and Minnesota. They elected their
          Governors in each of these States,
          although the Republicans carried
          them by increased majorities for, the
          electoral ticket.
          In most of the States where United
          States .senatorships were at stake the
          Republicans have elected their Legis
          latures. The Senators elected to
          begin their six-year terms on March 5,
          1905, will practically be in the same
          proportion as to party atlliatiod as
          those now sitting, thus continuing the
          Republican control of the Senate.
          At midnight William J. Bryan
          claimed Nebraska for the fusion can
          didate for Governor. This probably
          means that a fusion legislature has
          been elected. Bryan made his cam
          paign in Nebraska in the hope of secur
          ing the Legislature and his election to
          the United States Senate.
          In Wisconsin Gov. La Follette was
          elected over the Democratic and
          stalwart or bolting Republican can
          didates. The result on the Legislature
          is in doubt at midnight. Unless La
          Follete carries the Legislature he will
          not be able to put his taxation theories
          into effect.
          President Roosevelt announced at
          u o'elock that under no hreuamstapees
          wi be be a eaadldste tavelection
          in loR. rThis leaves the held open to
          the many Republicans who have pre
          sidental asjpirations, including Vice
          President-elect FairbanKs. Senator
          Foraker and Secretary Taft of Ohio.
          Secretary Sliaw of Iowa and C-ove
          La Follette of Wisconsin.
          There are au few returns as yet on
          Sociali4t and Populist vote. W Vat-on
          ran exceedingly well in some part
          of the South. hut most of his exlpeted
          strength in New York seems to have
          gone to Roosevelt.
          Debs, the Socialist candidate, re
          ceived 45.4)tt votes in Chicago and
          was heavily supported in many of the
          cities. It is expected that his vote
          will approximate half a million.
          The election of Douglas, Democrat
          ic candidate for Govereor in Mass
          achusetts. was the greatest surprise
          in the East. Douglas received :14.1):1
          plurality in Boston to 10.$74 for
          Foot Ball Saturday
          INDUSTRIAL INSTITUTE
          VERSUS
          LAKE CHARLES HIGH SCHOOL
          On the Industrial Institute Campus at 2 p. m.
          SATURDAY
          The Biggest Oame of the Season
          ADMISSION 25 CENTS.*
          Parker in the same city. He carried
          the State by 2).4(0) while Roosevelt's
          plurality was 80.0010.
          In Indiana, where the Democrats
          made one of the fiercest fights. the
          results are fully as remarkable as in
          New York. Roosevelt carries the
          State by 40,000. Chairman Taggart
          spent the three last weeks of the cam
          paign in Indiana. Marion county,
          which contains Indianapolis. and
          which is Taggart's home county,
          gave Roosevelt four times the plurali
          ty which iL gave McKinley four years
          ago.
          The play alities in the Southern
          State. are about the same size as they
          were four years ago.
          Services at Episcopal Church.
          Regular services on the second
          and fourth Sundays of each
          month at the Episcopal Church,
          will be resumed next Sunday at
          4:30 p. m.
          W. B. Corsets, all styles, at
          Levy Bros.
          Mrs. Z. J. Francez, of Caren
          cro, was in town yesterday after
          noon.
          For a nice Pate de Foies Gras
          aux Truffes, Guava Jelly, pure
          Olive oil, go to Alex Delahous
          saye.
          Don't forget to call and see
          the Guarenteed Dollar Razor
          at Ruger's Jewelry Store.
          OFFICIAL RETURNS
          For Lafayette Parish. A Light
          Vote Polled,
          The election Tuesday passed
          off very quietly and only a light
          v'te was polled. No incidents of
          any special moment occurred.
          The commissioners of election
          met yesterday morning and can
          vassed the returns.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014248/1904-09-05/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=roosevelt+elected&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.327,0.385,0.41,1.053,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          hen tin- is-ople wanted coal; he got
          them coal; tliereiore Roosevelt.
          When tin- jH-ople wanted an isthmian
          canal, he got them the Panama canal;
          therein! e Roosevelt.
          "Inn Great Jliilain and Germany en
          deaveren to ignore the Monroe dnettilie,
          be called them down; there lure Roosevelt.
          When mwar, lie organized the rough riders; there
          lore Roosevelt.
          When tin* time came to fulfill William
          McKinley s promises of aid to Cuba, he
          carried the ’uban reciprocity hill; there
          fore Roosevelt.
          When matters in the postal department
          needed investigation, lie forced the inves
          tigation; therefore Roosevelt.
          \Vhen the time came to enforce John
          Sherman’s anti-miM law, he enforced it;
          there tore Roosevelt.
          When it is necessary to speak “right
          nut in meeting” lie does so; therefore
          Rooscveit.
          W hen there is work to 1m* lone on bo
          halt of tin whole American people, he
          does it; therefore Roosevelt.
          When relations with Spain were be
          coming straiin 1, he put Dewey and his
          I1* t where it might be wanted; therefor**
          Roosevelt.
          A h,-ji the time came to resume William
          McKinlev’s burden of responsibility, and
          to erry out his policy, he di«l both*
          th* r- tore Roosevelt.
          hen the necessity arc.se to recognize
          the rights of our colored fellow citizens,
          he recognized them; therefore Roosevelt.
          W li n ;he people of New' York city sent
          nim to Albany, as assemblyman, to pro
          tect tln-ir interests, he protected them
          then fore Roosevelt.
          hen tin* people of the state of New
          ork called him to the governor’s chair,
          ne made one of the best governors the
          state ever had: therefore Roosevelt.
          When his party nominated him for the
          presidency on the platform they had
          adopted, he did not dodge, or seek to
          dodge, any of its planks; therefore
          Roosevelt.
          When he accepted the nomination
          accepted it without reserve as to any
          his party’s Issues: therefore Roosevelt
          When his party nominated him i
          ctand on a platform of gold, he did ru
          wobble on one of silver, with gold trip
          "ones of Id* :|S does his opponoii
          therefore Roosevelt.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016413/1901-08-15/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=roosevelt+elected</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86075272/1926-10-21/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=roosevelt+elected</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>